<rss>
	<item>
		<title>More Thursday Night Games for the N.F.L.</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>3 Mar 2011 06:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		INDIANAPOLIS — The N.F.L. will play more Thursday night games next season, with every team playing at least one Thursday game following a Sunday game and each team having at least one prime-time game, either on Thursday, Sunday or Monday. That will give the league a total of 17 Thursday games, including the season opener and three games on Thanksgiving. Thursday night games will be played every week between Weeks 2 and 15. The NFL Network, which had been airing eight games, will expand its offering to 13 Thursday games, probably an effort by the league to increase the value of the network as it continues to try to negotiate deals with Time Warner Cable and Cablevision to carry the network. Coaches and players are likely to have mixed emotions about the schedule switch. Playing Thursday after a Sunday game gives coaches less time to prepare and players less time to heal, but players often say they appreciate what feels like an extra bye week when they are off on the Sunday after a Thursday game. “Adding these games to the NFL Network schedule will give more players, teams and cities the prime-time stage,” Commissioner Roger Goodell said  Friday at his annual state of the league news conference. “Our fans can now get an early start on the N.F.L. weekend in the season’s first 15 weeks.”
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Moving On, Minus Its Genius</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>6 Oct 2011 14:24:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Heard of Apple TV? A lot of people have not. That is because even though Steven P. Jobs helped upend so many businesses with a string of groundbreaking products in music, mobile phones, games and tablet computers, he barely made a dent in television. Under Mr. Jobs, Apple dipped its toe only slightly into the television business with Apple TV, a set-top box for accessing Internet video. That product has been one of the rare disappointments in its lineup, especially when compared with smashes like the iPhone and iPad. But many in the tech industry contend that television is ripe for technological makeover, and that the next big challenge for Apple, after the death of Mr. Jobs, is likely to be in that area. “It’s the big area they haven’t colonized,” said James McQuivey, an analyst at Forrester Research. “It’s the thing we spend more of our time on than sleep."  In the meantime, companies like Microsoft have started to take a stronger leadership role in helping to push the technology of television forward, as Apple did in areas like music and mobile phones Apple’s Many Competitive Fronts OCT. 6, 2011 interactive
Which of Steve Jobs’s Products Mattered Most? OCT. 6, 2011 With Time Running Short, Steve Jobs Managed His Farewells OCT. 6, 2011
Master of the Media Marketplace, and Its Demanding Gatekeeper OCT. 6, 2011 Steve Jobs Defended His Work With a Barbed Tongue OCT. 6, 2011
Television is such a tantalizing target in part because people spend so many hours watching it, but also because the industry over all has been slow to innovate except perhaps in making screens larger. In particular, the consuming public is still waiting for television content — everything that people watch — to be delivered over the Internet in a convenient, affordable package on all the devices people are now using.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>They’re New, They’re Conservative, and They Say They’re Here to Make Cuts</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>26 Mar 2011 12:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Ross Ramsey, the managing editor of The Texas Tribune, writes a regular column for the Tribune. Behold the mighty freshman Republicans of the Texas House of Representatives. They’re supposed to be quiet, to bow to their tenured colleagues, to stay out of the way. The Texas Legislature has been described as high school, but with money. And the freshmen here get the same respect you got on your first day of high school. But here they are, quietly and deferentially exercising some clout on the only piece of legislation that absolutely has to pass: the state budget. After the House Appropriations Committee voted out a budget that will go to the full House this week, Representative Jim Pitts, Republican of Waxahachie and the committee’s chairman, gave this explanation for the cuts it contains: voters. He didn’t put all the blame on the new guys, but he said the budget was tight, in part, because the House was full of members who believed that the voters wanted cuts. And he pointed out that the numerous newbies were the core of that sentiment. “It’s a budget that reflects the money we have,” Mr. Pitts said. “There’s a lot of members of the House; this is as far as we can go. They feel like they were elected to make cuts, and they just accurately reflect what their constituents want.”
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>This Week’s Health Industry News</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>28 Dec 2010 11:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		With the Congress in adjournment and many business people taking off the time between holidays, we do not expect any substantive health industry news this week. But we could be surprised. Take, for instance, the news reported Sunday by our colleague Robert Pear in Washington. The Obama administration, through an administrative rule, is resurrecting the notion of end-of-life planning services for older people — the same sort of planning that was falsely characterized as death panels in one of the hottest attacks on the health care overhaul. Starting next week, the government can pay doctors through Medicare to advise people about voluntary advance care planning, according to the rule quietly issued by Dr. Donald M. Berwick, administrator of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Service. The planning could take place during the annual physical checkup that Medicare offers under the new legislation. The planning may include advance directives on how aggressively to treat patients who can no longer make their own decisions. That rule takes effect on Saturday. The 112th Congress convenes four days later, on Jan. 5. After that, we foresee a lot of health industry news coming from the Republican-controlled House of Representatives in the form of oversight hearings and spending measures. There are no Food and Drug Administration advisory committees meeting this week. The F.D.A. has scheduled a decision on Wednesday for the fast-acting inhaled insulin drug Afrezza from MannKind. But many analysts expect a further delay.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Libya Delayed Nuclear Fuel Disposal Deal</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>3 Sep 2010 12:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[ 
		In the early morning of Nov. 25, 2009, a large Russian cargo plane left the Libyan capital, Tripoli, on a secret mission without its intended cargo. A small stockpile of spent nuclear fuel destined for disposal in Russia remained behind in a lightly guarded research center, apparently because of a fit of pique by Libya’s mercurial leader, Col. Muammar el-Qaddafi. In a frantic cable back to Washington, American officials in Tripoli warned of dire consequences unless the carefully brokered deal to remove the 5.2 kilograms (11.4 pounds) of highly enriched uranium stored in seven five-ton casks was quickly resurrected. If the enriched uranium “is not removed from the casks within three months, its rising temperature could cause the casks to crack and to release radioactive nuclear material,” the American Embassy in Tripoli reported, according to cables made public by WikiLeaks. “Security concerns alone dictate that we must employ all of our resources to find a timely solution to this problem, and to keep any mention of it out of the press.” The seeds of what appeared to be the demise of the secret deal were planted weeks earlier in New York, when Colonel Qaddafi expressed unhappiness that he was not permitted to set up his tent in Manhattan or to visit ground zero during a United Nations session. But the scope of the colonel’s anger was not fully realized until Nov. 20, 2009, when the Libyan government unexpectedly ordered a team of visiting American and Russian scientists to halt preparations to ship the spent nuclear fuel to Russia, despite separate agreements Libya had reached with the United States and Russia.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>DEALBOOK ONLINE; OIL DEAL</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>23 Nov 2010 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		The independent company Energy XXI has agreed to buy $1 billion in oil and natural gas properties in the Gulf of Mexico from Exxon Mobil. The deal, announced on Sunday, includes nine shallow-water fields on the Gulf of Mexico shelf, located primarily between Energy XXI's two main drilling operations there. Energy XXI is the operator of 94 percent of the assets being acquired. The purchase would make Energy XXI the third-largest oil producer on the shelf, with interests in seven of the 11 largest oil fields there, the company said. The addition of the Exxon fields would increase the company's proved plus probable reserves 72 percent, to 158.1 million barrels of oil equivalent, from 92.1 million barrels as of June 20. It would also increase its daily production more than 77 percent from its daily average as of Sept. 30. ''The Exxon Mobil properties are an extraordinary fit with our existing, oil-focused core assets, which generate some of the highest margins in the industry,'' Energy XXI's chairman and chief executive, John D. Schiller Jr., said in a statement. Exxon Mobil announced in October that it intended to sell a small slice of its oil and natural gas production assets in the Gulf of Mexico, mostly in shallow waters. Energy XXI, for its part, said it expected to realize ''meaningful cost savings'' from the consolidation of the properties within its core focus area on the Gulf of Mexico shelf.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
</rss>
