<rss>
	<item>
		<title>2010 Tour de France Winner Found Guilty of Doping</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>6 Feb 2012 23:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		After 17 months of legal wrangling and an investigation by Basque authorities to determine the source of some purportedly tainted steaks that Alberto Contador said he ate during the 2010 Tour de France, an appeals court ruled Monday that Contador, a three-time winner of the Tour, was guilty of doping. The decision from the Court of Arbitration for Sport in Lausanne, Switzerland, resulted in Contador’s being stripped of his victory in the 2010 Tour and 12 other victories since then, and is yet another blow to a sport that has been repeatedly tarnished by doping scandals among the best cyclists in the world. Only two Tour de France winners since 1995 — Carlos Sastre in 2008 and Cadel Evans last year — have not become embroiled in controversies involving performance-enhancing drugs. Contador is perhaps the most talented cyclist of his generation and one of only five riders to win the grand tours of France, Italy and Spain. His downfall was a positive test for clenbuterol, a weight-loss and muscle-building drug, during the 2010 Tour. Some farmers are known to give clenbuterol to cattle and swine to improve their market value. Contador claimed to be a victim of such bad meat. He told investigators that because he prefers Spanish cuts of meat, a friend purchased a large veal tenderloin in the Basque Country near the French border and brought it to nearby Pau, where it was cooked for Contador and his teammates at a hotel. In elaborate detail over several pages, the panel’s decision describes how an inspector from the Basque government’s department of public health confirmed statements from Contador’s friend as well as his team’s chef that 3.2 kilograms of “veal solomillo,” a large piece of tenderloin, were purchased from the Larrezbal butcher shop at the rather steep price of 32 euros per kilo by Contador’s friend. Inspectors traced the veal back to a wholesale supplier, a slaughterhouse and finally a farmer named Lucio Carabias. was not substantiated.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Apple May Announce an iPad Upgrade in March</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>9 Feb 2012 15:53:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Apple is planning to introduce an upgraded version of its iPad tablet at a press event early next month, according to people briefed on the company’s plans. An Apple employee said that the version of the new iPad that is being tested inside the company is “essentially the same size and shape as the iPad 2,” with an improved and “truly amazing” screen. The tablet will include a faster processor, said the employee, who did not want to be identified because Apple is not fond of leaks. It’s unclear whether the product will be called the iPad 3. In the weeks leading up to Apple’s introduction last October of a new iPhone, there was rampant speculation that it would be called the iPhone 5. It was actually called the iPhone 4S, a name that implied more modest changes than the bold redesign some pundits had hoped for. That early grumbling did not stop the iPhone 4S from helping Apple post record holiday sales. Apple’s first iPad was released in April 2010, and the iPad 2 came out in March 2011. The company typically upgrades its mobile products about once a year. With the iPhone 4, Apple introduced a screen with a higher pixel density, which it called a retina display. The next iPad could presumably come into line with recent iPhone models and have a similar display. All Things D, the technology blog, reported earlier that Apple would announce a third-generation iPad next month at an event in San Francisco. An Apple spokeswoman declined to comment. Over all, Apple has sold more than 55 million iPads to date. If you consider the iPad to be a computer, Apple was the biggest seller of personal computers in the world during the holiday season of 2011, according to Canalys, a research company.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Court Won’t Rule on San Diego Cross</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>14 Feb 2011 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		The Supreme Court on Monday announced that it would not decide whether a cross at a veterans memorial in San Diego can be allowed to remain on public land. In a statement, Justice Samuel A. Alito Jr. said that although the case presented “a question of substantial importance,” the court could not rule because a binding decision had not yet been rendered by the lower courts. A district court has been assessing whether a modification might be made to the cross so that it passes constitutional muster. Since 1913 a cross has stood prominently on Mount Soledad in San Diego, first placed there as an explicitly religious symbol. The current cross, 43 feet high, was erected in 1954 and dedicated “as a lasting memorial to the dead of the first and second World Wars and the Korean conflict.” Only in the 1990s was a veterans memorial, consisting of plaques surrounding the cross, added to the site. The first lawsuit opposing the cross was filed in 1989 by two Vietnam veterans; the site has been the focus of near-constant litigation ever since. The most recent ruling on the subject, made by the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit, in San Francisco, found that the cross violates the First Amendment’s prohibition of government establishment of religion.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Heart Warning Added to Label on Popular Antipsychotic Drug</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>18 Jul 2011 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		AstraZeneca is adding a new heart warning to the labels of Seroquel, its blockbuster antipsychotic drug, at the request of the Food and Drug Administration, company and agency officials said on Monday. The revised label, posted without fanfare last week on the F.D.A. Web site, says Seroquel and extended-release Seroquel XR “should be avoided” in combination with at least 12 other medicines linked to a heart arrhythmia that can cause sudden cardiac arrest. Sandy Walsh, a spokeswoman for the F.D.A., said the statement was only a precaution for doctors, and should not be considered a complete ban against prescribing Seroquel with the other drugs. Ms. Walsh said the label was changed after the F.D.A. received new information about reports of arrhythmia in 17 people who took more than the recommended doses of Seroquel. Though it should not be a problem at a normal dosage, she said, it may still be good advice to avoid using the drugs together. The arrhythmia, known as prolongation of the QT interval, referring to two waves of the heart’s electrical rhythm, is estimated to cause several thousand deaths a year in the United States. As AstraZeneca prepares to report its second-quarter earnings at the end of this month, it faces additional scrutiny this week. The F.D.A. is considering the London-based company’s dapagliflozin, a proposed diabetes drug with Bristol-Myers Squibb, and is expected to decide soon on Brilinta, an anticoagulant. The company is facing the loss of patents for Seroquel next year and for the heartburn drug Nexium in 2014. Seroquel is one of the top-selling drugs in the world, at $5.3 billion last year, including $3.7 billion in the United States. Introduced in 1997, it has been approved for schizophrenia, bipolar disorder and severe depression. Seroquel has caused legal problems for AstraZeneca, including a $520 million payment in 2009 to settle government charges of illegal marketing. Thousands of lawsuits are pending over side effects like diabetes. The previous Seroquel labels had mentioned the risk of a prolonged QT interval, but had not identified other drugs to avoid, Stephanie Andrzejewski, a spokeswoman for AstraZeneca, said Monday. The new warning also is separated from other warnings and precautions on the label, she said, “to provide some additional guidance to physicians” treating patients ”who are already at risk of QT prolongation.”
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Sudan: Bashir Forced to Skip 2 International Events</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>1 Dec 2010 10:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		President Omar al-Bashir, who is wanted on charges of genocide, was forced to stay away from two high-profile international events this week after diplomatic pressure. On Wednesday, judges at the International Criminal Court, who had issued a warrant for Mr. Bashir’s arrest, warned the Central African Republic that it was obliged by treaty to arrest him should he arrive on its territory. Mr. Bashir, left, abruptly canceled his planned trip to attend the Central African Republic’s independence celebrations on Wednesday. He was also forced to stay away from the 80-nation African-European summit meeting in Libya, which ended Tuesday, after a number of European nations had informed the Libyan government that they would not attend the meeting if Mr. Bashir were present.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>U.S. Import Prices Rebound</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>14 Dec 2011 11:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		American import prices recorded their largest increase in seven months in November as the cost of oil surged, but underlying import inflation pressures remain contained. Overall import prices in the U.S. rebounded 0.7 percent, the Labor Department said Wednesday. They had fallen 0.5 percent in October. Last month’s increase was the largest since April. Economists polled by Reuters had expected prices to rise 0.9 percent last month. Import prices were up 9.9 percent in the 12 months through November. Excluding oil, import prices fell 0.2 percent after declining 0.3 percent in October. Despite the 3.6 percent rise in the cost of imported oil last month, inflation pressures remain largely in check, after a surge in energy prices early this year dampened growth. Prices on imported petroleum rose in November for the first time since July and reversed a 1.1 percent drop in October. Suggesting benign inflation pressures, imported food prices slipped 0.1 percent last month after falling 0.7 percent in October.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
</rss>
