<rss>
	<item>
		<title>Wild-Card Probabilities: Packers Over Eagles</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>6 Jan 2011 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Brian Burke, a former Navy pilot who has taken up the less dangerous hobby of N.F.L. statistical analysis, operates Advanced NFL Stats, a blog about football, math and human behavior. Of the four wild-card games this weekend, the efficiency probability model disagrees with the general consensus on only one game, Green Bay at Philadelphia. The Packers are slightly favored by my system, ranking third in overall team efficiency compared with seventh for the Eagles. On offense, the Eagles’ rushing attack leads the N.F.L. at 5.5 yards per carry (YPC), far ahead of the second-most-efficient rushing team at 4.9 YPC. You might think that’s because of Michael Vick’s elusiveness, but running back LeSean McCoy is averaging 5.2 YPC, and his backup Jerome Harrison has 40 carries at a 6.0 YPC clip. But if there’s one guy who defies a simple efficiency model, it’s Vick. His running yards are typically on passing downs, but they show up in the Eagles’ running efficiency. Using a more advanced statistic called Expected Points Added (EPA), which is agnostic as to whether a play is a run or pass and measures a squad’s production of net scoring advantage, the Eagles’ offense has generated 130 EPA, while the Packers’ offense has generated about 108 EPA. The real difference between the two teams is on defense, where the Packers have a significant advantage. Their defensive unit is responsible for nearly -53 EPA (negative is better for defenses), while the Eagles’ defense is on the other side of the spectrum, having given up 49 EPA. Vick will get all the attention Sunday, but I think Rodgers has had a slightly better season. Rodgers has averaged 0.22 EPA per play, and Vick has averaged 0.20. I think the Packers are the better overall team, enough to overcome the Eagles’ home-field advantage by a narrow margin. It’s still a tight matchup, but the edge goes to Green Bay.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Google Adds Posts From Its Social Network to Search Results</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>10 Jan 2012 09:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		SAN FRANCISCO — Google’s popularity was built on its ability to help people find just the right Web pages. Then came the social Web, led by Facebook, where people go to see vast amounts of material that has largely been off-limits to Google — conversations and photos posted by their friends On Tuesday, Google sparked controversy when it made some of the biggest changes ever to its search results, adding content from its fledgling Google Plus social network. That includes posts, photos, profiles and conversations from Google Plus that are public or were shared privately with the person searching. With the new feature, which Google calls Search Plus Your World, it is once again reimagining what people want from its search engine, which for many is the front door to the Web. It is betting that they are looking for more personalized and timely updates than it has been offering, as it competes with Facebook and others for users’ time. “What you search today is largely written by people you don’t know; we call that the faceless Web,” said Amit Singhal, a Google Fellow who oversees search. “Search Plus Your World transforms search and centers it around you.” But many people turn to Google for links to expert information, and might not want their search results to be cluttered with friends’ postings, or find it disconcerting to see personal information from friends in search results. For some experts the new feature also raised antitrust concerns, because in many instances Google will show information from its social network before or instead of others. Twitter said it was concerned that Google’s change would make timely information from Twitter harder to find on Google. “We think that’s bad for people, publishers, news organizations and Twitter users,” the company said in a statement. Danny Sullivan, an expert on the search industry and editor of the blog Search Engine Land, said Google was right that people wanted to see social posts — but most of those posts are on other social networks.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Top Candidates for State Dept. Are Both Facing Possible Hurdles</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>12 Nov 2012 05:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		 For months, the Beltway parlor game about who will succeed Hillary Rodham Clinton as secretary of state has revolved around two names: Susan E. Rice, the American ambassador to the United Nations, and Senator John Kerry of Massachusetts. But now that President Obama’s re-election has made the exercise real rather than hypothetical, both front-runners for the most coveted job in his cabinet are dogged by issues that could complicate their path to Mrs. Clinton’s State Department office. Of the two, Ms. Rice, an outspoken, ambitious diplomat with close ties to Mr. Obama, has emerged as the clear favorite. But she would face stiff resistance on Capitol Hill, where she has come under withering criticism from Republicans for asserting that the deadly attack on the American mission in Benghazi, Libya, might have been a spontaneous protest rather than a terrorist attack. Mr. Kerry, who is the chairman of the Senate Foreign Relations Committee and prepped Mr. Obama for his debates with Mitt Romney, holds a Senate seat that the White House worries could fall into Republican hands if he gave it up for a cabinet post.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Cancer Risk From Barrett’s Esophagus Lower Than Thought</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>13 Oct 2011 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		People who have a condition known as Barrett’s esophagus, a complication of acid reflux disease, have a higher risk of developing esophageal cancer — but the risk is far smaller than widely believed, a new study shows. Those with Barrett’s esophagus, which affects about a million Americans, have long been encouraged to undergo repeated, invasive screening tests to look for signs of cancer in the cells lining the food pipe. The condition was thought to make cancer of the esophagus up to 40 times as likely. But the new study found that the risk of esophageal cancer in Barrett’s patients was only about a fifth of what is currently believed. That suggests that the routine tests and endoscopies patients are subjected to may not be necessary in many cases, said Dr. Peter Funch-Jensen, a professor of surgery at Aarhus University in Denmark and an author of the study, which was published this week in The New England Journal of Medicine. The study is by far the largest and most comprehensive to date on the subject. “If you combine the data from all other studies, it adds up to about 60,000 patient-years, and our study comes out to about 70,000 patient-years,” Dr. Funch-Jensen said. To come up with the new estimate, Dr. Funch-Jensen and his colleagues collected data over nearly 20 years on more than 11,000 people in Denmark who had a diagnosis of Barrett’s esophagus. The researchers used Danish medical registries, which contain data on Denmark’s entire population of over five million people, many of them tracked since birth.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Egypt: President Frees Islamists</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>1 Aug 2012 12:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		President Mohamed Morsi has freed a group of Islamists jailed for militancy during Hosni Mubarak’s era, a step seen as a gesture to hard-liners who supported his presidential bid. A lawyer for 17 Islamists, many of them held since the 1990s, said they owed their release to a pardon issued by Mr. Morsi. At least three of those released had been condemned to death, said the lawyer, Ibrahim Ali. Those released in recent days include members of Gamaa al-Islamiya, jailed during the group’s armed insurrection against the state in the 1990s, and Islamic Jihad, the movement behind the 1981 assassination of President Anwar el-Sadat. Mr. Morsi is facing calls from Islamists to secure the release of the remaining few dozen of their brethren who they believe are being kept behind bars by security forces resistant to the new president’s wishes.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>New Governor Named For the Bank of Canada</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>22 Dec 1993 13:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		John Crow, whose Draconian anti-inflation policies have made him a political target in a period of double-digit Canadian unemployment, is stepping down as the governor of Canada's central bank, the Government announced today. But he is to be replaced by his deputy, Gordon Thiessen, a longtime Bank of Canada employee, who is expected to keep the same emphasis on price stability. The announcement by Finance Minister Paul Martin ended one of the biggest guessing games here since the e-lection of the Liberal Government nearly two months ago. Mr. Crow's policies had been attacked by many Liberals, including the new Prime Minister, Jean Chretien, whose campaign slogan was "jobs, jobs, jobs." But until now the Government had ducked the issue of whether he would be reappointed when his seven-year term expired next month. Policy Called 'Misguided' Bankers had argued that Mr. Crow was essential to maintain the country's financial credibility abroad and prevent a collapse of the Canadian dollar. Yet many on the left wanted to dump him. A recently formed "Crow To Go" coalition called the policy of fighting inflation with high interest rates "misguided and destructive." Jeff Rubin, the chief economist at Wood Gundy Inc., a leading brokerage firm, said Mr. Crow "became a sacrificial lamb." The change in the guard did not fluster the markets. The Canadian dollar, after touching a six-year low, rebounded immediately after the announcement and closed against the American dollar at 74.82 cents, up 0.43 cent.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
</rss>
