<rss>
	<item>
		<title>Rangers Players' Move Could Save Team and Sport</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>13 Mar 2012 12:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		LONDON — Insolvency experts appointed to save — or close down — Rangers Football Club in Glasgow set Friday as the deadline for potential buyers to show their money. The administrators say there is interest from the Far East and North America, as well as from Scotland. The future of more than just the Rangers, formed 140 years ago, depends upon it. The stricken club is reminiscent of a gigantic ocean liner in distress. It is taking on water, and livelihoods, if not lives, are at stake. If Rangers F.C., one of the world’s first clubs, which five years ago was apparently one of the wealthiest, can go down, then where is the safety for others. Rangers is more of a Protestant institution than a mere sports club. Its base in Scotland is where many of the British banks, and a major part of the tax revenue collection system, have their roots. That, of course, is the mirror to our times. The banks lent too much to soccer. The governments were too slow to collect their taxes because, until now, soccer was considered the people’s sport. But Rangers symbolizes the sport at large. For example, in Switzerland, long considered Europe’s safe banking house, three professional clubs are in serious trouble. Neuchâtel Xamax was dropped from the Swiss Super League and declared bankrupt in January after a disastrous ownership by an exiled Chechen. Genève-Servette has also filed for bankruptcy protection. And the sport’s international body, FIFA, based in Switzerland and led by a Swiss man, threatened last year to ban the Swiss federation over a dispute about ineligible players.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>How the Tech Parade Passed Sony By</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>14 Apr 2012 13:45:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		THE lights dimmed. The crowd hushed. The teleprompters flickered.

Kazuo Hirai stepped up and flashed a winning smile: it was show time. The scene was oddly upbeat inside the Sony Corporation last Thursday as Mr. Hirai, the company’s new chief executive, faced the cameras. He outlined a strategy that, he vowed, would return the troubled electronics giant to profit. “The time for Sony to change is now,” said Mr. Hirai, who formally took up the C.E.O. post on April 1. He posed for the cameras, one finger held high in a No. 1 sign. “I believe Sony can change,” he said. Outside Sony — and inside it, too — not everyone is quite so sure. That is because Sony, which once defined Japan’s technological prowess, wowed the world with the Walkman and the Trinitron TV and shocked Hollywood with bold acquisitions like Columbia Pictures, is now in the fight of its life. In fact, it is in a fight for its life — a development that exemplifies the stunning decline of Japan’s industrialized economy. Once upon a time, Japan Inc., not to mention Sony itself, seemed invulnerable. Today, Sony and many other Japanese manufacturers are pressed on all sides: by rising Asian rivals, a punishingly strong Japanese yen and, in Sony’s case, an astonishing lack of ideas.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Obama and Romney React to Court’s Immigration Decision</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>25 Jan 2012 12:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		The rivals for the presidency reacted swiftly on Monday to the Supreme Court’s decision to strike down parts of Arizona’s aggressive immigration laws while letting a controversial provision stand. President Obama said the decision to stop enforcement of parts of the Arizona law underscored the need for comprehensive immigration reform by the federal government. But he said he remained concerned about a provision that requires the police to check the status of people they suspect may be in the country illegally. “I remain concerned about the practical impact of the remaining provision of the Arizona law that requires local law enforcement officials to check the immigration status of anyone they even suspect to be here illegally,” Mr. Obama said. “No American should ever live under a cloud of suspicion just because of what they look like.” Mitt Romney issued a brief statement saying he supported aggressive efforts by states to fight illegal immigration. “I believe that each state has the duty – and the right – to secure our borders and preserve the rule of law, particularly when the federal government has failed to meet its responsibilities,” Mr. Romney, the presumptive Republican nominee, said in a written statement. Neither candidate chose to make remarks on camera. Mr. Obama was traveling to New Hampshire and Boston for campaign events on Monday. Mr. Romney was campaigning in the West, including a fund-raising stop in Arizona.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Study Sees Heart Risk in Meridia Diet Pill</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>1 Sep 2010 17:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		A clinical trial of Meridia, a controversial diet pill, in nearly 10,000 overweight or obese older patients over many years found that the drug increased the risks of heart attacks and strokes while doing little to slim their waists. The study was paid for by Abbott Laboratories, Meridia’s maker, and published in The New England Journal of Medicine. And the authors of the study, three of whom are Abbott employees, concluded that the trial results did little more than show that patients with heart problems should not be prescribed Meridia — a restriction already included in Meridia’s label. But in an unusual rebuke, The Journal’s top editors wrote an editorial concluding that the study actually showed that Meridia, also known as sibutramine, should be removed from the market. “It wasn’t that we disagreed with the interpretation of the authors,” said Dr. Gregory D. Curfman, The Journal’s executive editor. “It’s just that we thought they didn’t quite go far enough.” Many patients, Dr. Curfman added, “have cardiovascular disease and don’t know it. How are you supposed to identify those patients who might be put at risk by putting them on drugs like sibutramine?” After seeing preliminary results of the trial in January, the European Medicines Agency ordered Abbott to remove Meridia from the European market. The Food and Drug Administration took a less forceful step and instead requested that Abbott state on the drug’s label that Meridia should not be used in patients with a history of cardiovascular disease. The agency will ask a committee of experts on Sept. 15 whether further steps are needed. Dr. David J. Graham, a drug-safety official at the F.D.A., said the agency’s decision to allow continued marketing of Meridia was mistaken and resulted because officials who approved the drug remain in charge of assessing its safety.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Killing of General Vexes Rebels in Libya</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>2 Aug 2011 13:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		In a mourning tent for the Libyan rebels’ top military leader, who was assassinated last week in mysterious circumstances, relatives and members of his tribe warned on Tuesday of dire consequences, including violence, if rebel leaders did not move quickly to find his killers. The relatives, including three of his sons, warned that the provisional rebel government, the Transitional National Council, was moving too slowly to form a committee to investigate the death the commander, Gen. Abdul Fattah Younes. General Younes and two colleagues were shot to death by unknown gunmen on Thursday. “A week passed with no information,” said one of the sons, who demanded that his first name not be published. “What we cannot take by law, we’ll take by arms.” Other people at the gathering spoke in more measured terms but also warned of untold consequences if the Transitional National Council failed to identify the killers and explain their motives. Their admonitions deepened the sense of crisis around the rebel leaders, who are facing homegrown strife while struggling to root out what they say is a well-armed fifth column of supporters of the Libyan leader, Col. Muammar el-Qaddafi, who lurk in the rebel stronghold of Benghazi. In western Libya, seven rebel fighters were killed and dozens were injured near the city of Zlitan as rebels fought soldiers loyal to Colonel Qaddafi, Reuters reported. Late Monday night, one of the colonel’s sons, Seif al-Islam Qaddafi, said in his first television appearance in weeks that his father’s forces had no intention of giving up, regardless of whether NATO withdrew. “The fighting will continue until all of Libya is liberated,” he said. In Benghazi on Tuesday, the second day of Ramadan, the city settled into different routines and coped with new challenges. Calls to bring armed men under central control were fueled by accusations that General Younes was killed by a person in one of the dozens of armed militias in the rebel areas.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Shares Continue Losing Streak for Week as Europeans Fail to Act on Debt Crisis</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>2 Aug 2012 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Stocks fell for a fourth consecutive day on Thursday after the president of the European Central Bank, Mario Draghi, disappointed investors hoping for immediate action to contain Europe’s debt crisis. The losses on Wall Street, at less than 1 percent, were not as severe as those in the euro zone markets, where declines ranged from 2.2 percent in Germany to 5.2 percent in Spain. Although the markets were focused mostly on the European Central Bank, traders were also looking ahead to Friday’s closely watched employment report in the United States, which could bring a volatile end to an eventful week. Mr. Draghi said the central bank was willing to start buying Italian and Spanish government bonds to hold down borrowing costs, but it would act only after euro zone governments moved first. The announcement surprised traders, who had thought that central bank action was imminent after Mr. Draghi pledged last week to do “whatever it takes” to save the euro. “People were looking for concrete steps and an outline of exactly what path the E.C.B. would take to do that, and there weren’t any,” said Brian Gendreau, market strategist with the Cetera Financial Group. “Just as the market went up on the ‘whatever it takes’ comments, it is coming down on the lack of specificity.” Wall Street rallied late last week in part on hopes for new economic stimulus from the Federal Reserve but mostly as expectations grew that the European Central Bank would finally take action to protect the euro. But the Fed took no new steps to support the economy on Wednesday, although it said it was ready to act if needed.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
</rss>
