<rss>
	<item>
		<title>England Loses National Team Coach and Invites Uncertainty</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>8 Feb 2012 08:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		England invented competitive soccer as the world plays it, and a legal system copied by many.But an astonishing few hours Wednesday left the sport and the concept of fair play open to question. During the lunch hour, Harry Redknapp, the manager of Tottenham Hotspur, was acquitted of a charge of income tax fraud. After tea, Fabio Capello, the Italian who coached England’s national team since 2008, resigned. The two apparently disparate events were soon joined. Redknapp has been the favorite to succeed Capello as the national team manager for some time. The news media is relentless in stating that England should be coached by an Englishman. Now, four months before the European Championship, the vacancy exists. What brought Capello’s resignation, or certainly accelerated it, followed another case of sport and the law. A magistrate in London agreed last week to postpone the trial of John Terry, the England captain and also the captain of Chelsea, until July. This meant that Terry, charged by the public prosecutor with racially abusing a black player during a game last October, remains free to represent his club and his country until after Euro 2012. Nobody could envision a sport diverting the course of justice for so long. But it left England’s soccer authority, the Football Association, in a delicate situation.The F.A. announced, seemingly without first consulting Capello, that Terry could play for England but could not be captain of the team. That decision divided the nation. How could someone who pleads not guilty be deemed fit to play for the nation, but not be its leader, as Capello chose him to be?
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Sony Puts Its Weight Behind 3-D TV</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>5 Jan 2011 11:25:30 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Sony put on an elaborate sales pitch for 3-D devices Wednesday and announced new programming for 3NET, the 3-D television network that will start up in a few months. At a news media event before the opening of the Consumer Electronics Show, the company also said it would introduce new lines of 3-D and Internet-connected television sets and Blu-ray players. Howard Stringer, the chief executive of Sony, wore a pair of 3-D glasses on stage at the beginning of the event, even after the snippets of 3-D video had stopped. “I wore mine for the whole thing and didn’t even remember, they were so comfortable,” he remarked a few minutes later. “That’s not a plug,” he added, chalking it up to being “stupid.” Having to wear the glasses, of course, is one of the chief limitations of 3-D TV, and Sony is among the companies that says it is working on technology that would enable 3-D viewing without any headgear at all. Indeed, Sony has big screens that display 3-D movies without glasses at its booth on the show floor, and they are a sight to see. “Cloudy With a Chance of Meatballs” is one of the films that is featured in the highlights reel. But Sony has not indicated when such screens will make it to market. More imminently, Mr. Stringer said that this year, Sony would release 3-D-enabled Handycam and Bloggie camcorders and a 3-D-enabled Vaio computer. “Imagine watching your child’s soccer games in 3-D,” Mr. Stringer said. On the show floor, Sony is displaying some highlights from 3NET, its forthcoming cable channel venture with Discovery Communications and Imax. The companies announced the name for the channel on Wednesday, but did not announce a start date. People with knowledge of the plans said they expected it to start in March or April, but they insisted on anonymity because the plans had not been made public.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Justices Refuse to Hear Ex-Governor’s Appeal</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>4 Jan 2012 14:49:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		The Supreme Court on Monday declined to hear the appeals of former Gov. Don E. Siegelman of Alabama and the man convicted of bribing him, a case which has tested the murky limits of when a campaign donation can be considered corrupt. The two were convicted in 2006 on federal bribery charges after Richard M. Scrushy, the former chief executive of HealthSouth, contributed $500,000 to help pay off the debt of a 1999 referendum campaign for a state lottery favored by the governor, who in turn named Mr. Scrushy to a state hospital board. Mr. Scrushy is in prison and Mr. Siegelman has been out on bail as the case bounced around the courts, its status complicated by subsequent rulings of the Supreme Court involving corruption and campaign finance. Among other defenses, their lawyers have argued that Mr. Siegelman did not personally benefit from the payment and that there was no explicit quid pro quo to turn Mr. Scrushy’s campaign contribution into an illegal bribe. But the prosecution of Mr. Siegelman, begun during the Bush administration but carried on by the Obama administration as well, has provoked a considerably broader political and legal debate. His defenders claimed it began as a politically inspired attempt by Republicans to take down a rising Democrat, pushed through by overly zealous prosecutors on shaky legal grounds. Scores of former state attorneys general and legal scholars came to his defense, saying that there was a danger in allowing prosecutors too much discretion in making a crime out of political contributions. It is a question that has new salience in light of the recent trial of former presidential candidate John Edwards, and in a new era of enormous financial support for candidates from wealthy individuals supposedly operating independently from candidates.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>U.S. Drug Move Said to Deprive Elderly</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>23 Mar 2010 09:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		A Senate panel will hear complaints on Wednesday from nursing home operators, doctors, nurses and pharmacists that a Drug Enforcement Administration narcotics crackdown has left seriously ill patients crying for pain relief. The D.E.A. says it is merely enforcing the law that requires pharmacies to wait for prescriptions that are signed by physicians before dispensing potent painkillers like Vicodin, Percocet and morphine. But the nursing home groups say the new enforcement rules upend many years of practice in which the government informally allowed nurses to speed the process by taking doctors’ orders orally, or from medical charts, and passing them along to pharmacies, similar to the procedures used in hospitals. Now many of the nation’s nursing homes report delays of a day or more in getting pain drugs to patients, according to the Quality Care Coalition for Patients in Pain, a group set up by nursing home operators, pharmacists and nursing groups. The delays “leave vulnerable, frail patients to struggle through unimaginable pain for hours and even days, while physicians, nurses and pharmacists struggle to collect required D.E.A. paperwork,” the group says in a report to be released on Wednesday to coincide with the hearing. The hearing, by the Senate Special Committee on Aging, whose chairman is the Wisconsin Democrat Herb Kohl, has been titled “The War on Drugs Meets the War on Pain: Nursing Home Patients Caught in the Crossfire.” Nearly two million people live in the nation’s 16,000 nursing homes, the Census Bureau says. Surveys show pain management is an issue for 40 to 85 percent of them, and Medicare says they often need more pain relief. Since last year, though, the D.E.A. has tried to crack down on the nurses’ shortcut and taken action against some pharmacies in Ohio, Michigan, Wisconsin and Virginia that the agency accused of dispensing painkillers without having prescriptions in hand. Industry officials say the D.E.A. enforcement arose from a case in Ohio last year where a doctor complained about a nurse’s giving an opiate to a dying patient without the doctor’s knowledge and permission. D.E.A. officials declined interview requests, saying it would be inappropriate before the hearing.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Safely Back, a Pilot Tells of His Raid Over Libya</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>25 Mar 2011 23:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		As Capt. Ryan Thulin steered his F-16 fighter jet over the central Libyan coast early last Sunday, he peered into the inky darkness to hunt his target: Libyan tanks, artillery and other fielded forces. Suddenly, red tracers of antiaircraft fire streaked up from the desert below. Captain Thulin, a 28-year-old Air Force Academy graduate on his first combat mission, instinctively veered his single-seat jet away from the ground fire and dropped 500-pound, precision-guided bombs on the Libyan forces. A huge fireball lit up the cloudless sky. Several minutes later, the scene replayed itself, only this time Captain Thulin bombed army targets much closer to the outskirts of a city in eastern Libya where government troops, rebel fighters and civilians were in dangerous proximity. In the air campaign against Libya, allied warplanes have not attacked targets in cities and are under strict instructions to avoid hitting civilians. “It’s always something we’re considering on every attack,” said Captain Thulin, a pilot in the 555th Fighter Squadron based at Aviano Air Base in Italy. “You have to be confident that all the rules of engagement are met so when you do drop that weapon, in your heart of hearts, you know you’re doing the right thing.” Given in a telephone interview from Aviano, Captain Thulin’s account of his mission on the second day of the weeklong allied air operation offered a window into the world of pilots from the United States and other allies who through Friday had flown more than 450 combat flights.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Midday Shutdown Shows Struggle of London Exchange</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>25 Feb 2011 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Investors were left in limbo for four hours on Friday as the London Stock Exchange halted trading because of a technical problem — the latest embarrassing lapse to hit the bourse as it tries put a new system in place. The exchange suspended dealings shortly after the opening auction, blaming issues with market data technology just two weeks after it introduced its new platform, called Millennium. It restarted trading shortly after midday, with the chief executive, Xavier Rolet, expressing “sincere regret” at the inconvenience caused. The apology did little to appease many traders on what was expected to be a busy morning, after the release of data showing that Britain’s economy was faring worse than previously thought and amid the volatility stemming from the Libyan political crisis. The outage is the latest in a string of blackouts caused by technical problems at the exchange in recent years — including a full-day shutdown in September 2008 and a three-and-a-half-hour knockout in November 2009 — and comes just days after Borsa Italiana, the London exchange’s Milan platform, was hit by a five-hour blackout. “At a time of uncertainty in the markets, where traders are having to keep on their toes with the situation in Libya, the last thing they need is an unexpected halt to trading,” Joshua Raymond, market strategist at City Index, said.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
</rss>
