<rss>
	<item>
		<title>Hoping for Olympic Gold, Countries Build Up Rugby Sevens Teams</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>20 Feb 2012 15:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		It would make an excellent quiz question: Who is the reigning Olympic Games rugby champion? It is likely that not many people know the answer is the United States. In 1924 in Paris, the U.S. men won the gold by virtue of defeating France and Romania, who collected the silver and bronze medals. (Only three countries played.) Not long after, rugby was removed from the Olympic program. However, in 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, rugby — in its shortened sevens format — will return to the world’s biggest sporting event, and both men’s and women’s teams are set to compete. The rugby landscape now is a vastly different one from those Summer Games almost a century ago. For starters, the sport is no longer played just for “fun.” The majority of players competing in the highest echelons are paid to do so, and that is beginning to extend to the shortened, quicker format, where more and more countries are putting extra resources into their sevens squads.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Sony Rolls the Dice With Two New Tablets</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>31 Aug 2011 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Risk-taking is a rare thing among tablet makers. As far as operating systems are concerned (and assuming you’re not Apple), your company can try to go it alone, as RIM has done and H.P. tried to do. But most manufacturers have gotten on board the Android bandwagon. From a design standpoint, the options would appear to be even more limited, boiling down to how big or small you would like your rectangle to be.
 Sony, at least, is trying something different. The electronics maker announced on Wednesday that it will begin shipping two Android tablets — the company’s first — starting in September. The first model will be the Tablet S, a fairly conventional 9.4-inch tablet that will run on Android 3.1 (upgradeable to 3.2 later this year). Like many Android devices, this one will include special software and hardware from Sony intended to add a little razzle-dazzle to the Android experience. That includes DLNA compatibility, so you can “throw” sound and images to compatible devices wirelessly; a built-in infrared transmitter that allows the Tablet S to function as a supercharged universal remote; as well as access to music, video and book stores run by Sony. The Tablet S is Wi-Fi only and costs $499 for the 16 gigabyte model and $599 for the 32 gigabyte model. It will be presold starting Wednesday with delivery expected later in September. But it’s the other tablet in Sony’s stable, the Tablet P, that is considerably more interesting. Like a Nintendo DS, the Tablet P is a dual-screen device that folds like a clamshell. When closed, the Tablet P resembles a large sunglasses case. When opened, two 5.5-inch displays are revealed. Both displays are touch-sensitive, and can function either together, displaying a page across both screens (this is less than perfect, since there’s a break between screens to accommodate the hinge), or separately, showing an e-mail in-box on one screen, for example, and the content of a particular e-mail in another. The Tablet P will be sold through ATT, as it will be both Wi-Fi and 4G-compatible. The company did not disclose pricing and availability.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Red Mass Marks Start of Supreme Court Session</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>2 Oct 2011 17:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		In 58 years, the Red Mass, held the first Sunday of October at St. Matthew’s Cathedral in Washington to kick off the Supreme Court session, has gone from a token ritual to a power conclave. When the Mass started in 1953, there were no Catholic members of the Supreme Court. The service’s traditional “Catholic seat” had to be filled at the time by Justice Sherman Minton, a Protestant whose wife was Catholic. Today, there are six Catholic justices, three Jewish justices and, for the first time in history, no Protestant justices. On Sunday, the ceremony was attended by five of the Catholic justices — Chief Justice John Roberts and Justices Antonin Scalia, Clarence Thomas, Samuel A. Alito Jr. and Anthony Kennedy — plus Justice Stephen Breyer, who is Jewish. (Justices of other faiths sometimes attend as a sign of respect.) Justice Sonia Sotomayor, the sixth and least conservative Catholic on the court, did not attend. Neither did Justice Elena Kagan, who is Jewish, or Justice Ruth Bader Ginsberg, who came once and was so offended by the “outrageously anti-abortion” homily that she never returned. There was also a weighty Catholic contingent from the executive branch — the White House chief of staff Bill Daley, Secretary of Transportation Ray LaHood and Secretary of Defense Leon Panetta — listening to Archbishop Peter Sartain of Seattle give a homily emphasizing a quality that bickering politicians in Washington often
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>This Week’s Health Industry News</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>24 Jan 2011 10:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		The coming week is a busy one for the Food and Drug Administration. An advisory committee will discuss heart devices at meetings on Tuesday and Wednesday. The committee will first look at how the agency should classify external defibrillators, which the F.D.A. has been arguing should be more tightly regulated because they can malfunction. The next day, the committee is expected to review Abbott’s carotid stent system, RX Acculink. My colleague Duff Wilson takes a look at another coming F.D.A. decision on how to regulate electroconvulsive, or shock, therapy that is the subject of another advisory committee review at meetings at the end of the week. Duff’s article can be found in Monday’s paper. Investors can also look forward to a number of earnings results this week. Amgen reports on Monday, and Johnson Johnson on Tuesday. If it’s Wednesday, it must be WellPoint, following on the heels of fellow health insurer UnitedHealth Group’s strong results last week. Look for Bristol-Myers and Eli Lilly on Thursday. You will also probably hear more debate this week over whether the new health care law should be repealed, following last weeks’ vote by the Republican-controlled House to revoke the legislation. The Senate is likely to have a vote, or votes, on repeal, according to an article by our colleague in Washington, Edward Wyatt. No one is betting on a full-blown repeal, but you might see some tweaking of the legislation, along with much heated discussion. Make sure not to miss the article that ran on Sunday by another Washington colleague, Gardiner Harris, about the federal government’s efforts to spur drug development so as to have more new medicines. You might also want to take a glance at Monday’s USA Today story on federal regulators’ fight against health care fraud in which they recovered a record $2.5 billion. As always, let us know if there’s anything else to be on the watch for this week.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Amid Exodus From Libya, Europe Braces for Refugees</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>24 Feb 2011 08:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Frantic operations to evacuate foreigners from the widening chaos in Libya continued Thursday, and European officials were already looking toward the next challenge: coping with what could be a huge influx of refugees from across the Mediterranean. More than 10,000 people crowded into Tripoli’s main airport on Thursday, the Turkish Foreign Ministry said. Amateur video posted by the British newspaper The Independent showed desperate travelers filling the trash-strewn terminal and flowing out the doors into the roads. The scramble by foreigners to leave the country began several days ago, but the number of commercial flights could not keep up with demand. Many countries have been mobilizing military and chartered ships and planes. Some government-led evacuations were able to proceed Thursday, with two Greek ferries carrying about 4,500 Chinese workers departing from the eastern city of Benghazi. The United States Embassy said on its Web site that it was chartering a flight from Tripoli for Friday. Other efforts to remove American citizens have been frustrated, first when a chartered plane was denied permission to land and then when rough seas kept a chartered ferry from departing for Malta. Those on the ferry, which has been secured, were being given food and water, said Philip J. Crowley, a State Department spokesman. There were 285 passengers on board, including 167 Americans. The State Department said 40 members of the United States Embassy staff were on the vessel, which holds about 600 people. The State Department said roughly 6,000 United States citizens, most of them holding dual citizenship, were in Libya when the uprising against Col. Muammar el-Qaddafi began. “My understanding is that they would need the permission of the Libyan government to depart,” Mr. Crowley said during a news conference, referring to those with dual citizenship.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Storm Forces Markets to Remain Closed</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>29 Oct 2012 13:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Even in an era of widespread electronic trading, markets and those who tend to them are still proving vulnerable to the fury of a major hurricane. Stock markets in the United States will be closed again on Tuesday for a second day without trading as Hurricane Sandy’s approach intensified the wind and rain in the New York area. The New York Stock Exchange, the Nasdaq stock market and BATS Global Markets said in separate statements that they had agreed to close, after consulting with other exchanges and clients. The N.Y.S.E. added that it planned to operate on Wednesday, pending developments in weather conditions. The stoppage is the first time the markets have been closed for consecutive days because of weather since a blizzard forced the N.Y.S.E. to close for two days in 1888. And it remained the first unscheduled market closure since the Sept. 11 terrorist attacks. Markets in Europe and Asia were roughly flat on Monday. The FTSE 100 index closed down 0.2 percent, at 5,795, while the Hang Seng was down 0.2 percent at 21,511.05.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
</rss>
