<rss>
	<item>
		<title>Just Like Old Times for Thierry Henry</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>10 Jan 2012 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Sport is the theater of man’s often absurd dreams. At Arsenal, a few miles from Tottenham, Thierry Henry returned to English soccer Monday. Henry managed within 10 minutes what 22 younger athletes failed to do in 90. He rolled back the years. He scored the only goal in an F.A. Cup tie against Leeds United. It is almost five years since Henry performed like this for Arsenal. He is on borrowed time, loaned back to London for six weeks from his retirement team, the New York Red Bulls. “It’s weird,” Henry said after the game. “I never thought I was going to score for Arsenal again. I was on holiday in Mexico 15 days ago. I rejoin Arsenal as a fan.” Henry said he had answered the call because he loves Arsenal. Love is not often as sincere in modern soccer as this. Henry meant it, and he received love from the 59,615 fans. Some called his name even before he stripped for action. When Henry joined the play, he was kicked on the calf. He glowered in his French manner, then punished the perpetrator in his own way. Henry at 24 had exceptional pace. Henry at 34 has speed of mind. He created his space by disengaging, by moving stealthily away from his marker. Arsenal midfielder Alex Song spotted him and delivered the ball along the turf. With one dab of his foot, Henry had it under control. With one glance, he saw the goalkeeper advance. With one seemingly laconic stroke, he caressed the ball, delicately, deliberately around the goalie and low inside the far post. Henry has resumed his role and now has 227 career goals for Arsenal. Class is permanent
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Internet Gets Physical</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>17 Dec 2011 08:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		THE Internet likes you, really likes you. It offers you so much, just a mouse click or finger tap away. Go Christmas shopping, find restaurants, locate partying friends, tell the world what you’re up to. Some of the finest minds in computer science, working at start-ups and big companies, are obsessed with tracking your online habits to offer targeted ads and coupons, just for you. But now — nothing personal, mind you — the Internet is growing up and lifting its gaze to the wider world. To be sure, the economy of Internet self-gratification is thriving. Web start-ups for the consumer market still sprout at a torrid pace. And young corporate stars seeking to cash in for billions by selling shares to the public are consumer services — the online game company Zynga last week, and the social network giant Facebook, whose stock offering is scheduled for next year. As this is happening, though, the protean Internet technologies of computing and communications are rapidly spreading beyond the lucrative consumer bailiwick. Low-cost sensors, clever software and advancing computer firepower are opening the door to new uses in energy conservation, transportation, health care and food distribution. The consumer Internet can be seen as the warm-up act for these technologies. The concept has been around for years, sometimes called the Internet of Things or the Industrial Internet. Yet it takes time for the economics and engineering to catch up with the predictions. And that moment is upon us. Dr. Mike December 19, 2011
The Internet: Loves me, loves me not... Maybe I'm just a number or a digital ID?"All good" (maybe) that so much "smart technology" can...
Charles Jencks December 19, 2011 I can only assume that Steve Lohr is aware that much of what he mentions in the article has been online for quite some time. I imagine the... IndigNATION December 19, 2011 Wasn't there a movie about a computer system like this?What was it called?Skynet!Let's hope this doesn't turn into a similar plot... “We’re going to put the digital ‘smarts’ into everything,” said Edward D. Lazowska, a computer scientist at the University of Washington. These abundant smart devices, Dr. Lazowska added, will “interact intelligently with people and with the physical world.” The role of sensors — once costly and clunky, now inexpensive and tiny — was described this month in an essay in The New York Times by Larry Smarr, founding director of the California Institute for Telecommunications and Information Technology; he said the ultimate goal was “the sensor-aware planetary computer.”
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Democrats Seek to Impose Tougher Supreme Court Ethics</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>8 Sep 2011 18:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		House Democrats, seeking to capitalize on recent questions about the political leanings of several Supreme Court justices, are pushing for toughened ethics standards that would hold the justices on the high court to the same judicial requirements as federal judges. In a letter that is being sent Friday to House Judiciary Committee leaders, 43 Democrats called for a hearing on a bill that would require Supreme Court justices to follow the ethics requirements of the Judicial Conference Code of Conduct in withdrawing from cases where they may have a financial or political conflict. The justices now use the code for “guidance” but are not required to follow it. The bill, sponsored by Rep. Christopher S. Murphy, Democrat of Connecticut, would also require the justices to disclose publicly their reasons for any withdrawal from a case and would set up a process to review possible conflicts if a justice refuses to step aside. The notion of imposing higher ethics standards on the Supreme Court appears to be gaining momentum among House Democrats and outside legal scholars, but its prospects in the Republican-controlled House are still uncertain. The bill “would go a long way towards restoring the public’s confidence in the Supreme Court” after several recent controversies, the Democratic lawmakers said in the letter. An advance copy was provided to the New York Times. The Democrats singled out three conservative justices -– Antonin Scalia, Clarence Thomas, and Samuel Alito –- for “alarming reports” of their appearances at politically themed events.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Patterns: Heart Study Suggests Place Matters</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>21 Nov 2011 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		In the so-called stroke belt in the Southeast, cardiovascular disease rates are much higher than in the rest of the country. Scientists generally believe that is because people in the region have higher rates of such risk factors as smoking, obesity and diabetes. Now a large study, published in the November issue of PLoS One, suggests that there may be more to it than that. Using nationwide data on 26,029 healthy women whose average age was 53, researchers found significant geographical variations in inflammation as measured by blood levels of C-reactive protein and two other markers that significantly increase the risk for heart problems in women. Women in the Southeast and Appalachia had the highest levels, but none of the clinical and lifestyle risk factors for cardiovascular disease could account for the finding. Even after controlling for race, ethnicity, obesity, smoking, diabetes, exercise, cholesterol levels and blood pressure, the geographic variation in the inflammatory markers persisted. “Our research doesn’t answer why, but my guess is that it has something to do with economic differences between places,” said the lead author, Dr. Cheryl R. Clark, an assistant professor of medicine at Harvard University. “Place matters in questions of health,” she added, “and we’re trying to understand what some states might be doing differently from other states that might affect heart disease risk.”
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Protests Take Aim at Leader of Libya</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>16 Feb 2011 14:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		The protests sweeping the Middle East reached Libya on Wednesday, with demonstrations against its leader, Col. Muammar el-Qaddafi, reported in several cities. In Benghazi, Libya’s second-largest city, a crowd armed with gasoline bombs and rocks protested outside a government office to demand the release of a human rights advocate, Reuters and other news agencies reported. The demonstrators, estimated at several hundred to several thousand, marched to the city’s central square, where they clashed with riot police officers. In the city of Zentan, hundreds marched through the streets and set fire to security headquarters and a police station, according to The Associated Press. The A.P. also said that anti-Qaddafi demonstrations broke out in Al Beyda, east of Benghazi. In both cities, the protests were also spurred by the arrest of human rights advocates, news agencies reported. Protesters using social networking sites like Twitter and Facebook are calling for nationwide demonstrations on Thursday to demand Colonel Qaddafi’s ouster. Wednesday’s eruptions were highly unusual because Colonel Qaddafi, who has ruled Libya for four decades, commands a pervasive security apparatus to keep dissent in check. The unrest was not reported in Libya’s state-run media, which focused instead on rallies held in support of Colonel Qaddafi in Tripoli, the capital, and other cities. The tactic was reminiscent of pro-government demonstrations unleashed in Egypt and Yemen to counter unrest. Colonel Qaddafi also proposed a doubling of state employees’ salaries and released 110 suspected Islamic militants from jail, The A.P. reported. Libyan state television showed images of a pro-Qaddafi rally in Tripoli, where demonstrators chanted slogans critical of Al Jazeera, the Qatar-based satellite broadcaster that provided close coverage of the events in Tunisia and Egypt that have rattled autocratic leaders of the Arab world.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Procter, Colgate and Unilever Profit as Brands Sell Again</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>29 Apr 2010 11:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Brand-name consumer products companies, by cutting prices, introducing products and pumping up promotions, are starting to win back shoppers who traded down to store brands. Procter and Gamble, Colgate-Palmolive and Unilever all showed strong sales growth in Thursday’s quarterly report, although P. G.’s results were hurt by charges, including some from the American health care overhaul. Colgate was hit by Venezuela’s currency devaluation. While consumers are still minding their budgets, the rising sales are an encouraging, if tentative, sign of economic rebound after more than a year of steep shopper cuts. “These are companies that sell everyday household products,” said Jack Russo of Edward Jones, who covers Procter and Colgate. “Procter has been introducing products that have more of a value equation. I wouldn’t say that consumers are jumping back in on the premium products.” The three companies’ sales surged over all, particularly in emerging markets and after price cuts meant to lure consumers back from cheaper private label and store brands. Colgate shares rose 19 cents in afternoon trading but finished the day down 20 cents to $84, while Procter was off 97 cents, or 1.5 percent, to $62.20. Procter and Gamble is trying to combine brand strength with lower-price alternatives. The company, which makes Tide detergent and Pampers diapers, said revenue rose 7 percent, to $19.2 billion, while profit dipped 1 percent to $2.59 billion, or 83 cents a share, with a charge of 5 cents a share for costs from health care changes in its third fiscal quarter. Colgate-Palmolive, maker of Colgate toothpaste, Palmolive dishwashing liquid and Ajax cleanser, said revenue rose more than 9 percent, to $3.83 billion. But first-quarter earnings fell 30 percent, to $357 million, or 69 cents a share, after the company took a charge for the currency changes in Venezuela, an important South American market.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
</rss>
