<rss>
	<item>
		<title>Michigan Club Team’s Transition to the Big Time</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>10 Feb 2012 12:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		After defeating rival Michigan State last May, the Michigan men’s club lacrosse team gathered at midfield for what players thought would be a routine postgame talk. Instead, their longtime coach John Paul broke exciting news: Michigan had decided to make lacrosse a varsity sport. “Jaws dropped,” said Trevor Yealy, the club team’s senior co-captain last season. “We had heard rumors for so long, but we were finally doing it.” The college lacrosse world was ecstatic, too. Although women’s varsity teams have cropped up at high-profile Football Bowl Subdivision universities like Florida and Southern California in recent years, men’s programs have been elusive quarry. Michigan, which opens its inaugural varsity season Sunday, is one of 13 F.B.S. colleges with a men’s lacrosse team — and the first to add the sport since President Reagan took office. The expansion of Division I men’s lacrosse, which is not a revenue sport, at F.B.S. universities has been hindered largely by high overhead costs and Title IX compliance. Michigan leapt these hurdles with a grass-roots approach. Instead of starting a team from scratch, Michigan promoted its talented men’s club organization — which once went 50 games without a loss — to varsity. The Wolverines will face top Division I teams like Denver and North Carolina this spring with a roster full of former club players, including Yealy, now a fifth-year senior. Paul will stalk the sideline. More important, Michigan’s athletic department budget is shouldering little of the program’s cost. The men’s team and the new women’s squad that begins play in 2013 will be financed from the nearly $5 million raised by the club team in the last two years. This is not unprecedented in college sports, much less at Michigan. In 2000, the university promoted its men’s club soccer program to varsity. Last year, Penn State announced that its men’s and women’s club hockey teams would move to Division I, financed by an $88 million donation.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Facebook Offers to Sweeten Deal to Settle ‘Sponsored Stories’ Suit</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>9 Oct 2012 20:46:13 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Facebook says a form of advertising known as Sponsored Stories is its most promising money-maker. Sponsored Stories don’t seem like advertisements exactly; they are simply notices on your page that your friend X “likes” Y.  They cost virtually nothing to produce (X doesn’t get paid), and because they take up very little real estate, they can be easily shown on a mobile device, which is precisely where Facebook is struggling to make money But Sponsored Stories are also proving to be a legal headache for the company. Efforts to settle a class action lawsuit involving them have stumbled. Now, Facebook has offered to sweeten the deal, in effect offering to compensate millions of users whose names and pictures were used in a Sponsored Stories ad with $10 apiece.
The previous settlement offer, filed in federal court earlier this year, offered $10 million in plaintiff lawyers fees and another $10 million in charitable contributions to a dozen privacy research and advocacy groups. United States District Judge Richard Seeborg rejected that offer last August. He demanded proof that the dollar amounts had not been “plucked from thin air” and sought clarification on why there was no relief for the millions of Facebook users whose names and photographs had already been used in the advertisements. The revised settlement, filed Saturday and first reported by Reuters Monday, offers to split the $20 million differently. It would allow users to lay claim first – for $10 a piece. It would then disburse the remaining amount to plaintiffs lawyers and privacy-related charities. The court filing does not explain how the lawyers fees will be calculated. It indicates that 125 million Facebook users have been affected by the practice. As part of the proposed deal, Facebook has already agreed to better inform users about sponsored stories and to allow people under 18 to opt out of the function.
A Facebook spokesman reiterated what the company had said last August, when the first settlement offer was rejected by the court, calling the revised offer “fair, reasonable, and adequate.”
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Court Puts Hold on Arizona’s Campaign Fund</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>8 Jun 2010 13:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		The Supreme Court on Tuesday barred officials in Arizona from providing matching funds to candidates for state office who accept public financing, a program meant to help them keep pace with the unlimited spending of candidates who don’t take public financing. In an unsigned order without noted dissents, the justices reinstated a trial court injunction that had been stayed by the United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit, in San Francisco. The Supreme Court’s own stay will probably remain in effect through both the primary in August and the general election in November.  The court instructed the candidates challenging the matching fund law to file a prompt appeal.  If the court agrees to hear the case, as is likely, it is unlikely to be argued and decided before the November election. The Arizona law matches money spent by candidates for state office who do not accept public financing — and therefore can raise and spend without limits — by providing equivalent public money for those who take the public money and face limits. A federal judge said those matching funds would place an unconstitutional burden on the First Amendment rights of candidates relying on private funds.  The Supreme Court has been skeptical of efforts to level the financial playing field in elections. Richard L. Hasen, a professor at Loyola Law School in Los Angeles, said Tuesday’s order did not bode well for either the Arizona law or for campaign finance regulation efforts more generally.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Airstrikes in Libya; Questions Back Home</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>20 Mar 2011 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		President Obama’s decision to authorize military strikes against Libya exposed him to another set of political crosscurrents from right and left and further complicated his plan to keep his agenda focused on the domestic economy. As the air assault continued for a second day in Libya, Mr. Obama sought to project an air of normalcy and play down the role of the United States. He continued his visit to South America without altering his schedule, and barely mentioned, in a televised speech from Brazil, that allied forces were engaged in another military intervention in a Muslim world. But some Republicans suggested that Mr. Obama had waited too long to protect the rebels against Col. Muammar el-Qaddafi, had been too reluctant to employ American power and had not clearly explained the objectives of the action. Their comments maintained a pattern of attacking Mr. Obama as a weak leader at home and abroad. “I don’t know what finally got the president to act, but I’m very worried that we’re taking the back seat rather than a leadership role,” Senator Lindsey Graham, Republican of South Carolina, said on “Fox News Sunday.” The action against Colonel Qaddafi’s forces drew support from many Democrats, but also concern. A coalition of liberal Democrats voiced objections, arguing that the president overstepped his authority by not seeking Congressional approval before authorizing the airstrikes. The airstrikes against the Libyan government crystallized the complexities and risks of addressing the multifaceted uprisings in the Arab world and could leave the administration stretched thin as its heads toward a budget showdown with Republicans in Congress and a decision by summer about how quickly to reduce the American military presence in Afghanistan. Even for a president whose term has been filled with unforeseen events, the commencement of a military action that held the risk of becoming a third war at a time of upheaval in the Middle East created a new dynamic whose consequences were especially hard to predict.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>In a Surprise, Car Sales Start New Year Strongly</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>1 Feb 2012 10:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		New-vehicle sales in the United States were unexpectedly strong in January, an early sign that the auto industry could have its best year since 2007, carmakers and analysts said Wednesday. Sales increased 11.4 percent from January 2011, according to the research firm Autodata. The industry’s annual selling rate, an important measure of its health, climbed to 14.18 million, the highest in more than two years. The Chrysler Group beat forecasts with a 44 percent increase in monthly sales, and Honda posted its first year-over-year gain since it began struggling with inventory shortages after last year’s earthquake and tsunami in Japan. Honda’s sales were up 8.8 percent. Toyota, Ford Motor and Nissan each reported modest increases, while Hyundai and Kia set January records. Volkswagen reported a 39.5 percent gain, its best January since 1974. In contrast, General Motors said sales were down 6.1 percent from January 2011, when sales were inflated by big discounts offered after the company’s public stock sale. Sales of G.M.’s plug-in hybrid, the Chevrolet Volt, also fell from December after a government investigation into the potential for its battery to catch fire after a crash received widespread publicity. Small cars were among the biggest factors driving the increase. Car sales rose 19.9 percent, while truck sales increased 3.7 percent. “This is healthy, this is good. It’s sustainable,” said Jesse Toprak, vice president of industry trends and insight at the automotive research Web site TrueCar.com. “It’s going to be another year of recovery where we have a very good chance of getting to that magic 14 million number.”
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
</rss>
