<rss>
	<item>
		<title>2010 Online, by the Numbers</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>14 Jan 2011 07:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Think your e-mail in-box is overflowing because you get dozens of e-mails a day? That’s nothing: Internet users collectively sent 107 trillion (yes, that’s with a “t”) messages in 2010. Granted, a large percentage of those messages were spam, but that’s still a lot of e-mail. And that’s only a tiny slice of the bits that flew around the Internet last year. In an effort to figure out how many e-mails, videos, photos and other digital stuff we collectively uploaded and passed around the Web in 2010, Pingdom, an Internet monitoring service, corralled a number of research reports and company statistics to create a picture of the year in online stuff. Of course, e-mail is just one piece of the digital pie. Below are a few highlights. The number of people online naturally keeps growing. As of June 2010 there were 1.97 billion Internet users worldwide, with 825.1 million of them in Asia, 475.1 million in Europe and 266.2 million in North America. Social media continues to grow at a fast pace. An estimated 25 billion Twitter messages were sent through the service last year, and the company added over 100 million users. Facebook also saw record numbers, reaching 600 million users. It’s amazing to think that Facebook started 2010 with 350 million users. As for the things people are sharing online: Internet users sent 360 billion pieces of content across Facebook over the year, which included links, notes and photos. Flickr, just one of a number of popular photo sites, saw 130 million photos uploaded to the site each month.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Vacuum After Qaddafi</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>27 Feb 2011 23:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Col. Muammar el-Qaddafi sounded a resonant warning, exhorting his dwindling supporters toward civil war. “At the appropriate time, we will open the arms depots so all Libyans and tribes will be armed,” he shouted into a handheld microphone at dusk Friday, “so that Libya turns red with fire!” That is indeed the fear of those watching the carnage in Libya, not least because Colonel Qaddafi spent the last 40 years hollowing out every single institution that might challenge his authority. Unlike neighboring Egypt and Tunisia, Libya lacks the steadying hand of a military to buttress a collapsing government. It has no Parliament, no trade unions, no political parties, no civil society, no nongovernmental agencies. Its only strong ministry is the state oil company. The fact that some experts think the next government might be built atop the oil ministry underscores the paucity of options. The worst-case scenario should the rebellion topple him, and one that concerns American counterterrorism officials, is that of Afghanistan or Somalia — a failed state where Al Qaeda or other radical groups could exploit the chaos and operate with impunity. But there are others who could step into any vacuum, including Libya’s powerful tribes or a pluralist coalition of opposition forces that have secured the east of the country and are tightening their vise near the capital. Optimists hope that the opposition’s resolve persists; pessimists worry that unity will last only until Colonel Qaddafi is gone, and that a bloody witch hunt will ensue afterward. “It is going to be a political vacuum,” said Lisa Anderson, the president of the American University in Cairo and a Libya expert, suggesting that chances are high for a violent period of score-settling. “I don’t think it is likely that people will want to put down their weapons and go back to being bureaucrats.”
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Growing Business of Online Reputation Management</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>4 Apr 2011 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Over the weekend I wrote an article for Sunday Styles about new Web services that deal with a new problem — online reputation management. These businesses have cropped up over the past few years to address one major negative aspect of our online world: As quickly as images, blog posts, commentary, status updates and photos are posted on the Web, they are replicated by algorithms and search engines, and dissipate like an airborne virus. The Internet is a permanent record of our past, and it never forgets anything posted online. The new crop of services help people erase negative or unflattering content from the Web — sometimes put there by themselves, and in other instances, put there by someone else. They work with any number of clients, large and small. In the article, for example, I wrote about some of them: a physiologist whose name had been smeared online, celebrities, banker, lawyers, and college students who are trying to remove unwanted drunken party photos posted in their youth. As I interviewed executives at a number of companies that offer these services, including Reputation.com and Metal Rabbit Media, I consistently heard warnings that this is only the beginning of a time where everyone will be forced to manage their image online. “I believe that we are heading into an era where there will be the equivalent of a WikiLeaks moment for everyone,” said Michael Fertik, the chief executive of Reputation.com, which is based in Redwood City, Calif. “Every two weeks we find new and novel ways that people can be harmed on the Web.” Mr. Fertik warned that the Web is changing so quickly, with new social services popping up almost daily, that it has become impossible for people to understand what they have shared online in the past, and if it can affect them negatively later. In most instances, he said, it will.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
</rss>
