<rss>
    <item>
        <title>Libyan Rebels Defiant but in Disarray, as Qaddafi’s Forces Gain Momentum</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=204fe7d2a61b5a03a9b515fe695816b9
        </link>
        <pubDate>11 Mar 2011 05:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                Forces loyal to Col. Muammar el-Qaddafi trumpeted their retaking of the rebellious city of Zawiyah near the capital and pressed toward the country’s largest refinery here Friday, as rebel lines began to crumble before an onslaught of airstrikes, tank and artillery fire, and relentless siege. Plumes of smoke turned clear skies a somber gray after warplanes struck a fuel-storage tank at the refinery and fighters set a dozen tires on fire in a futile attempt to provide cover. Rumors tumbled through dwindling crowds of fighters that spies were among them, and volleys of antiaircraft fire seemed aimed more at lifting people’s flagging spirits than at bringing down the warplanes that sent rebels scurrying for cover behind sand dunes. The setbacks were the clearest sign yet of the momentum Colonel Qaddafi’s government has seized as it tries to crush the greatest challenge to his nearly 42 years of idiosyncratic rule. Through fear and intimidation, he has silenced protests in Tripoli, ravaged Zawiyah, where the rebels had once delivered the revolt to his doorstep, and brought himself within striking distance of a series of strategic oil towns in eastern Libya. “We’re exposed here,” said Yusuf Ibrahim, a lieutenant colonel from Benghazi who deserted to the rebel ranks and has tried to coordinate defenses here. “There are no trenches. Do you see any trenches here? This is a wide-open space, and anything is possible.” “This isn’t an army,” he added. The advances of Colonel Qaddafi’s forces raised questions of what strategy he might be pursuing in the aftermath of the three-week revolt. Eastern Libya remains tentatively but almost uniformly in opposition hands, and tens of thousands turned out for Friday Prayer, where a cleric urged patience with the revolt. But with the fall of Ras Lanuf and Zawiyah, Colonel Qaddafi is on the verge of retaking installations that refine nearly 90 percent of Libya’s oil production, pumped from the largest reserves in Africa.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Pakistan Prime Minister Says No Plans to Dismiss Military Chiefs</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=2e7d59ac6bcf55b13f1819bb47664410
        </link>
        <pubDate>26 Dec 2011 06:06:06 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                Prime Minister Yousaf Raza Gilani on Monday denied news reports that he was planning to dismiss the country’s army and intelligence commanders in the aftermath of tensions that have emerged over a controversial memo that claims the civilian government had sought American help in constraining the powerful Pakistani military. Last week, in an unusual outburst, Mr. Gilani had warned of conspiracies against the civilian government, accused the commanders of acting as “state within a state” and reminded them they were accountable to the parliament. The tone of his remarks suggested that dismissals were possible — the opposite of the message he sought to convey on Monday. Speculation about the government’s intentions dismiss the two commanders — Gen. Ashfaq Parvez Kayani, the head of the army, and Lt. Gen Ahmad Shuja Pasha, the head of Pakistan’s intelligence service, were fueled by news reports in the stridently anti-American press in Pakistan, where many people view the United States as an arrogant adversary instead of an ally. Any hints of clandestine collaboration between the civilian government and Washington represents potential political damage to Mr. Gilani and the president, Asif Ali Zardari, who is already unpopular. On Monday, The News, an English language daily known for aggressive reporting against the Mr. Gilani’s Pakistan Peoples Party, the majority party that runs the government, published a report titled “Is sacking of Generals Kayani and Pasha on the cards?” The speculative article, which carried no byline, claimed that United States officials had encouraged the civilian government to dismiss the two generals. The article said their removal would make it easier for the United States to impose its “desired strategy in the region”, a veiled reference to the Pakistani military’s differences with the United States over the conflict in neighboring Afghanistan. Denying any such plans, Mr. Gilani also rejected speculation that tensions even existed between the military and his civilian government. “How can we run a government if there is any tension?,” Mr. Gilani said in response to a question during a news conference at the prime minister’s house in the capital. “There is no clash between the government and the military.”
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Ryan’s Remarks on Patriots Move Jets to Shrug</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=57980bd5dfec241237ae577966ba234f
        </link>
        <pubDate>11 Jan 2011 07:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                On Tuesday, most of the Jets claimed they had not heard the latest headlines generated by Coach Rex Ryan, despite the national attention his comments generated. Ryan spent 20 minutes Monday afternoon setting his agenda for the week. He boiled the Jets’ playoff game Sunday against New England down to one element, the head coaches, himself versus Bill Belichick. It made for a good story. If only it were true. Relayed the story line, offensive tackle D’Brickashaw Ferguson sighed, shook his head, then buried his head in his hands. He did not have a problem with what Ryan said. In fact, he said he respected that his coach appeared to shoulder more of the expectations, or at least tried to. Even if he did not necessarily agree, Ferguson placed the comments under the category of Rex Ryan being Rex Ryan. His teammates agreed. “It’s who he is, man,” Ferguson said. “It’s his personality. He’s been consistent every week. It’s not like he’s pretending for reporters, and then behind closed doors, he’s saying something totally different. The same thing he says to you, he says to us.” Cornerback Dwight Lowery took that reasoning one step further. He said players stuck to routines throughout the season. Those routines differ among players, based on how they want to prepare, what makes them comfortable, what worked in the past. Ryan, Lowery said, conducts his own routine. News conferences are a part of that. “That’s part of his preparation,” Lowery said. “There’s a little bit of gamesmanship in how he does it.” Asked to elaborate on what he viewed as gamesmanship, Lowery continued: “It’s really about what you do. I don’t think he talks to talk. He speaks from his heart. Sometimes, there’s a misconception about that. People think that he’s being cocky, or just talking to talk. He says it because he believes it. Or he wants to.”
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Calculating Playoff Odds for Jets and Giants</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=131f63b962899e94352bf51b8d63830b
        </link>
        <pubDate>24 Dec 2011 08:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                “There’s some more important things that go into it, because basically, you’re out of the playoffs if you lose this game, either team is.” Rex Ryan, Jets coach, earlier this week. Ryan has proved to be somewhat unreliable in his playoff math. The Giants and the Jets can still make the playoffs with a loss today; the Giants would be in worse shape. Heading into today’s game, according to NFL-Forecast.com, the Jets have a 37.9 percent chance of reaching the playoffs, and the Giants a 35.2 percent chance. An important caveat: As the site states, “Individual game predictions that are the basis of the playoff race simulations are based on the team efficiency ratings at Advanced NFL Stats.” Advanced NFL Stats has the Giants as the eighth-best team in the N.F.L., and the Jets as the 16th best. Another site, Football Outsiders, has it roughly in the reverse order, with the Jets rated ninth and the Giants 14th. Accordingly, Football Outsiders gives the Jets  a 45.4 percent chance of advancing to the postseason and the Giants a 26.6 percent chance. So a key factor in the playoff probability odds is which team is thought to be better. In other words: Who is going to win today’s Giants-Jets game? Luckily, we can toss out the numbers in a few hours because we’re about to find out on the field. Here’s the A.F.C. playoff odds picture before the Texans-Colts game. Go to NFL-Forecast.com for the rest of the charts.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Calculating Playoff Odds for Jets and Giants</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=8cc91eee006394a796405d118ed2dc55
        </link>
        <pubDate>24 Dec 2011 08:08:08 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                “There’s some more important things that go into it, because basically, you’re out of the playoffs if you lose this game, either team is.” Rex Ryan, Jets coach, earlier this week. Ryan has proved to be somewhat unreliable in his playoff math. The Giants and the Jets can still make the playoffs with a loss today; the Giants would be in worse shape. Heading into today’s game, according to NFL-Forecast.com, the Jets have a 37.9 percent chance of reaching the playoffs, and the Giants a 35.2 percent chance. An important caveat: As the site states, “Individual game predictions that are the basis of the playoff race simulations are based on the team efficiency ratings at Advanced NFL Stats.” Advanced NFL Stats has the Giants as the eighth-best team in the N.F.L., and the Jets as the 16th best. Another site, Football Outsiders, has it roughly in the reverse order, with the Jets rated ninth and the Giants 14th. Accordingly, Football Outsiders gives the Jets  a 45.4 percent chance of advancing to the postseason and the Giants a 26.6 percent chance. So a key factor in the playoff probability odds is which team is thought to be better. In other words: Who is going to win today’s Giants-Jets game? Luckily, we can toss out the numbers in a few hours because we’re about to find out on the field. Here’s the A.F.C. playoff odds picture before the Texans-Colts game. Go to NFL-Forecast.com for the rest of the charts.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Thursday’s Matchup: Browns Continue to Drop the Ball</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=f2f832a5c7ab1ef7cdce5b33be410adf
        </link>
        <pubDate>7 Dec 2011 09:09:09 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                The Browns’ signature play this season has been the dropped pass. Browns receivers have dropped 35 passes, the highest figure in the league, according to Stats LLC. They have collectively dropped more passes than all but one of their receivers has caught. Greg Little leads the team with 15 drops, and few were borderline cases of an off-target pass glancing off his outstretched fingertips. Little’s hands and stomach seem to magnetically repel footballs. Running back Montario Hardesty is more culpable than Little, who at least leads the team with 50 receptions. Hardesty has 12 catches and 6 drops, most of them on dump-off passes that travel with all the distance and velocity of a stuffed bunny tossed to a toddler. If the Browns’ receivers had caught half the passes they dropped this season, Colt McCoy’s completion percentage would be nearly 4 points higher, and more important, the Browns may have won close games against the Rams and the Bengals. If the Steelers beat the Browns, they can clinch a playoff berth on Sunday with losses by the Bengals, the Jets and the Titans; or losses by the Bengals, the Jets, the Raiders and the Broncos; or losses by the Bengals, the Titans, the Broncos and the Raiders; or losses by the Bengals, the Jets, the Navy Midshipmen, the Nashville Predators, the Georgia Tech men’s basketball team and Shaun White in snowboarding at the Winter Dew Tour Nike Open. (That final list may not be accurate.) With a list of clinching requirements that convoluted, there is only one thing the Steelers can do on Sunday: party at Troy Polamalu’s house with the TV tuned to the NFL RedZone channel!
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
</rss>
