<rss>
    <item>
        <title>Iran Invites Some Nations, Not U.S., for Nuclear Tour</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
        </link>
        <pubDate>4 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                Iran has invited Russia, China and several European Union members to visit its nuclear facilities this month, but pointedly snubbed the United States, European diplomats said on Monday. Tehran confirmed on Tuesday that it had offered the invitation to show what Ramin Mehmanparast, an Iranian Foreign Ministry spokesman, called transparency and “Tehran’s goodwill” on its nuclear program. The invitation — which seemed calculated to divide the alliance of nations opposed to Iran’s nuclear ambitions before the next round of negotiations over the program — was swiftly dismissed by the United States. “It’s a clever ploy, but it’s not a substitute for Iran’s responsibilities to the I.A.E.A.,” said the State Department spokesman, Philip J. Crowley, referring to the International Atomic Energy Agency, which has been locked in an increasingly tense standoff with the Iranian government over its enrichment of uranium. “It won’t draw international attention away from the issues regarding Iran’s nuclear program,” Mr. Crowley added, noting that its enrichment activities violated six United Nations Security Council resolutions. The European diplomats said the invitation was not likely to be accepted, if at all, until after the next round of negotiations, expected to be held in Istanbul at the end of this month. “This is something that in principle could be interesting, but not before the next round of talks,” said one diplomat, speaking on condition of anonymity to discuss the confidential deliberations. “This seems like Iranian tactics: they would like to put up a smokescreen and link things that can’t be linked.”
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Rebels’ Sudden Success Sends European Backers Scrambling</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=ca797ad85787cab96de30cf5f22bee29
        </link>
        <pubDate>22 Aug 2011 01:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                The apparent collapse of Col. Muammar el-Qaddafi’s security forces is at least a partial victory for President Nicolas Sarkozy of France and Prime Minister David Cameron of Britain, who pushed the Security Council and then the NATO alliance into vital military support for the rebels. But few among the Western countries and their allies anticipated the speed of the demise of the Qaddafi government, and they are now scrambling during the August vacation and the holy month of Ramadan to put together a post-conflict plan for Libya. “How it ends is a determinant of what happens,” a senior Western diplomat said. “There is a lot of back and forth about where to go.” To that end, France has called an urgent meeting of the so-called contact group for Libya next week in Paris, and Mr. Sarkozy has invited Mahmoud Jibril, the prime minister of the rebel government, to attend. The group was not supposed to meet until the United Nations General Assembly convened next month, but “there’s a lot to figure out,” a senior Western diplomat said. “The Libyan people need to be in charge; The N.T.C. has to do it,” the diplomat said, referring to the rebel government, the Transitional National Council. “It’s not for the international community, let alone NATO, to tell them what to do.” NATO itself has already ruled out putting any of its troops on the ground in Libya, the NATO diplomat emphasized, though he conceded that individual countries might choose to do so, if invited. NATO itself, he said, would consider any role that the Libyan rebel leaders or the United Nations requested, but preferred not to have foreign troops on liberated Libyan territory. Still, there is significant concern about reprisals and score-settling, said François Heisbourg of the Foundation for Strategic Research in Paris, a Defense Ministry adviser. “It’s less about individuals than about tribes, that this tribe was for Qaddafi and this one rebelled, and there were some signs of that in the Nafusah Mountains. That’s a major danger in humanitarian and political terms.”
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Yemen President Apologizes to the White House</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=d5801a11f552ec1e88fb6976e1a9674a
        </link>
        <pubDate>2 Mar 2011 02:02:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                President Ali Abdullah Saleh of Yemen called the White House on Wednesday to express “regret for misunderstandings” over remarks he had made accusing the United States and Israel of fomenting unrest in the Middle East, the administration announced in a statement. Mr. Saleh, who has faced widening calls in Yemen to relinquish power, offered his regrets to John O. Brennan, President Obama’s top counterterrorism adviser, and said he was committed to political reform in Yemen, according to the statement. The administration had played down the remarks by Mr. Saleh, an American ally in the fight against terrorism, with officials saying off the record on Tuesday that they assumed the beleaguered president was trying to score points at home by attacking the United States and Israel. The statement on Wednesday said Mr. Brennan had encouraged Mr. Saleh to continue with his “constructive outreach” to the opposition. Opposition parties on Monday refused the president’s offer to join a unity government. On Wednesday, however, the parties were meeting with the president late into the night to see if they could devise some political compromise. The mainstream opposition parties have expressed their wish for Mr. Saleh to step down in the next several months, rather than in 2013 as he has said he would. They also have been urging him to remove his sons from powerful posts to try to ensure they do not seek the presidency. It is unclear if the protesters who have taken to Yemen’s streets would recognize any compromise worked out between the mainstream political parties and Mr. Saleh. The demonstrators, many of them young, have been calling for the president to step down immediately. The Youth Revolution Coalition, organizers of a continuing sit-in the capital, Sana, said, “We condemn all attempts to seek to circumvent the clear objective of our revolution and overthrowing the regime.”
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Hezbollah Leader Backs Syrian President in Public</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=715ea13c0d348c41eec0ea4f2460f476
        </link>
        <pubDate>2 Mar 2011 03:03:03 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                President Ali Abdullah Saleh of Yemen called the White House on Wednesday to express “regret for misunderstandings” over remarks he had made accusing the United States and Israel of fomenting unrest in the Middle East, the administration announced in a statement. Mr. Saleh, who has faced widening calls in Yemen to relinquish power, offered his regrets to John O. Brennan, President Obama’s top counterterrorism adviser, and said he was committed to political reform in Yemen, according to the statement. The administration had played down the remarks by Mr. Saleh, an American ally in the fight against terrorism, with officials saying off the record on Tuesday that they assumed the beleaguered president was trying to score points at home by attacking the United States and Israel. The statement on Wednesday said Mr. Brennan had encouraged Mr. Saleh to continue with his “constructive outreach” to the opposition. Opposition parties on Monday refused the president’s offer to join a unity government. On Wednesday, however, the parties were meeting with the president late into the night to see if they could devise some political compromise. The mainstream opposition parties have expressed their wish for Mr. Saleh to step down in the next several months, rather than in 2013 as he has said he would. They also have been urging him to remove his sons from powerful posts to try to ensure they do not seek the presidency. It is unclear if the protesters who have taken to Yemen’s streets would recognize any compromise worked out between the mainstream political parties and Mr. Saleh. The demonstrators, many of them young, have been calling for the president to step down immediately. The Youth Revolution Coalition, organizers of a continuing sit-in the capital, Sana, said, “We condemn all attempts to seek to circumvent the clear objective of our revolution and overthrowing the regime.”
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Suicide Bomber Strikes Iraq Police Station</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=9cbac080199a4d51b5df4d8e01f655dc
        </link>
        <pubDate>21 Feb 2011 04:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                A suicide bomber on Monday detonated a truck packed with explosives outside a police headquarters just north of Samarra, killing 12 officers and wounding 20 others, a local official and a law enforcement official said. The attack demonstrated that the police and security forces remain a target of insurgents despite the significant drop in violence across Iraq in the past year, and highlighted the tenuous security situation in and around Samarra, a predominantly Sunni city 60 miles north of Baghdad that is home to a Shiite shrine. Around 9:30 a.m., the bomber rammed the truck through a checkpoint at the headquarters in Qasr al-Ashiq, five miles from Samarra. The bomber then detonated the truck near a crowd of officers, said the local official, Mohamed E’laian, who heads the security committee for Salahuddin Province. “I was standing at the front of the compound where the bar was located and suddenly a white pickup truck filled with empty chicken cages got closer to us,” said Mohamed Hillan Athab, a 35-year-old police officer stationed at the headquarters. “First, we thought, he is a farmer and lost his way. But then he drove faster, and once he got close he detonated the car.” Mr. Athab added: “It was a huge explosion. I didn’t feel anything at that moment, then I was at the hospital.” Another police officer said he tried to stop the truck by shooting at it. “We opened fire on him with pistols but he drove faster and hit the front bar and then blew himself up,” said the police officer, who spoke on the condition of anonymity because he was not authorized to speak with journalists. A battalion of emergency police officers from the southern city of Amara was stationed at the headquarters. Officers from the predominantly Shiite cities in Iraq’s south often travel to Samarra to bolster security during Shiite pilgrimages to the city’s golden dome, one of Iraq’s most revered Shiite shrines. The dome was destroyed by insurgents in 2006, setting off months of violence between Shiites and Sunnis in which tens of thousands of people were killed. The recent pilgrimages, which commemorated the death of the imam Hassan al-Askari, for whom the mosque is named, were marked by violence. On Feb. 10, a car bomb exploded near a procession of pilgrims south of Samarra, killing nine people, including one child, and wounding dozens more.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
</rss>
