<rss>
    <item>
        <title>Jason Garrett Too Cautious in Cowboys’ Defeat</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=2d714d1cb5cc6f3d0c2b9be19089a6ae
        </link>
        <pubDate>5 Dec 2011 10:10:10 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                Forget that the regular-season overtime rules prevented the Cowboys from even touching the ball after regulation of a 19-13 loss at Arizona – that was merely karmic justice. Any coach that mismanages timeouts and field position as spectacularly as Dallas Coach Jason Garrett did in the final minutes deserves to lose. First, Garrett seemingly iced his own kicker by calling a timeout just before Dan Bailey’s 49-yard field goal on what would have been the game’s final play. (Bailey made the initial kick, but couldn’t repeat it.) Analyzing timeout usage as it pertains to a kicker’s rhythm is like analyzing how your day might have been different if you’d only brushed your teeth three minutes earlier. It’s a fruitless practice that’s all hindsight and presumption. Garrett’s biggest mistake was actually made before Bailey’s kick. When the Cowboys got the ball to the Arizona 31-yard line, they had 31 seconds remaining and two timeouts. Instead of using one of those timeouts, they slowly lined up so that Tony Romo could kill the clock with seven seconds left. They were setting up the game-winning field goal…from 49 yards away! It was almost as if Garrett owed the Fox broadcast a favor. Instead of going for an easier shot at a win, he went for the drama. Another coach might have tried to pick up another 10 or 12 yards. Garrett was content with the Scott Norwood range. He defended his clock management, saying: “We very well could have taken a timeout there. We felt like we were in field-goal range. We have yard lines that we use as guidelines before the game. We felt like we were in range at that point.” All that means is that the bad decision was made before the game, rather than in the heat of the moment. Extra point Brian Burke of Advanced NFL Stats weighs in: “There is no such thing as field goal range, except in the most technical and useless sense. Closer is always better.”
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Adu Returns to M.L.S.</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=58ac7e841afd61bbab776a18207cb22c
        </link>
        <pubDate>11 Aug 2011 11:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                Freddy Adu is coming back to Major League Soccer. The Philadelphia Union is expected to announce his acquisition on Friday. Adu, now 22, signed with the league at age 14 in 2004. He will be reunited with Peter Nowak, his coach at D.C. United. Nowak has the Union in second place in the Eastern Conference in the team’s second year in existence. Since leaving M.L.S. in 2007 and signing with Benfica of Portugal for a $2 million transfer fee, Adu has led an itinerant soccer life, playing on loan for teams in France (Monaco), Portugal (Belenenses), Greece (Aris) and most recently in the Turkish second division (Caykur Rizespor). He had one year remaining on his contract with Benfica. After a two-year absence from the United States senior national team, Adu was included in the team for June’s Concacaf Gold Cup, and played well in the semifinal against Panama and in the team’s 4-2 loss to Mexico in the tournament final. Adu was in Philadelphia for the United States match against Mexico, a 1-1 tie, on Wednesday night, but did not dress for the game. Adu was introduced to the news media on Friday, and said he was eager to get back on the field. His decision signifies an immediate reunion with Adu and Union manager Peter Nowak. Adu signed his professional contract with D.C. United at the age of 14 and spent three seasons with Nowak from 2004-06, including winning the MLS Cup in 2004. From the A.P.: The Union (8-5-9) play host to FC Dallas (12-6-6) on Saturday night, and enter the match just one point behind the Columbus Crew (9-7-7) for first place in the Eastern Conference. “I think I’m a better player,” Adu said, “than I was when I left MLS four years ago.” Though that doesn’t mean he will start on Saturday. Nowak certainly realizes his talent level, without question. But there’s chemistry to develop, and a learning curve, as well. “Of course, we’re looking to play Freddy,” Nowak said. “I know he’s ready to go. We have another 20 guys in the locker room ready to play as well.”
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>GOAL; M.L.S. Playoffs Bring Second Chances and Hectic Schedules</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=0b11ee2aedadfe6589490dc97322893f
        </link>
        <pubDate>11 Oct 2011 12:12:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                There are many things Thierry Henry has come to terms with since joining the Red Bulls from Barcelona last year. But Major League Soccer's playoff system will never be one of them. ''I will never get used to it; in Europe, Los Angeles would be champions,'' Henry said Monday after a training session at Montclair State. After missing last Thursday's latest must-win win against Philadelphia after receiving a red card in the previous game, Henry and the Red Bulls are preparing for Wednesday night's playoff opener against Dallas in Frisco, Tex. ''You fight all season like the Galaxy, but rules are rules,'' he said. ''You have to adapt to it. I guess it can make things more exciting, but I will never get used to it.'' In Henry's eyes, the Red Bulls will ''have to do something amazing'' if they hope to challenge for the league championship, a run that would include four games, three on the road, before landing in MLS Cup '11 in Carson, Calif., on Nov. 20. Under the revamped playoff system, 10 teams qualify for the M.L.S. postseason: the top three teams in each conference plus the next four teams (wild cards) with the most points. The Red Bulls squeaked in as wild card No. 4. If they defeat Dallas, the Red Bulls will cross over to the Western Conference bracket and play the Galaxy (the league's No. 1 team over all with 67 points) in a home-and-away, total-goals series beginning Sunday at Red Bull Arena in Harrison, N.J. In the other wild-card pairing, Columbus will play at Colorado, with the winner advancing to play Sporting Kansas City. The two other conference semifinal matches have Seattle facing Real Salt Lake in the West and Philadelphia playing Houston in the East. Unlike the semifinal series, the conference finals are one-game affairs. It might be a curious systems, but it is the only one M.L.S. has got, for now. The schedule, for all teams, is daunting and compressed, with three rounds to be played in 12 days (Wednesday through Nov. 6). The league will take time off during FIFA's international game days the next week. The Red Bulls enter the postseason after an up-and-down season in which they had a league-record 16 draws. But they have won three of their last five games (3-1-1) and could be a dangerous opponent.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Czechs Grab Point With Late Goal in Scotland</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=f3ceaa955e13d6399f5be4e6e0004b59
        </link>
        <pubDate>3 Sep 2011 13:13:13 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                A late penalty by Michal Kadlek gave the Czech Republic a 2-2 draw with Scotland in Glasgow on Saturday to keep it on course for a playoff spot for the 2012 European championship. Scotland seemed on the verge of a crucial victory when Darren Fletcher scored with eight minutes to go. But the Czechs salvaged a point when Kadlek blasted his spot kick into the roof of the net after Danny Wilson was judged to have tripped the substitute Jan Rezek in the penalty area in the 90th minute. The world champion Spain is the commanding leader in Group 1 with 15 points from five games, while the Czechs remain in second with 10 points from six matches. Scotland moved up to third with 5 points from five matches. CAMEROON CRUSIES Cameroon routed Mauritius, 6-0, in Younde to revive its chances of qualifying for next year’s African Cup of Nations. Cameroon scored all six goals in the second half after Mauritius put up a stubborn defense for the first 45 minutes. Midfielder Leoni Kweke finally broke the deadlock with a hard shot right after the break, and Mathew Nbuta added the second in the 62nd. The captain Samuel Eto’o converted a penalty in the 70th and Eric Choupo-Moting added two late goals. The win gave Cameroon 8 points from five games in Group E, but it still trails the leader Senegal by 2 points with a game more played. (AP)
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>JPMorgan Names New Head for Mortgage Business</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=72aef0150a431aea08aab51f550cbcdd
        </link>
        <pubDate>11 Feb 2011 16:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                Hoping to troubleshoot some of the problems plaguing its mortgage operations, Jamie Dimon dispatched one of his top lieutenants on Friday to oversee the Chase Home Lending business. Frank Bisignano, JPMorgan Chase’s chief administrative officer, will now add supervision of the Chase mortgage origination and loan payment collection businesses to his other duties, which include managing technology and real estate for the bank. David Lowman, the current head of Chase Home Lending, will retain his title but report to Mr. Bisignano. The management change comes as Chase’s mortgage business has faced considerable challenges as a result of the recession. Chase, like most of its peers, has faced enormous losses on its large portfolio of home equity and mortgage loans after loosening its lending standards during the housing boom. But it has also struggled to digest the mortgage operations that it acquired with its takeovers of Washington Mutual and Bear Stearns during the financial crisis. Many parts of the business ran on separate technology systems, making a three-way integration especially tricky. At the same time, Chase has come under fire from Washington for failing to cope with a giant wave of foreclosures as well as overcharging several thousand military veterans. “The mortgage business for everybody has changed tremendously,” Mr. Bisignano said in a brief interview on Friday. “Adding help to it can never be a bad idea.” Charles W. Scharf, the head of Chase Retail Financial Services, and Mr. Lowman have had their hands full contending with all of these issues over the last few years. They have significantly tightened the bank’s lending standards, halted the sale of new mortgages through independent brokers and overhauled the bank’s servicing operations. They have also hired thousands of employees and improved technology to try to keep up with the foreclosure mess. In 2010, Chase also began cordoning off its existing portfolio of real estate loans from those that conformed to its tougher new standards, a so-called good bank/bad bank strategy that has been used frequently by financial institutions to restructure their operations.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Accel Raises $1.3 Billion in Funds for China</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=1f4ee16717990d5d1833440a33fcec5f
        </link>
        <pubDate>1 Apr 2011 17:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                Accel Partners has closed two new funds for China, totaling $1.3 billion, the company said on Friday. One fund, valued at $550 million, will focus on young start-ups, while the second, a $750 million fund, will focus on later-stage financings. Accel, which has been active in China since 2005, has made several investments in the region with its partner IDG. The closing of Accel’s funds, comes as several of its large peers are raising billions in funding. As DealBook was first to report on Friday, Bessemer Venture Partners raised $1.6 billion for a fund focused on early stage start-ups and India. The fund, Bessemer’s largest to date, was heavily oversubscribed, with about $2.5 billion in intended commitments, according to two people close to the firm, who were not authorized to speak publicly. Jim Breyer, a partner at Accel, said the new funds represented Accel’s growing commitment to the market: “I spend several weeks each year in China with the team. We continue to remain very excited by the potential in China; its consumer Internet, social applications, mobile and media have remained our core focus over the last six years.” In 2010, Accel had nine exits in China, including five initial public offerings, Mr. Breyer said.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Former Wal-Mart Chief to Leave Goldman Board</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=2b5afff67252c3ab974c0699cfce24f3
        </link>
        <pubDate>18 Mar 2011 19:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                Another Goldman Sachs director is stepping down. On Thursday, the investment bank announced that H. Lee Scott Jr., the former chief executive of Wal-Mart Stores, will not stand for re-election at the annual meeting in May. “Lee made an important contribution to our board and the firm during a challenging period,” Goldman’s chief executive, Lloyd C. Blankfein, said in a statement. “I am particularly grateful for the enormous time and effort he committed to the board’s efforts related to the business standards committee.” Mr. Scott has not been at Goldman for long. In 2010, Goldman tapped him to replace the former managing director of McKinsey Company, Rajat K. Gupta, when he left the board. This year the Securities and Exchange Commission accused Mr. Gupta of sharing confidential information about Goldman, including passing along a tip about Warren E. Buffet’s $5 billion investment in Goldman in 2008. The investment bank lost another director last year, Ruth J. Simmons, the president of Brown University. She left after students and alumni of the elite college started grumbling about her ties to the investment bank and her role in approving lavish pay packages.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
</rss>
