<rss>
	<item>
		<title>The Leadership of Rex Ryan</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>17 Jan 2011 16:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		What Rex Ryan said immediately after the game (above). What he said before the game: “I recognize that this guy’s probably the best football coach, maybe in the history of the game. I don’t think there’s any doubt. In my opinion, he is. But I just want to be the best coach one particular day and that’s Sunday.” – Ryan on Bill Belichick Here are a few snippets from an interview with Michael Lombardi that ran on the NFL Network before the game: Lombardi: How many times did you watch the 45-3 [Week 13 Patriots] game? Ryan: Probably 20. 20 times, I’d say. Lombardi: Was it all your coaching, or do you think it was positioning of the players? Ryan: It was all my coaching. Lombardi: Do you do that to take all the pressure off the players? Ryan: I just state the facts. Lombardi: So when you win, it’s all the players and when you lose, it’s all on you? Ryan: Pretty much. That’s how it should be. If you’re a competitor and you see yourself as a leader, then that’s part of it. My job is to get my players prepared to play to the best of their abilities and I clearly failed. Extra point: In the last two seasons, the Jets have proved to be a better playoff team than regular-season team. Rex Ryan is a big reason for that, and probably the sole reason. An extra level of effort/intensity is required. His players appear to like him and like playing for him. He engenders loyalty, the way his father did. After winning the Super Bowl, the 1985 Bears lifted Mike Ditka on their shoulders, and notably, they did the same with Buddy Ryan. The Jets know Rex Ryan will do his all for them, back them up, and so they do their all for him. It helps, of course, that Ryan is acknowledged as a defensive master. But his lessons of leadership transcend football.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Google Tries Something Retro: Made in the U.S.A.</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>27 Jun 2012 20:48:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Etched into the base of Google’s new wireless home media player that was introduced on Wednesday is its most intriguing feature. On the underside of the Nexus Q is a simple inscription: “Designed and Manufactured in the U.S.A.” The Google executives and engineers who decided to build the player here are engaged in an experiment in American manufacturing. “We’ve been absent for so long, we decided, ‘Why don’t we try it and see what happens?’ ” said Andy Rubin, the Google executive who leads the company’s Android mobile business. Google is not saying a lot about its domestic manufacturing, declining even to disclose publicly where the factory is in Silicon Valley. It also is not saying much about the source of many of its parts in the United States. And Mr. Rubin said the company was not engaged in a crusade. Still, the project will be closely watched by other electronics companies. It has become accepted wisdom that consumer electronics products can no longer be made in the United States. During the last decade, abundant low-cost Chinese labor and looser environmental regulations have virtually erased what was once a vibrant American industry Since the 1990s, one American company after another, including Hewlett-Packard, Dell and Apple, has become a design and marketing shell, with production shifted to contract manufacturers in Shenzhen and elsewhere in China. Now that trend may be showing early signs of reversing.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Immigration to U.S., After Dip, Is Back Up</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>16 Feb 2010 15:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		The flow of immigrants to the United States has resumed, after falling to the lowest level in decades during the recession, a new study finds. The number of immigrants in the United States was estimated to have risen by about half a million in the year that ended in 2009, a jump from the previous year, when immigration stopped almost completely during the recession, according the study, which was conducted by the Brookings Institution and is being released on Thursday. The rise pointed to an increase in demand for immigrant labor in the economy, said Audrey Singer, a demographer and co-author of the report. However, the number is still far below the increases of more than a million a year that took place earlier in the decade. The flow reached a peak in 2006, with a 1.8 million increase in the foreign-born population. “It’s an uptick in opportunity,” Ms. Singer said. “Immigrants are very mobile in responding to economic changes.” The foreign-born population in the United States increased by 4.5 million in the decade ending in 1980. In the decade ending in 2000, it increased by 11.3 million, bringing the foreign-born population to about 13 percent of the total. In the early 20th century, after the last big wave of immigration to the United States, immigrants had reached 15 percent of the population. In 2008, immigration came to a standstill, the first big slowdown in decades of surging numbers, according to the report, which was based on estimates by the Census Bureau. The foreign-born population increased by 7.4 million between 2000 and 2009. “After three decades of nonstop growth, immigration seems to have paused,” the report says. The biggest losses were in cities that had boomed in recent years, particularly in the housing industry, including Phoenix, Riverside and San Bernardino in California and Tampa, Fla.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Study Ties Ovarian Cancer and Hormone Therapy</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>12 Nov 2010 22:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		More bad news about postmenopausal hormone therapy: a new European study reports that women who take the hormones are at significantly increased risk for ovarian cancer, which is rare but often fatal. Findings from the European Prospective Investigation into Cancer and Nutrition, which included some 126,920 postmenopausal women, were presented at a conference of the American Association for Cancer Research this month in Philadelphia. After nine years of follow-up, 424 ovarian cancers had been diagnosed. Even after controlling for body mass index, smoking and several other risk factors, researchers found that women on postmenopausal hormone therapy had a 29 percent greater risk of ovarian cancer, compared with those who did not use hormones. Women who used estrogen-only hormone therapy, typically taken after a hysterectomy, faced an increased risk of 63 percent compared with nonusers, while the increased risk of ovarian cancer among women taking a combination of estrogen and progestin did not reach statistical significance. Still, the study’s author, Konstantinos K. Tsilidis, a cancer epidemiologist at the University of Oxford in England, said there was a clear increase in risk for current users of all hormones, though only if they had been using them for at least five years. “It’s important to get the message out to women,” Dr. Tsilidis said. “This is a very lethal cancer.”
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Syria's President Disparages Foes</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>16 Aug 2011 13:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		President Bashar al-Assad of Syria said in an interview broadcast Wednesday that he faced no real domestic opposition in the 15-month-old uprising against him, the violence in his country is entirely the work of foreign-backed terrorists, and the boycott of parliamentary elections last week was a fiction. The interview, conducted on Tuesday by Russiya 24, a Russia state television station, was Mr. Assad's first since December. It suggested he had hardened longstanding views about his adversaries in the face of escalating international pressure. He also was dismissive of a question over why the political reforms sought by opponents was so slow in Syria. ''We have an acute problem with terrorism,'' he said, ''Terrorists don't care about reform, they are not fighting for reform.'' Street protests that erupted in March 2011 demanding greater democratic freedoms in Syria were met with a widespread security crackdown. An estimated 10,000 civilians have been killed as well as hundreds of soldiers. The United Nations continues to say that an unacceptable level of violence exists in Syria, laying the onus on the government to withdraw its troops and heavy armaments from major population centers first to allow an April 12 truce to take hold. A recent Syrian protest movement called ''Stop the Killing'' has emerged in Damascus and other cities, trying to reclaim the initial peaceful nature of the calls for change. Many of its organizers have been arrested. Activists said the gradual arming of the opposition came in response to the government's unbridled repression of protesters. ''The political course will not free us from terror,'' said Mr. Assad. Mr. Assad has been promising political reforms since 2001, when he inherited the presidency from his father, who had ruled for 30 years. But he said many Syrians believed that political reforms came about ''too early.''
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>AFTER THE ATTACKS: THE CENTRAL BANKS; Central Banks Inject Billions In Move to Stem Risks of Panic</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>13 Sep 2001 12:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Central banks around the world swung into action today in a coordinated effort to calm financial markets and reduce the chances that the attack on the United States would lead to a global economic crisis. The Federal Reserve and its counterparts in Europe and Japan injected large amounts of money into their financial systems to reduce the possibility that panicky reactions by investors, depositors or financial institution managers could lead to bank failures or some other calamity. ''The central banks out there know what they have to do, and they did it,'' said Carl Weinberg, chief global economist at High Frequency Economics, a consulting firm. There were also signs that the Fed and other central banks were prepared to cut interest rates in coming days -- perhaps even before stock markets in the United States reopen on Friday or Monday, but especially if Wall Street shows signs of severe distress after trading resumes. Although the markets in Japan and other Asian countries plunged, those in Europe moved higher today, providing some hope that Wall Street can avoid a big drop when equity trading resumes. Oil prices, after surging on Tuesday in the wake of the World Trade Center and Pentagon attacks, fell back yesterday, with statements from producing nations that they would seek to keep prices stable by increasing output, if necessary. The dollar, which tumbled against many currencies on Tuesday, seemed to stabilize.
		]]>
		</description>
</rss>
