<rss>
	<item>
		<title>As N.F.L. Deadline Nears, Would Decertification Be a Sham?</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>3 Mar 2011 06:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		The N.F.L. players union made big gains in 1993 after it voluntarily agreed to be decertified a few years earlier. The union, which doesn’t have a great  record of negotiating with owners, has had better luck in the judicial system. So as the midnight deadline nears for the labor deal to expire, the union is again considering decertification. But Andrew Brandt, a former Packers executive who writes for The National Football Post, said a sequel may not be as effective as the original: The success of the this strategy by former NFLPA leader Gene Upshaw may actually be a hindrance to the NFLPA and leader DeMaurice Smith, however. The NFL will seek to show the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) that the strategy is just that, a legal maneuver without substance, and therefore a sham to play the leverage game. On Wednesday, in an excellent summary of the possibilities that could unfold Thursday, Brandt addressed the topic again: Despite the baring of its fangs with the decertification option, I have always felt that the NFLPA does not want to do this In the event the NFLPA proceeds with it decertification strategy and then the NLRB agrees with the NFL, the union will have lost a big part of any leverage it had. In the last go-around, the union reconstituted itself after achieving its goal: the right to free agency. Judy Battista of The Times: After the N.F.L.P.A. decertified in 1989, an action unsuccessfully challenged by the N.F.L, it acted as a trade association. It was allowed to re-form as a union and resume collective bargaining activities when a settlement with owners was finally reached in 1993, the same course the current union would likely take if it dissolves. So the N.F.L. would seemingly be able to argue that this is a transparent attempt to avoid bargaining. The Biz of Football has the text of the complaint filed by the N.F.L. to the National Labor Relations Board last month. Here is one excerpt: As in the past, the NFLPA’s threatened disclaimer as the representatives of the players, together with the now-familiar antitrust litigation that is expected to follow, is a ploy and an unlawful subversion of the collective bargaining process; there is no evidence whatsoever of any (let alone widespread) disaffection with the Union by its members.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Drumming Up More Addresses on the Internet</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>14 Feb 2011 15:20:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Who could have guessed that 4.3 billion Internet connections wouldn’t be enough? Certainly not Vint Cerf. In 1976, Mr. Cerf and his colleagues in the R. D. office of the Defense Department had to make a judgment call: how much network address space should they allocate to an experiment connecting computers in an advanced data network? They debated the question for more than a year. Finally, with a deadline looming, Mr. Cerf decided on a number — 4.3 billion separate network addresses, each one representing a connected device — that seemed to provide more room to grow than his experiment would ever require, far more, in fact, than he could ever imagine needing. And so he was comfortable rejecting the even larger number of addresses that some on his team had argued for. “It was 1977,” Mr. Cerf said, in an interview last week. “We thought we were doing an experiment. “The problem was, the experiment never ended,” added Mr. Cerf, who is a former chairman of the Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers, or Icann, a nonprofit corporation that coordinates the Internet naming system. “We had no idea it would turn into the world’s global communications network.” Today, the Internet that Mr. Cerf helped create more than 30 years ago is about to max out. Within the next 12 to 18 months, or perhaps sooner, every one of the 4.3 billion Internet Protocol addresses will have been allocated, and the Internet, at least as it exists today, will have reached full capacity. I.P. addresses are the unique sequence of numbers assigned to each Web site, computer, game console or smartphone connected to the Internet. They are distinct from domain names, which identify Web sites, like nytimes.com. “There are 4.3 billion addresses, and a lot of people have more than one,” said Leo Vegoda, manager of number resources at Icann. “And there are seven billion people on the planet. That’s a big mismatch.”
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>What Early Presidential Polls Tell Us</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>16 Aug 2011 13:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Monday’s post on the strength of the Republican primary field has elicited a couple of critiques, such as this one from Brendan Nyhan. The article looked at favorability ratings for potential Republican candidates this year and found that the public’s view of them ranges from tepid, to uncertain, to fairly poor. In contrast, at a comparable point in elections dating back to 2000, at least a couple of candidates in each field were reasonably popular. Mr. Nyhan was able to retrieve some data on elections earlier than those contained in the PollingReport.com database. He found that the 1996 Republican field contained a number of popular candidates. Bob Dole had exceptionally high favorability ratings in early 1995, and two other Republican candidates — Phil Gramm and Pete Wilson — had fairly strong ones. On the other hand, Mr. Nyhan reported, Bill Clinton was barely known at this point in 1991 — he had a favorability rating of 15 percent against 12 percent unfavorable. This example is interesting in a couple of ways. First, there were several Democrats who were quite popular that year (Mario M. Cuomo, Al Gore, Richard A. Gephardt), but who chose not to run. In contrast, I can’t find any plausible Republican who has especially strong favorable ratings today unless you want to count David Petraeus or Colin Powell. Second, the public still held a lukewarm view of Mr. Clinton even upon electing him: a New York Times poll in October 1992, just weeks before the election, found 33 percent of voters with a favorable view of him but 39 percent unfavorable. Mr. Clinton won despite being a candidate whom voters were slow to develop a liking for. A more unambiguously favorable precedent for Republicans is that of Ronald Reagan. Mr. Nyhan reports that at this point in 1979, Mr. Reagan’s ratings were 38 percent favorable, against 39 percent unfavorable. However, his favorability ratings were fairly strong by mid-summer 1980, and he soundly defeated Jimmy Carter later that year.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Ferrying a Drug Into a Cancer Cell</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>3 Jun 2011 21:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Investigators released preliminary results from a clinical trial of T-DM1, a drug that targets and kills a type of cell that appears in some breast cancers. LINKING A toxic chemotherapy drug is attached to an antibody using tiny molecular linkers. The combined molecule, known as T-DM1, is then injected into the patient. BINDING In some breast cancer patients, the tumor cells are covered with huge numbers of a receptor called HER2. The antibody locks onto one of these receptors, with drug in tow. ABSORPTION The cell responds by enveloping and absorbing the joined antibody and receptor. Once inside the cell, the antibody and receptor begin to break down. RELEASE The cell breaks the antibody into pieces, which releases the drug. As more copies of the antibody are absorbed, the drug begins to disrupt the cell, eventually killing it.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Egypt: President Reappears</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>16 Mar 2010 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		President Hosni Mubarak appeared on Egyptian state television talking with his doctors on Tuesday — his first appearance since an operation in Germany 10 days earlier. The broadcast followed a swirl of rumors and speculation over the 81-year-old president’s health since what doctors said was the removal of his gall bladder on March 6. The Information Ministry issued photographs and video of Mr. Mubarak, below, sitting and talking with his doctors at Heidelberg University Hospital. “He was upbeat and in very good spirits as usual,” Dr. Markus Buechler, who leads the physicians treating him, said in a televised statement. “His resolve and willpower that we have witnessed all this week was very obvious this morning as he looked forward to going back to his normal activity.” Mr. Mubarak’s term expires next year, and the surgery has only heightened speculation as to whether he will retain control for another term in office.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>BANK ACCOUNTS; The Middle Class Struggles to Find Dollars</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>5 Feb 2002 13:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		With banks and exchange houses closed today, the first day of a two-day emergency bank holiday declared this weekend, black market dollar-dealers -- known as arbolitos, or little trees, for all of their green -- are doing brisk business in the city center. On Wednesday, when the government's partial relaxation of month-old restrictions on bank withdrawals takes effect, the early morning lines in front of downtown exchange houses, while normally large, are expected to wrap around the block. As the bankrupt government does everything it can to stop Argentines from cashing out of the insolvent banking system, the desperate and mostly middle-class depositors have been scrambling to stay one step ahead of the restrictions, trying everything, from boat trips to Uruguay to buying shares on the Buenos Aires stock market, to protect their wealth. ''It's a shame, but Argentines tend to expend more energy trying to get around the system that is in place than coming up with new solutions to our problems,'' said Nicolas Ducote, executive director of the Center for the Implementation of Public Policy for Equity and Growth, a research group known here as Cippec. After years of economic upheaval and hyperinflation, Argentines began depositing money in the banks in huge amounts by the mid-1990's, believing in the strength of the 1991 convertibility plan, which pegged the peso to the dollar. Deposits swelled from $41 billion in 1995 to $89 billion by the end of January 2001, according to Central Bank figures. But the confidence was in the dollar, and that is where Argentines sought refuge when government finances started to weaken significantly last year as a result of a four-year recession. By the time the government clamped down on bank withdrawals and transfers in December, deposits had fallen to $69 billion. Around $2 billion more has left the banking system since then.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
</rss>
