<rss>
    <item>
        <title>Supreme Court Is Elected, but Bears Perry’s Stamp</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=cb174c821d1d643463575d9723e8fc1f
        </link>
        <pubDate>11 Aug 2011 22:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                Gov. Nathan Deal of Georgia on Friday signed into law one of the nation’s toughest immigration measures, empowering local police officers to question certain suspects about their immigration status. The law is similar to measures in Arizona and Utah that have drawn legal challenges and economic boycotts. Mr. Deal, a Republican, said he would have preferred a comprehensive immigration overhaul from the federal government. “Illegal immigration is a complex and troublesome issue, and no state alone can fix it,” he said. “We will continue to have a broken system until we have a federal solution. In the meantime, states must act to defend their taxpayers.” The law takes effect July 1. Already, civil rights groups, including the American Civil Liberties Union and the Southern Poverty Law Center, say they are considering lawsuits against Georgia. Business groups, including the state Chamber of Commerce, have raised fears that the law will diminish tourism. In Arizona and Utah, court injunctions have delayed carrying out the laws while their constitutionality is determined. One of the Georgia law’s authors, Matthew L. Ramsey, a Republican state legislator, said the measure was written to withstand legal challenges. Lawmakers set clear guidelines on when the police are allowed to request a suspect’s immigration status, he said. The law allows state and local police officers to request immigration documentation from criminal suspects and, if they do not receive it, to take the suspects to jails, where federal officials could begin the deportation process. “States don’t have the legal authority to deport. We don’t have the legal authority to secure our borders,” Mr. Ramsey said. "But our goal is, within a constitutional framework, to eliminate incentives for illegal aliens to cross into our state." The law also creates stricter requirements for businesses hiring workers and harsher punishments for anyone who harbors or employs an illegal immigrant. There are 425,000 illegal immigrants in Georgia, the seventh most of any state, the Pew Hispanic Center estimates. Two other Southern states, Alabama and South Carolina, are also considering similar immigration bills that are expected by many experts to pass this year.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>A Snapshot of the Race for the Senate</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=9c4b7d881af58524830c2b18de613ebf
        </link>
        <pubDate>27 Dec 2011 12:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                The electoral implications of the impending retirement of Senator Ben Nelson of Nebraska are fairly obvious. This is bad news for Democrats, who were already going to have a difficult time holding on to their narrow 53-47 advantage in the upper chamber. It’s not as bad for them as something like the retirement of Senator Kent Conrad of North Dakota, which took a seat that Democrats were likely to retain and turned it into a likely gain for Republicans. Rather, with middling approval ratings in a red state in an anti-incumbent climate, Mr. Nelson’s re-election prospects were tenuous to begin with. If Democrats can get former Senator Bob Kerrey of Nebraska to run in Mr. Nelson’s place, their odds of retaining the seat will not necessarily be worse than they would have been with Mr. Nelson. Nevertheless, Mr. Kerrey is not assured of running, and Democrats have a very thin bench in the state. Without a strong recruit, this could be a seat that effectively winds up in the G.O.P. column long before the voting actually begins. It’s worth considering Nebraska in the context of the broader Senate picture. Our objective technique for forecasting Senate races is not designed to be applied until summer of the election year. (Before then, the polling is a little too rough, and there is too much uncertainty about the identity of nominees, for polling-based forecasts to be of all that much value.) So you will have to wait on those. However, I have traditionally issued subjective estimates of the probability of the parties winning each seat in advance of our objective numbers. Basically, I’m looking at the same thing that other forecasters do: approval ratings, recent electoral history, candidate quality and so forth — and yes, I do look a little bit at head-to-head polls, especially if both candidates are well known. I also tend to place more emphasis than most forecasters on the overall partisan makeup of a state. For instance, although Senator Joe Manchin III of West Virginia has quite strong approval ratings for the time being, I’m not comfortable classifying the race as completely safe for Democrats given that Barack Obama will be on the ballot and is very unpopular in West Virginia. Mr. Nelson is one of several examples of senators who were once very popular but who were brought down to earth by partisan gravity.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Two New Jersey Democrats to Face Each Other</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=61314aa1cec4d668c5e3c4b829943ef5
        </link>
        <pubDate>27 Dec 2011 22:34:05 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                Get ready for some Democrat-on-Democrat infighting in New Jersey. Representative Steve Rothman, a Democrat whose 9th District has been upended by redistricting, will face off against a fellow Democrat, Representative Bill Pascrell Jr., who currently represents the state’s 8th District. Under the newly configured districts, Mr. Rothman’s home town of Fair Lawn was plopped into the redrawn 5th District, currently held by Representative Scott Garrett, a Republican and one of the more conservative members of the House. The new district favors Republicans and would have offered an uphill race for Mr. Rothman. So he will move, and run against Mr. Pascrell in the new 9th District, creating the latest House battle between incumbents of the same party, a natural outgrowth of redistricting, which occurs every 10 years. There are roughly a dozen such races around the country, divided almost equally among incumbent Republican and Democrats. Mr. Rothman, now serving his eighth term, represents about 55 percent of the voters in the new district, while Mr. Pascrell represents about 45 percent. “Congressman Rothman was born in the 9th District, he was raised in the 9th District and he will be running in this district,” said Paul Swibinski, a spokesman for Mr. Rothman’s campaign. While Mr. Rothman has not decided where his new home will be in the redrawn district, which will include parts of Bergen, Passaic and Hudson Counties, Englewood seems a safe bet. “He was mayor of Englewood,” Mr. Swibinski said. “He had a law practice in Englewood, and my guess is it’s a pretty good chance he will move back to Englewood.” In a statement released by his re-election campaign, Mr. Pascrell, who was first elected in 1996, said: “The New Jersey Congressional Redistricting Commission has made their decision and so have I. I couldn’t be more ready to begin serving the people of New Jersey’s new 9th Congressional District.”
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Obama’s Jobs Plan Is Blocked Again by Senate Republicans</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=0a7964c449defd6c2d00a94390fd4d6a
        </link>
        <pubDate>20 Oct 2011 8:34:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                For the second time in 10 days, the Senate on Thursday rejected Democratic efforts to take up a jobs bill championed by President Obama. The vote to advance the bill was 50 to 50. Democrats needed 60 votes to overcome a Republican filibuster. This time, the bill was narrowed to provide $35 billion to state and local governments to prevent layoffs of teachers, police officers and firefighters. To offset the cost, the bill would impose a surtax of 0.5 percent, starting in 2013, on income in excess of $1 million. Despite the vote Thursday, Democrats said they hoped to gain a political edge, by forcing Republicans to vote on this and other discrete parts of broader legislation proposed by Mr. Obama to create jobs and revive the economy. Campaigning for his $447 billion jobs package this week in North Carolina and Virginia, Mr. Obama suggested that Republicans could not understand the whole thing all at once, so he said “we’re going to chop it up into some bite-sized pieces.” The Senate last week blocked consideration of the larger bill, which included a 5.6 percent surtax on income over $1 million. Republicans objected to the tax and said the bill would be no more successful than the economic stimulus law Mr. Obama signed in February 2009. The vote late Thursday generally followed party lines. Two Democrats — Senators Ben Nelson of Nebraska and Mark Pryor of Arkansas — and Senator Joseph I. Lieberman, independent of Connecticut, joined Republicans in voting against immediate consideration of the bill for public employees. Both parties seized on the smaller bill to draw contrasts in advance of the 2012 elections. Democrats said the bill would save or create jobs for nearly 400,000 teachers and force millionaires to make a small sacrifice for the benefit of the nation.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Less Web Tracking Means Less Effective Ads, Researcher Says</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=fac2a3346b1f456d65b99f582e873e2a
        </link>
        <pubDate>15 Sep 2011 17:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                No wonder Internet companies are so anxious about stricter privacy rules. Research by Catherine Tucker, a professor at the M.I.T. Sloan School of Management, has found that European Union regulations that limit the tracking of Internet users were associated with a 65 percent drop in the effectiveness of online marketing. In other words, if Internet companies cannot track what you do online, they find it harder to pitch you stuff that you may be persuaded to buy. This is relevant now because lawmakers in the United States are weighing legislation to regulate consumer privacy on the Internet, to the dismay of Internet giants that rely on advertising revenue. Ms. Tucker is scheduled to testify before a Congressional subcommittee on Thursday. The success of online advertising relies on Internet companies tracking and analyzing an unwitting consumer’s behavior online: following a user as she searches the Web and chronicles her habits and desires on social networks like Facebook. For companies, that data can be used “to deliver online advertising in an extraordinarily precise fashion,” Ms. Tucker points out in her planned testimony. For consumers, she goes on, it can seem “creepy.” The European Union in 2002 moved to limit behavioral targeting. According to Ms. Tucker’s testimony to the Congressional subcommittee on commerce, manufacturing and trade, it led to a two-thirds decline in “purchasing intent” – effectively, a measure of how likely an Internet user is to purchase the product after viewing an advertisement. “Online advertising became much less eﬀective in Europe relative to elsewhere after the regulation was enacted,” she said. The impact was not equally felt across all Web sites, according to the research she did with Avi Goldfarb of the University of Toronto, which was published earlier this year in the journal Management Science.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>I.B.M. Researchers Create High-Speed Graphene Circuits</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=13c60490a593faef0f05ce8c0d9131d4
        </link>
        <pubDate>9 Jun 2011 20:24:47 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                I.B.M. researchers said Thursday that they had designed high-speed circuits from graphene, an ultra-thin material that has a host of promising applications, from high-bandwidth communication to a new generation of low-cost smartphone and television displays. The I.B.M. advance, which the researchers reported in the journal Science, is a circuit known as a broadband frequency mixer that was built on a wafer of silicon. Widely used in all kinds of communications products, the circuits shift signals from one frequency to another. In the Science paper, the I.B.M. researchers describe a demonstration in which they deposited several layers of graphene on a silicon wafer, then created circuits based on graphene transistors and components known as inductors. They demonstrated frequency mixing up to speeds of 10 gigahertz. In the past I.B.M. has created stand-alone graphene transistors, but not complete electronic circuits. Scientists began making flakes of graphene, an atomic-scale lattice of carbon atoms, in the 1970s. They have gradually refined the process so they can now produce films of the material that are just a single atom thick. The film arranges itself in a hexagon-shaped array of carbon atoms and has the advantages of being flexible, transparent and inexpensive to manufacture. But it is not yet a candidate to replace today’s CMOS transistors, the basis for the microprocessors and computer memories in consumer electronics systems. Graphene does not have the same physical properties as semiconducting materials and cannot be used to completely switch on and off in the way that logic transistors are meant to do. That has not tempered the industry’s excitement over potential applications for the material. In Europe and Asia, government and corporate investments are running far in advance of those in the United States, said Phaedon Avouris, an I.B.M. chemical physicist who is a leader of the company’s research effort.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
</rss>
