<rss>
    <item>
        <title>Your Life on Facebook, in Total Recall</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=efc7eb1e797a79bd5fa5636c3b47549c
        </link>
        <pubDate>15 Dec 2011 6:37:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                Remember those karaoke videos from three years ago that somehow wound up on Facebook? They were embarrassing for the few hours they spent at the top of your Facebook profile, and then they were buried under a cascade of new updates. But on Thursday, Facebook started rolling out a revamped profile feature called Timeline that makes a user’s entire history of photos, links and other things shared on Facebook accessible with a single click. This may be the first moment that many of Facebook’s 800 million members realize just how many digital bread crumbs they have been leaving on the site — and on the Web in general. For better or worse, the new format is likely to bring back a lot of old memories. But it could also make it harder to shed past identities — something people growing up with Facebook might struggle with as they move from high school to college and from there to the working world. “There’s no act too small to record on your permanent record,” said Jonathan Zittrain, a law professor at Harvard who studies how the Internet affects society. “All of the mouse droppings that appear as we migrate around the Web will be saved.” The old Facebook profile page shows the most recent items users have posted, along with things like photos of them posted by others. But Timeline creates a scrapbooklike montage, assembling photos, links and updates for each month and year since they signed up for Facebook. When Mark Zuckerberg, the founder and chief executive of Facebook, introduced Timeline in September at a developer conference, he described it as a way to get a more comprehensive portrait of someone than by simply reading updates or looking at a profile picture: “We think it’s an important next step to help tell the story of your life.”
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>A Look Back at the Space Shuttle</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=933c74865e1826e755b91e0a789eecc7
        </link>
        <pubDate>9 Jun 2011 15:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                Two weeks ago, “CBS Sunday Morning” aired my story about the end of the Space Shuttle program. It was a story dear to my heart, one I’d hoped to do for years. It took me three trips to Kennedy Space Center to finally film the liftoff (because the final liftoff of the shuttle Endeavour kept being delayed). I’m especially proud of the final shot, which I timed a dozen times so that my lines would end simultaneously with the actual liftoff behind me. Mother Luck was with me that day, as you can see from the finished story here. Unfortunately, we could include only snippets of the interviews we conducted. But as always, in “From the Desk of David Pogue,” I have more space to share with you edited transcripts of those interviews. Here’s one I really loved: a chat with William Gerstenmaier, who’s the head of NASA’s Shuttle and Space Station programs. He’s been with the shuttle program since 1977, when he was an engineer performing wind-tunnel tests on shuttle models. I found him wise, modest and articulate. DP: I come here on behalf of 300 million Americans who want to know, in layman’s terms, why the space shuttle is being retired? ‘Cause everybody loves it! WG: Yeah– boy, it’s tough. But the mission that the shuttle was designed for is kind of going away. If you look at the space station, this large spacecraft we built from parts from around the world… it weighs 900,000 pounds in orbit. I mean, it’s as big as a football field. It’s huge. That international space station could never have been built without a space shuttle. The shuttle has this large cargo bay that can carry large pieces up. And that was the uniqueness of the shuttle. It could carry these big pieces to space. It has an air lock, so the crews can put on spacesuits, and go outside and do work. It has a robotic arm.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Detroit Auto Show Reveals a Google-Designed Van That Could Steer the Industry</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=28f86547b8ab39668ef8ce656b88662e
        </link>
        <pubDate>8 Jun 2017 19:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                DETROIT — There are shiny new sport utility vehicles, brawny pickups and sleek sedans. But the unlikely star of the annual Detroit auto show is an odd-looking minivan capable of driving itself. The van, designed by Google, grabbed the spotlight on Sunday, the first day of press previews at the show. The vehicle’s introduction highlighted the industry’s fascination with autonomous driving vehicles, as well as the rising sway of the technology industry in the auto business. Google’s parent company, Alphabet, spun off its driverless car project last month. The new business, called Waymo, is considered a sign that the company is ready to commercialize a decade of research and development of a vehicle operated solely by computer. The van shown on Sunday is the first fruit of those labors. In many ways, it looks like a conventional minivan. But it is also equipped with the self-driving sensors and vision systems developed by Waymo, some of which protrude from its body. That combination is telling. The van was built by the Detroit automaker Fiat Chrysler, making it the first heavyweight collaboration between a major automaker and one of Silicon Valley’s elite. And it shows how Waymo, widely considered the leader in autonomous driving technology, hopes to sell its self-driving systems to car companies unwilling to bear all the costs of developing vehicles. Some automakers, like General Motors and Ford Motor, have committed to creating their own driverless cars. Both companies recently announced plans to build their first fully autonomous vehicles at factories in Michigan. But Google is intent on offering another option to automakers by creating a ready-made package of self-driving equipment that can be integrated into mainstream vehicles.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Google’s Lab of Wildest Dreams</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=5e4cb097564fdbe97e7d2d92d98e982e
        </link>
        <pubDate>13 Nov 2011 8:54:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                In a top-secret lab in an undisclosed Bay Area location where robots run free, the future is being imagined. It’s a place where your refrigerator could be connected to the Internet, so it could order groceries when they ran low. Your dinner plate could post to a social network what you’re eating. Your robot could go to the office while you stay home in your pajamas. And you could, perhaps, take an elevator to outer space. These are just a few of the dreams being chased at Google X, the clandestine lab where Google is tackling a list of 100 shoot-for-the-stars ideas. In interviews, a dozen people discussed the list; some work at the lab or elsewhere at Google, and some have been briefed on the project. But none would speak for attribution because Google is so secretive about the effort that many employees do not even know the lab exists. Although most of the ideas on the list are in the conceptual stage, nowhere near reality, two people briefed on the project said one product would be released by the end of the year, although they would not say what it was. “They’re pretty far out in front right now,” said Rodney Brooks, a professor emeritus at M.I.T.’s computer science and artificial intelligence lab and founder of Heartland Robotics. “But Google’s not an ordinary company, so almost nothing applies.” At most Silicon Valley companies, innovation means developing online apps or ads, but Google sees itself as different. Even as Google has grown into a major corporation and tech start-ups are biting at its heels, the lab reflects its ambition to be a place where ground-breaking research and development are happening, in the tradition of Xerox PARC, which developed the modern personal computer in the 1970s. A Google spokeswoman, Jill Hazelbaker, declined to comment on the lab, but said that investing in speculative projects was an important part of Google’s DNA. “While the possibilities are incredibly exciting, please do keep in mind that the sums involved are very small by comparison to the investments we make in our core businesses,” she said.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Apple Unveils iPhone 4S With Voice-Recognition Features</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=52094726562a3497acc9978365795307
        </link>
        <pubDate>4 Oct 2011 12:17:56 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                Tech journalists descended upon Apple’s headquarters in Cupertino, Calif., on Tuesday for some iPhone-related announcements. Our updates from the event are below, with the most recent at the top. Tim Cook is back on stage. He’s reviewing everything we’ve heard today. Now he’s pivoting from the devices to the company. “Only Apple could make such hardware and services…” “I am so incredibly proud of this company and all of the teams that worked so hard to bring all the amazing things you’ve seen to reality.” And that’s your Apple press event. Mr. Cook exits, stage left. “Layla” now playing over the speakers. So, in spite of the many mockups that circulated online, and “new cases” that were “revealed,” the iPhone 4S looks exactly the same as the iPhone 4. Investors seem unhappy with what they’ve heard. Apple’s stock is down 2.6 percent on heavy volume. Prices for the iPhone 4S are as follows: $199 for 16 gigabytes of storage, $299 for 32 GB, and $399 for 64 GB. There will be an iPhone 4 with 8 GB for $99. And there will be an iPhone 3GS for… free, with a two-year contract. Preorders for the 4S start Oct. 7, delivery on the 14th. Sprint gets it too! So a world phone on three out of four major networks. We’ll have more coverage soon. Thanks for reading. Siri can schedule events in your calendar, read messages, take dictation, all by voice. You can create a reminder by voice. “Remind me to call my wife when I leave work,” says Mr. Forstall. Siri, based on previous conversations, knows who your wife is and uses geolocation to remind you when you leave a location. You can search Wikipedia by voice. Apple has also linked up with Wolfram Alpha to provide data and definitions for Siri to access. “Define mitosis,” says Mr. Forstall. Siri generates and reads back a definition. We are clearly headed to Terminator/HAL territory here. Humans are doomed. Deal with it. Mr Forstall asks Siri, “Who are you?” Siri replies, “I am a humble personal assistant.”
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>In Defense of the Slow and the Boring</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=1c1878d75bc7bf5d7eea239bdcec4136
        </link>
        <pubDate>3 Jun 2011 12:14:15 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                WHAT is boring? This question was inspired by a piece in the May 1 edition of The New York Times Magazine by Dan Kois that offered a cheerful conformist’s take on what in certain circles is sometimes termed slow cinema and that he simply finds boring, the equivalent of eating his “cultural vegetables.” Mr. Kois writes that he knows he’s supposed to embrace celebrated films that he variously describes as “slow-moving, meditative” and “stately, austere” and “deliberately paced.” But he can’t, won’t, doesn’t like or understand them. In this he empathizes with his 6-year-old daughter, Lyra, who, at a friend’s urging, tuned into “Phineas and Ferb,” a TV show that she doesn’t fully get but watches “aspirationally, as a sort of challenge to herself.” Mr. Kois watches aspirationally too. He sees Kelly Reichardt’s “Meek’s Cutoff,” the subject of his longest lament, but his eyes roll back in his head. This makes him feel guilty, but not really. He and his daughter “both yearn,” he writes: she wants to be older than she is, while he aches to “experience culture at an ever more elevated level.” To that end he has watched films by Andrei Tarkovsky, including “Solaris,” but this too bored him as did, apparently, the very different Hou Hsaio-hsien. “As I get older,” Mr. Kois concludes, “I find I’m suffering from a kind of culture fatigue and have less interest in eating my cultural vegetables, no matter how good they may be for me.” Happily for him, movie theaters offer a cornucopia of junk food. For instance: “The Hangover Part II,” which I find boring, raked in $137.4 million over the five-day Memorial Day weekend. It’s the kind of boring that makes money, partly because it’s the boring that many people like, want to like, insist on liking or are just used to, and partly because it’s the sort of aggressively packaged boring you can’t escape, having opened on an estimated 17 percent of American screens. Filled with gags and characters recycled from the first “Hangover,” the sequel is grindingly repetitive and features scene after similar scene of characters staring at one another stupidly, flailing about wildly and asking what happened. This is the boring that Andy Warhol, who liked boring, found, well, boring.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
</rss>
