<rss>
    <item>
        <title>Obama’s Jobs Plan Is Blocked Again by Senate Republicans</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=0546175905f4d76a5d8748e0f2e2f1ee
        </link>
        <pubDate>19 Aug 2011 16:04:35 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                ''It's too bad she won't live,'' Edward James Olmos tells Harrison Ford in ''Blade Runner.'' ''But then again, who does?'' And then again, there are those movies that just live on forever: Ridley Scott, who directed that moody 1982 science-fiction film noir, will direct and produce a new feature that is being described as a ''Blade Runner'' follow-up for Alcon Entertainment, a Warner Brothers-based financing and production company, its press representatives said on Thursday. The original ''Blade Runner,'' which was adapted from the Philip K. Dick story ''Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?'', starred Mr. Ford as a human bounty hunter (or is he?) charged with hunting down lifelike androids in a future version of Los Angeles (where Atari is apparently still a major video game publisher). Though the film got a mixed reception in its day (Janet Maslin called it ''muddled yet mesmerizing'' in her review for The New York Times), it has become a cult classic and released in at least seven different edits, with different endings depending on who was wielding the scissors. Mr. Scott, whose 2010 feature ''Robin Hood'' nabbed about $320 million in riches at the worldwide box office, has lately been getting reacquainted with his sci-fi roots. Next year, Fox plans to release his film ''Prometheus,'' an outer space adventure which is at least loosely connected to his 1979 chest-bursting thriller ''Alien.'' (Mr. Scott, the film's stars and its screenwriter have all offered varying descriptions of just how closely the new movie is tied to the earlier one.) In keeping with that tradition, a news release from Alcon said of the new ''Blade Runner'' project, ''The filmmakers have not yet revealed whether the theatrical project will be a prequel or sequel to the renowned original.'' This is a more complete version of the story than the one that appeared in print.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>A Soundtrack to Invest In</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=4e9e16dc9ed71fdac5e1eeecda282e50
        </link>
        <pubDate>31 Jan 2011 20:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                ''The King's Speech'' collected an impressive 12 Oscar nominations last week. It might have stopped short of a dozen without help from a British entrepreneur who has planted his business at the tricky intersection of film and music. In an unconventional deal that may promise a revival in film music, the Cutting Edge Group, based in London, and its chief executive, Philip Moross, effectively bought the musical portion of ''The King's Speech'' months ago. The investment then let the film's producers hire Alexandre Desplat, the award-winning French composer whose score was among its nominations, and recruit the London Philharmonic Orchestra to record works of Mozart, Beethoven and Brahms that would otherwise have been performed by a small ensemble. ''What we wanted to do was get the music that would do the images justice,'' Iain Canning, a producer of ''The King's Speech,'' said in an interview by phone last week of the decision to give up rights to the music in return for having enough money to get the music right. He added of Cutting Edge: ''They inflate your music budget.'' Traditionally, movie producers pay companies like Cutting Edge, which also manages catalogs of music rights and represents music supervisors and composers (though not Mr. Desplat), for help in assembling the scores and songs in their films. The role played by a company like Cutting Edge varies widely from film to film. Though creative control remains with the director and producers, the company will generally provide or recruit a music supervisor, who suggests what songs to include and helps clear the rights, and a composer who writes the score. It may also provide recording studio services, operate its own record label, administer publishing rights and distribute the music in other forms after a film is released.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Choosing Sides in the Revolving-Spy Game</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=f63254e8680474b05a943e0ee4149c2b
        </link>
        <pubDate>27 Oct 2011 17:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                In “The Double,” a moldy, post-cold-war spy thriller that vainly aspires to be a contemporary “Patriot Games,” Richard Gere, in his enigmatic, sinister mode, portrays Paul Shepherdson, a former C.I.A. officer who is suddenly called out of retirement. The killing of a United States senator on the streets of Washington has all the markings of crimes committed by a notorious international assassin and Soviet double agent, code named Cassius, who is presumed to be dead. Shepherdson spent the better part of two decades pursuing Cassius. So his boss, Highland (Martin Sheen), teams him with an eager new F.B.I. recruit, the Harvard-educated Ben Geary (Topher Grace), who wrote his thesis on the case and is convinced that Cassius remains at large. A half-hour into the movie, after some coy flashbacks that place Shepherdson at this or that killing site, it is bluntly revealed that he and Cassius are one and the same. It is hardly a surprise, since the trailer gives it away. Immediately the steam goes out of the movie. Once this bit of bogus suspense is cleared up, “The Double” becomes a tedious, impenetrable cat-and-mouse game involving Russian double and triple agents. The movie reserves its one big reveal — a preposterous, paranoid whopper — for the very end, long after you have given up investing yourself in the story, written by the director Michael Brandt and his longtime collaborator Derek Haas. Even that revelation, which arrives too late and too fast, is botched. By this point “The Double” has demonstrated so little connection to the real world that it feels like a fantasy invented by the creators of an espionage board game.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Hit Man Is Back, Teaching the Tricks of the Trade</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=87198dafdd7c8a0de71ed66a7d5300f0
        </link>
        <pubDate>27 Jan 2011 15:21:45 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                Sleek as a bullet, the action star Jason Statham jaw-clenches his way through “The Mechanic,” a sputtering remake in need of a more powerful recharge. A contempo update of the 1972 Charles Bronson vehicle of the same name (alternately titled “Killer of Killers”), the story pivots on one of those professional assassins in the employ of one of those hush-hush organizations in which men murmur murderous instructions into phones so that other men can die. For a hit man like Arthur Bishop (Mr. Statham), this makes for an isolated if lucrative life that comes with a swank pad, a vintage muscle car and paid nights with the local talent. That existence takes a turn for the vaguely complicated when Bishop, after some messy business with a colleague (Donald Sutherland), forms an unlikely partnership with that associate’s wayward son, Steve McKenna (Ben Foster). With his complementary buzz cut, hard-body profile and hyperbolic masculinity, McKenna turns out to be a capable if overly reckless sidekick and a rather adorable Mini Me for Bishop in what soon starts to resemble something of a hit-man hookup. Action flicks often bristle with the love that dare not speak its name, as men express themselves through eroticized violence and the usual expressive grunting and grappling, body slamming, inevitable spasms of death and climactic explosions. When Bishop and McKenna begin firing off their guns in tandem, it certainly looks like the start of a beautiful friendship.Yet while the two come across as Mr. and Mr. Smith of the action-flick set, Bishop and McKenna can’t really go the distance, of course, in the don’t ask, don’t tell movie world. So instead, McKenna, on his first solo contract job, lures a gay man home alone with feigned sensitivity and a little dog, and then engages in a sadistic fight to the death that conveys — with the customary physical struggle and oozing bodily fluids — what cannot be expressed in any other fashion. It’s unclear if the director, Simon West (“Con Air”), and Richard Wenk, who shares the script credit with the first film’s writer, Lewis John Carlino, understand what that scene is about, but its message comes through with blunt, somewhat queasy force.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Theater Talkback: Who Wrote Shakespeare? Who Cares?</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=ec2f4e9e1ffda67df6600ad845e6565f
        </link>
        <pubDate>27 Oct 2011 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                May I make a confession? And I realize that this may be regarded as a heresy by the members of my tribe, by which I mean those of us who were and always shall be nerdy English majors. I don’t care who wrote Shakespeare’s plays. I don’t care if they were written by Francis Bacon or Sir Walter Raleigh (or Francis Bacon with Sir Walter Raleigh) or Christopher Marlowe or Queen Elizabeth I. I don’t care if it turns out that they were written by the 20th-century playwright Christopher Fry, who, frustrated when the verse dramas he wrote fell out of fashion, time-traveled back to the Elizabethan age where he would be better appreciated. And I particularly don’t care if they were written by an aristocrat named Edward de Vere, 17th Earl of Oxford, which is the contention of a new film called “Anonymous” that has raised hackles in academia. The Shakespeare Birthplace Trust has registered its discontent with that movie, in a creative protest that involves covering up Shakespeare’s name on signs and pubs in Warwickshire County, where the so-called Shakespeare was supposedly born. And The New York Times has already published scholarly dismissals of “Anonymous” in both its Sunday magazine and on its Op-Ed page. For the record, if pushed for a stand on this issue, I will say that I lean unimaginatively toward the orthodox version: William Shakespeare was William Shakespeare the glove maker’s son from Stratford-upon-Avon. (This is perhaps partly because, like many people, I have on occasion been the subject of small-time conspiracy-theory whispers, and they have always been preposterously off the mark. Truth may never be pure and simple, but it is usually less complicated than idle minds like to make it.)
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>English King to Have Brief Reign in Beijing</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=e37da790a6d0fc4e6044a525913a32fe
        </link>
        <pubDate>15 Nov 2011 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                After more than 18 months of negotiations “Richard III,” starring Kevin Spacey, opened in Beijing last Friday, according to Agence France-Presse. Cultural productions are carefully scrutinized by government censors in China, and the the play, about a tyrannical king, is the first presentation of Shakespeare by a Western theater company in the Chinese capital. The Bridge Project — a collaboration between the Brooklyn Academy of Music in New York and the Old Vic and Neal Street theaters in London to present classical theater to international audiences — is producing the show. The director Sam Mendes has transported the action to the present in this production, which ran for three nights at the National Center for the Performing Arts. “As opposed to going to Hong Kong or going to Europe, or even going to Singapore, there just hasn’t been a lot of relationship-building,” Nick Schwartz-Hall, an organizer of the Bridge Project, said. “There’s not a lot of familiarity on either side with how a U.K.-U.S. company works, and does business, versus how it’s done here.” Correction: November 17, 2011
                Because of an editing error, a report in the “Arts, Briefly” column on Wednesday misstated the timing of a production of “Richard III,” starring Kevin Spacey, in Beijing. The three-night run began last Friday. It does not open on Friday.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
</rss>
