<rss>
    <item>
        <title>20 darsad Rise Seen in Number of Survivors of Cancer</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=80db2e25d76f3441af4116bdf930c1d0
        </link>
        <pubDate>10 Mar 2011 16:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                About one in every 20 adults in the United States has survived cancer, including nearly one-fifth of all people over 65, according to new federal data. The numbers, released Thursday by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the National Cancer Institute, indicated that the number of cancer survivors increased by about 20 percent in just six years, to 11.7 million in 2007, the latest year for which figures were analyzed, from 9.8 million in 2001. In 1971, the number of cancer survivors was three million. “There’s still a concept that cancer is a death sentence,” said Dr. Thomas R. Frieden, director of the Centers for Disease Control. But, he said, “for many people with cancer there’s a need for them and their families and caregivers to recognize that this is a stage. They can live a long and healthy life.” About 65 percent of cancer survivors have lived at least five years since receiving their diagnosis, 40 percent have lived 10 years or more, and nearly 10 percent have lived 25 years or longer. The implications, Dr. Frieden said, are that many cancers are treatable and that it is just as important for people who have had cancer not to assume that they will necessarily die early. “You might think, ‘I’ve had cancer — I don’t have to worry about eating right, quitting smoking, exercising,’ ” Dr. Frieden said. But people with cancer “need to be just as concerned about heart disease and other risks as they would otherwise,” he said. The study defined a survivor as anyone who ever received a diagnosis of cancer who was alive on Jan. 1, 2007, and it did not indicate if the person was cured, undergoing treatment, afflicted with a chronic cancer-related illness, or in the process of dying at that time.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Perceptions: Cancer Drugs Get on a Faster Track in U.S.</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=747fd1a58d85a9bed64aac77155fc230
        </link>
        <pubDate>20 June 2011 19:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                New cancer drugs are approved in just six months on average in the United States, half the time it takes for the same drugs to be approved in Europe, a new report finds. The analysis, published online this month by the journal Health Affairs, appears to refute critics who have charged the Food and Drug Administration is less efficient than the European Medicines Agency and has been slower to approve new cancer drugs. The study’s authors compiled a list of 35 new cancer drugs approved by either of the agencies between 2003 and 2010. They found that the F.D.A. had approved 32 of the products in an average of 182 days from the time that the first applications were filed. Only three products took more than a year to receive approval. By contrast, the European Medicines Agency approved only 26 of the drugs, taking just under a year on average. Nine drugs were not approved. All of the drugs that were approved by both agencies were available to patients in the United States first. The results surprised the study’s authors. “When we realized we were correct, we thought, ‘No one is going to believe us because this goes against urban legend,’ ” said Ellen V. Sigal, chair and founder of Friends of Cancer Research.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>F.D.A. Panel to Consider Warnings for Artificial Food Colorings</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=5dfd108b5c621f4dbc16a1117e5cfd34
        </link>
        <pubDate>29 Mar 2011 23:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                After staunchly defending the safety of artificial food colorings, the federal government is for the first time publicly reassessing whether foods like Jell-O, Lucky Charms cereal and Minute Maid Lemonade should carry warnings that the bright artificial colorings in them worsen behavior problems like hyperactivity in some children. The Food and Drug Administration concluded long ago that there was no definitive link between the colorings and behavior or health problems, and the agency is unlikely to change its mind any time soon. But on Wednesday and Thursday, the F.D.A. will ask a panel of experts to review the evidence and advise on possible policy changes, which could include warning labels on food. The hearings signal that the growing list of studies suggesting a link between artificial colorings and behavioral changes in children has at least gotten regulators’ attention — and, for consumer advocates, that in itself is a victory. In a concluding report, staff scientists from the F.D.A. wrote that while typical children might be unaffected by the dyes, those with behavioral disorders might have their conditions “exacerbated by exposure to a number of substances in food, including, but not limited to, synthetic color additives.” Froot Loops cereal contains artificial dyes. Credit Tony Cenicola/The New York Times. Renee Shutters, a mother of two from Jamestown, N.Y., said in a telephone interview on Tuesday that two years ago, her son Trenton, then 5, was having serious behavioral problems at school until she eliminated artificial food colorings from his diet. “I know for sure I found the root cause of this one because you can turn it on and off like a switch,” Ms. Shutters said.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>This Week’s Health Industry News</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=f6be10de18b25f8b0ab00acfe1bf281c
        </link>
        <pubDate>14 Mar 2011 12:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                Expect the talk in Washington about the federal health care law to intensify as we approach the one-year anniversary of the passage of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act next week. Congress is holding several hearings, including the Senate Finance Committee meeting on Wednesday morning to discuss “Health Reform: Lessons Learned During the First Year.” On Thursday, the Senate health committee will take a look at the exchanges being developed to offer heath insurance and what the states need to do to implement the new law. Meanwhile, in the House, the oversight committee’s health care subcommittee is holding a hearing on Tuesday about all the waivers federal regulators are granting under the new law. On Thursday, the House Energy and Commerce Committee will take a look at the so-called Class program, a new national insurance plan for long-term care. For those interested in following how this all plays out, Maine, which is the first state to receive a pass under the new health care, is holding some interesting public discussions this week. Anthem Blue Cross Blue Shield, which is part of for-profit insurer WellPoint, is asking for an increase in rates of nearly 10 percent for people who buy health insurance on their own. Regulators and the insurer have a long history in the state, so be prepared for a lot of back and forth. You can find more of the details about the proposed public session in an Associated Press story that ran on Sunday. The Food and Drug Administration will be talking innovation this week. On Tuesday, the agency will be holding a public day-long meeting about innovation in medical devices. The session will feature panel discussions with a range of participants from industry and academia.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>In Medicine, New Isn’t Always Improved</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=68ebfabd20c6c13c953800c4cc5793b4
        </link>
        <pubDate>25 Jun 2011 7:10:23 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                IT is an American impulse to covet the new and improved — whether it’s a faster computer, a smarter cellphone or a more fuel-efficient car. And in medicine, too, new drugs, devices and procedures have advanced patient care. But the promise of innovation can also prove a trap, a situation now playing out with dire consequences for possibly tens of thousands of people who received artificial hips intended to let them remain active. The implants, known as metal-on-metal hips, were regarded by device makers and surgeons as a major advance over previous designs that used both metal and plastic. Now federal regulators and medical researchers are scrambling to determine how many implant recipients have been injured by the devices, which can shed dangerous metallic debris through wear. In a highly unusual move, the Food and Drug Administration last month ordered manufacturers of all metal hips to undertake emergency. A review of the medical world’s embrace of the metal-on-metal hips over the past decade — including interviews with doctors, industry consultants, regulators, medical experts and patients — shows how innovation’s lure led almost everyone to seize on a product promoted as a breakthrough without convincing evidence that it was better or even as good as existing options. “As a non-American, I don’t completely understand it, but there is a phenomenon in the U.S., the latest and the greatest,” said Dr. Henrik Malchau, who practiced as an orthopedic surgeon in Sweden before going to Massachusetts General Hospital in Boston. “There was a patient demand to get these implants on the misconception that the latest was the best.”
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>Revisiting Bone Drugs and Femur Fractures</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=4d96851a507b849daf3a2a144d0edeff
        </link>
        <pubDate>6 Mar 2011 14:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                Nearly six years ago in this column, I discussed what was then a little-known problem associated with long-term use of bisphosphonates, the valuable drugs that protect against fractures caused by bone loss. The drugs, among them Fosamax, Actonel and Boniva, can slow bone loss, increase bone density and cut fracture rates in half in women with established osteoporosis. Reports had begun to emerge that some women taking bisphosphonates for many years suffered an unusual fracture of the femur, the long bone of the thigh. There was little or no trauma; in most cases the women were simply standing or walking when the femur snapped in half. In some, breaks occurred in both thighs, and many of the fractures were unusually slow to heal. Experts think the fractures happened because of the way the drugs work: by slowing the rate of bone remodeling, the normal process by which injured bone heals. As a result, microfractures that occur through normal wear and tear are not repaired. Although bone density may be normal, the bone can become brittle and crack under minor stress. In the years since, hundreds of cases of atypical femur fractures have been reported among women and some men taking bisphosphonates for five or more years. A number of studies have tried to assess the risk, and last fall the Food and Drug Administration issued a “safety announcement” and required that the drugs’ labels warn physicians and patients to be alert for this potential complication. But many questions remain, including who is most at risk for femur fractures and whether the risks outweigh the important benefits of taking a bisphosphonate for many years. The latest assessment was published Feb. 23 in The Journal of the American Medical Association by a team of physicians and epidemiologists in Toronto.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    <item>
        <title>When the Battle With Cancer Can’t Be Won</title>
        <link>
            http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=4224183a65e4b239908c69b1cb558307
        </link>
        <pubDate>16 Feb 2011 14:22:43 +0000</pubDate>
        <category>
            <![CDATA[ ? ]]>
        </category>
        <description>
            <![CDATA[
                “A diagnosis of advanced cancer is usually difficult for you and your family,” the booklet says.  There’s an understatement. But since the very word “cancer” can cause ears and brains to shut down, this 24-page guide from the American Society of Clinical Oncology strikes me as both honest and helpful. “Advanced Cancer Care Planning: What Patients and Families Need to Know About Their Choices When Facing Serious Illness” doesn’t evade the facts; it points out that by definition “advanced cancer” can’t be cured.  In this context, “advanced” is synonymous with “end-stage” or “terminal,” though that doesn’t mean that it’s untreatable or that death is imminent. In fact, it’s because patients will most likely face a number of choices — how and whether to treat, whether to enter clinical trials, whether and when to opt for palliative care or hospice — that a conversation-starter like this makes sense.  The free, downloadable booklet includes sections on costs, advance directives, emotional and spiritual needs. It ends with a list of questions to ask your health care team.  The authors recognize that doctor-speak requires translation, so after you ask, “What is the diagnosis?,” they prompt you to follow up with, “What does this mean?” Because we know that families often complain that they wish they’d turned to hospice or palliative care earlier, and because we know that some physicians (and patients) have trouble even saying “terminal” or “hospice,” this publication could ease the way for people with other diagnoses than cancer.  The questions will be much the same, and help in framing them just as valuable.
            ]]>
        </description>
    </item>
    
</rss>
