<rss>
	<item>
		<title>Chelsea and Birmingham in Cup Do-Over?</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>18 Feb 2011 14:15:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Chelsea faces a replay at second-tier Birmingham City in the fifth round of England’s F.A. Cup after Saturday’s 1-1 draw put more pressure on Coach André Villas-Boas. Birmingham City lost its captain, Stephen Carr, to an injury in the 12th minute but took the lead at Stamford Bridge in London eight minutes later on a goal by David Murphy. Chelsea earned a penalty in the 22nd minute, but goalkeeper Colin Doyle saved Juan Mata’s kick, and Chelsea needed an equalizer in the 62nd by Daniel Sturridge to salvage the draw. In other F.A. Cup matches, Sunderland surprised visiting Arsenal, 2-0; second-tier Leicester eliminated Norwich, 2-1; Everton beat Blackpool, 2-0; and Bolton won at Millwall, 2-0. Continue reading the main stor MORE BAD NEWS FOR RANGERS Rangers’ troubles deepened with a 1-0 Scottish Premier League defeat against Kilmarnock and the loss of their unbeaten home record. Four days after the 140-year-old Glasgow club had 10 points deducted for seeking bankruptcy protection, Rangers lost after Dean Shiels scored in the 12th minute. Sasa Papac was sent off as the defending champions’ first loss in 14 matches at Ibrox also ended a run of eight straight home wins over Kilmarnock.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Promoting Science, and Google, to Students</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>3 Apr 2011 05:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Google is synonymous with “search engine,” and now, for students, it wants to be synonymous with “science.” The company is getting into the science fair business with its first Google Science Fair, a global competition for teenagers that spans sciences as diverse as computer engineering, space exploration and medical technology. The event does not have the name recognition and deep roots of the science fairs from companies like Intel or Siemens, but for most children, Google is the most familiar company of the three. With the science fair, Google aims to play an even bigger role in their lives by encouraging young scientists to experiment — and to use Google products while they’re at it. Google’s science fair is different from the others in a major way: entrants submit their projects online, using Google products like Gmail, YouTube and Google Docs and Sites. It’s the modern-day version of showing up at the school gymnasium to demonstrate lava-spewing volcanoes or bacteria colonies in petri dishes The goal, Google said, is for students to be able to enter even if they live too far from a science fair or if their schools lack the resources to travel to the most prestigious fairs. Monday is the last day for science-minded teenagers to enter the competition. “The science fairs of today have not changed much in years — they’re still in gymnasiums with cardboard and glue,” said Tom Oliveri, a Google spokesman for the science fair. “So we can use the Web to reach a lot more students.” It also serves another purpose. By putting its products in the hands of budding scientists, Google is trying to make its brand central to students’ lives, just as Nike does when it outfits top high school football teams.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>A U.S. Portrait, in Numbers</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>7 Jan 2011 8:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Forget that adage about death and taxes: since 2000, both the death rate and the tax rate in the United States have declined. But the number of individuals reporting income of $1 million or more rose to 392,000 in 2007 from 240,000 when the decade began. And who knew that most Americans of Armenian ancestry live in the West? These are just a few of the factoids that can be gleaned from the 130th edition of the Statistical Abstract of the United States, the annual profile of the country published on Thursday by the Census Bureau. This year’s edition adds 65 categories of data, including the number of recent earthquakes (a high for the decade of 4,256 in 2009) and people who say they cannot sleep (the most rested seem to be men and high school dropouts). Compared with  2000, there are more atheists and Wiccans, fewer Unitarians and Jews. The consumption of fresh vegetables declined. And here are two more tidbits to digest: five states now have more pigs than people, and twice as many young adults bowl as ride bicycles. Collectively, the new tables paint an impressionistic portrait of the nation by the numbers. Individually, they reveal some tantalizing — if not always flattering — details.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Research Center to Focus on Cancer Genes</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>7 May 2011 13:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		To Dr. Susan Domchek, an oncologist at the University of Pennsylvania, the phone call from Jon and Mindy Gray last summer was no different from many others she has received from people seeking information about genetic mutations that can cause cancer. She spoke with the couple for an hour or so, and afterward gave it little thought. “This is embarrassing,” she recalled. “I had no idea who they were.” Nor did she realize that she had just closed a $25 million deal. Mr. Gray, 42, is a superstar in the financial world, the global head of real estate at the investment firm Blackstone. Mrs. Gray, 41, had lost a sister to ovarian cancer caused by an inherited mutation in a gene called BRCA. The couple had been looking for the best place to start a major center for research, counseling, cancer prevention and treatment for people with BRCA mutations. After speaking with Dr. Domchek, they decided that place was the University of Pennsylvania. Both had attended college there. The Basser Research Center — named for Mrs. Gray’s sister, Faith Basser — is expected to open in July with Dr. Domchek as its executive director. It will be the first comprehensive center to focus on a specific set of mutations known to cause cancer. Cancer experts say that what may appear to be an extremely narrow research focus actually has broad implications. Mutations in two genes, BRCA1 and BRCA2, are estimated to cause 5 percent to 10 percent of breast cancers and 10 percent to 15 percent of ovarian cancers among white women in the United States. The mutations are found in other racial and ethnic groups, too, but there is not enough data to tell how common they are. In all groups, the mutations increase the risk of certain other cancers as well.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Colombian Rebels Kill 4 Hostages</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>26 Nov 2011 05:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Colombian rebels executed four members of the security forces who had been held hostage by the group for years, prompted by a failed mission to rescue the men, Colombian officials said. The Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia, which is known as the FARC and has a policy of killing hostages if troops approach their camps, shot three of the captives in the head and the fourth in the back, President Juan Manuel Santos said. The bodies were in chains, he said. “These heroes of Colombia sacrificed their lives trying to bring peace to Colombia,” he said. Colombia has been wracked by bloodshed from guerrillas and cocaine barons for decades, but the FARC, once a powerful force that controlled large parts of Colombia, has been severely weakened. Troops opened the rescue operation, in the southern province of Caqueta, 45 days ago after a tip that the FARC captives were being held in the area.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>WHAT'S NEW IN FOOD BANKS; Bringing the Bounty into the Bank</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>4 Oct 1987 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		TODAY'S food banks rarely reflect their often-makeshift origins. New Jersey's Community Food Bank, which found its first home in founder Kathleen DiChiara's automobile, has a new 43,000-square-foot warehouse. Second Harvest members must meet rigid standards concerning food handling, warehousing, sanitation and modes of transportation for food. Computerization reassures donors that the food has not been waylaid as a bingo hall prize or flea market best buy, but has reached its promised destination. But that is the final result. Getting the donations in the first place is a challenge that food bankers seem to welcome. The methods are as different as the banks and people who run them. The Los Angeles Regional Food Bank will again be sponsoring its GTE/Raiders Food Day - post-football strike schedules permitting - on which fans will be asked to bring cans of food to a Raiders football game. Last year, Raiders fans contributed 7.76 tons of non-perishable food and employees of GTE collected 6.69 tons. In Ohio, corporate employees were given an opportunity to make a financial contribution to the Mid-Ohio Food Bank in Columbus by patronizing a ''country store.'' Stores were set up at various corporations during a 10-week period and stocked with much-needed food bank items - particularly infant formula and high-protein fare like tuna and peanut butter. William J. Ennis, executive director of the Westside Food Bank in Phoenix, Ariz. is spearheading a first-of-its-kind effort to set up a canning program, starting with ''anything that can be juiced.''
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
</rss>
