<rss>
	<item>
		<title>At Manchester United, Ferguson Will Play His Hand?</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>3 Mar 2011 06:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		He may see things that others cannot most of the time, but right now it seems that Alex Ferguson is blind to an issue in need of an urgent solution. Either that or he refuses to admit recognizing what everyone else perceives as a problem at Manchester United. When a journalist questioned Ferguson about his team’s depleted, and frankly anemic, central midfield presence at a news conference last month, Ferguson issued a typically barbed retort. He said he did not know why people insist he needs to sign a new midfielder. But what did Ferguson really mean? Was he honestly opposing the consensus? Ferguson’s (failed) attempt to lure the Dutch playmaker Wesley Sneijder to Old Trafford last summer contradicts his current stance. So does his insistence on using Phil Jones, bought primarily as a defender, and United’s most talented striker, Wayne Rooney, in midfield. Since Inter refused to lower it asking price for Sneijder, United has lost Tom Cleverley to an ankle injury (set to return in February) and Darren Fletcher to a mysterious bowel condition. Coupled with the retirement of Paul Scholes and a dramatic downturn in form from Anderson, United’s midfield has rarely looked so frail. The analysis of United’s early exit from the Champions League focused intensely on the midfield’s weaknesses. Ferguson fielded five defenders, four wings and a striker in the critical defeat to Basel in Switzerland, but not a single natural central midfielder. Jones and Ryan Giggs were asked to play in the center, as has often been the case this season. But while the pairing created a high level of possession, it lacked the creative spark required to break down a Champions League side away from home. A similar thing happened in Wednesday’s 3-0 defeat at Newcastle.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Google Unveils Superfast Internet in Kansas City, Mo.</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>26 Jul 2012 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Encouraging residents here to rally each other, Google on Thursday unveiled the highly anticipated details of its new ultrahigh-speed Internet network, which is supposed to run 100 times faster than typical broadband connections. The service, known as Google Fiber, will offer residents in selected parts of the metropolitan area in both Kansas and Missouri the option of purchasing the gigabit Internet service for $70 a month or both the Internet and a television service for $120 a month. The TV service, Google said, comes with a Nexus 7 tablet that serves as a remote. The announcement, made in a plaza on the Kansas-Missouri state line, is Google’s venture into a world of broadband providers who have looked skeptically at the company’s effort. Some have branded it a publicity stunt that will do little to advance the country’s broadband agenda. Typical broadband providers undertake the costly task of providing service to millions of homes, while Google’s prototype will reach far fewer customers – the initial round here is available to about 170,000 homes. But Google executives said they were hoping to bring Internet speeds up to date with existing technology, noting that the current average household broadband speed was only slightly faster than it was 16 years ago when it was first introduced in homes. “The next phase of the Internet, the next chapter of the Internet is written here today,” Patrick Pichette, Google’s chief financial officer, said in an interview after a presentation that included video demonstrations. Mr. Pichette and other Google executives were noticeably coy about whether the model announced on Thursday would be expanded nationwide. Instead, they said they were focusing on maximizing the product in Kansas City.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Security on Higher Alert Across U.S.</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>4 May 2011 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		There have been no known specific or credible threats received since American troops killed Osama bin Laden this week, but on Tuesday security at public spaces — including mosques, synagogues, train stations and basketball arenas — remained at elevated levels. Although the Department of Homeland Security has not issued an alert, the agency remains at what the homeland security secretary, Janet Napolitano, has called a “heightened state of vigilance.” The State Department, on the other hand, has issued a worldwide travel alert to Americans. In Philadelphia, the police commissioner, Charles H. Ramsey, has placed the department on “high alert,” increased patrols around religious buildings, and intensified security at tourist attractions and shopping malls, the police said. “We haven’t added more personnel; we’re just doing more checks and asking our officers and citizens to be more aware,” said Lt. Ray Evers, a police spokesman. The additional security includes hourly checks at some of the city’s synagogues and mosques, as well as arranging meetings with building superintendents and representatives of large businesses and manufacturers to remind them to report suspicious activity to the police, Lieutenant Evers said.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Genetic Aberrations Seen as Path to Stop Colon Cancer</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>18 Jul 2012 08:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		More than 200 researchers investigating colon cancer tumors have found genetic vulnerabilities that could lead to powerful new treatments. The hope is that drugs designed to strike these weak spots will eventually stop a cancer that is now almost inevitably fatal once it has spread. Scientists increasingly see cancer as a genetic disease defined not so much by where it starts — colon, liver, brain, breast — but by genetic aberrations that are its Achilles’ heel. And with a detailed understanding of which genetic changes make a cancer grow and thrive, they say they can figure out how best to mount an attack. They caution that most of the drugs needed to target the colon cancer mutations have yet to be developed, but they say they are building the road map that they hope will lead them to new treatments. The colon cancer study, published on Wednesday in Nature, is the first part of a sweeping effort that is expected to produce a flood of discoveries for a wide range of cancers. The colon cancer findings will soon be followed by studies of lung and breast cancers and, later this year, of acute myeloid leukemia. The effort, the $100-million-a-year Cancer Genome Atlas project, is being financed by two government agencies, the National Cancer Institute and the National Human Genome Research Institute. The colon cancer results, based on a study of 224 tumors, show what may be possible. “There are so many different ways that you can attack this tumor type,” said Raju Kucherlapati, the principal investigator for the colon cancer project and a professor of genetics and of medicine at Harvard Medical School. “We have an opportunity to completely change the landscape. Researchers caution, though, that although much is known about the genetic changes that occur in colon cancer, treatment has not caught up. “It is going to take time, and it is going to take effort,” said Dr. Charles Fuchs, a gastrointestinal cancer expert at Harvard who was an author of the study. But, he added: “I don’t want to minimize the singular importance of this paper. It is transformative.”
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Rebel Group in Colombia Announces Cease-Fire</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>19 Nov 2012 22:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Colombia’s main rebel group announced a unilateral two-month cease-fire on Monday, as guerrilla representatives sat down with government negotiators in Havana for peace talks aimed at ending a nearly 50-year war. The government did not immediately respond to the cease-fire announcement. President Juan Manuel Santos has repeatedly said that his government would not declare a truce during negotiations with the group, the Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia, known as the FARC. He hopes to avoid mistakes made in an earlier round of talks that ended in 2002, in which the FARC used a lengthy truce to gain strength. The two-month cease-fire was announced by the head of the FARC negotiating team, Iván Márquez. Reading a communiqué, he said all guerrilla units in Colombia were ordered to stop offensive military activities, including the sabotage of infrastructure, beginning Tuesday and lasting until Jan. 20. The communiqué, which was posted on the FARC’s Web site, said that the cease-fire pledge was meant to “strengthen the climate of understanding necessary so that the parties that are starting the dialogue achieve the purpose desired by all Colombians.” The government’s head negotiator, Humberto de la Calle, said before leaving Bogotá for Havana on Sunday that “there will be no concessions of a military character nor a cease-fire.” He added, “We are aware of the pain and anguish caused by the conflict, but in the past, the cease-fire has created advantages for the guerrillas that cannot be repeated.”
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>AHOULD BANKS CROSS STATE LINES?; A VITAL ALTERNATIVE FOR FAILING BANKS</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>22 Jun 1986 22:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		THIS week, the House Banking Committee will begin considering a bill that would permit emergency acquisitions of failing banks by out-of-state financial institutions. In view of the current economic distress in the farm belt and energy-producing states, as well as the pressures on the Government's deposit insurance funds, speedy passage of the legislation is essential. The ''regulators' bill'' - so-called because it is backed by the Secretary of the Treasury, the Federal Reserve Board, the Federal Home Loan Bank Board, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation - recognizes the fact that economic cycles today tend to affect regions unevenly. Thus, if a particular region is hit hard, even the strongest banks in that area may be unable to lend assistance to neighboring financial institutions. Regrettably, consumer groups see in the emergency atmosphere an excellent opportunity to advance their agenda. They are urging Congress to tighten further the regulatory noose that for more than half a century has constrained the ability of banks to compete. Specifically, they are pushing for a test to prove that interstate acquisitions would not dilute local competition, for public disclosure of the acquiring bank's community reinvestment record and for disclosure of the geographic placement of loans by the acquired bank. These amendments are not only unnecessary, but would be destructive as well. The sort of acquisitions that would be allowed under the bill would take place at the 11th hour, expressly to rescue a failing bank. To further encumber this process with unrelated tests - in a time of emergency -runs counter to the best interests of the community concerned. Moreover, the bill already provides that neighboring institutions should have preference in rescuing their failing neighbors.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
</rss>
