<rss>
	<item>
		<title>Van Persie and Arsenal End Liverpool’s Perfect League Record at Home</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244	
		</link>
		<pubDate>3 Mar 2011 17:43:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Robin van Persie scored his second goal of the game, in second-half injury time, to give Arsenal a 2-1 win at Liverpool in a match in England’s Premier League that Liverpool had dominated. In the third of eight minutes of second-half injury time, van Persie hit a volley past goalkeeper José Reina at the near post to end Liverpool’s unbeaten home record of 13 games this season and strengthen Arsenal’s chances of qualifying for next season’s UEFA Champions League. Arsenal goalkeeper Wojciech Szczesny had saved a penalty and rebound effort from Dirk Kuyt before Liverpool took a lead in the 23rd minute on an own-goal by Laurent Koscielny. Van Persie tied the score eight minutes later, heading in Bacary Sagna’s cross from the right. Van Persie, a striker from the Netherlands, has scored 31 goals this season for the Gunners in all competitions. “To score at Anfield is big because Anfield is a massive ground,” van Persie said. “I’m proud of that, but even more proud of this win. I don’t think we really deserved it to be honest because Liverpool played better.” Elsewhere, Chelsea’s chances of qualifying for next season’s Champions League and André Villas-Boas’s chances of keeping his job as coach took a hit in a 1-0 loss at West Bromwich Albion. League-leading Manchester City rode an own goal and a score by Mario Balotelli to a 2-0 win against Bolton. LEVERKUSEN BEATS MUNICH Bayer Leverkusen beat visiting Bayern Munich, 2-0, with two late goals to deal Bayern a serious blow to its Bundesliga title hopes in Germany. Stefan Kiessling put the host ahead in the 79th minute, and Karim Bellarabi put the result beyond doubt in the last minute with his first goal for Leverkusen.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Google’s Digital Music Service Falls Short of Ambition</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>10 May 2011 23:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Google had big plans for its new digital music service. It wanted an online store to compete with iTunes and Amazon, as well as a “smart locker” storage system in which the company would stream music to its millions of users from a gigantic central jukebox. But the service that the company unveiled on Tuesday, called Music Beta by Google, fell short of those ambitions. There is no store, the streaming function comes with restrictions, and, like Amazon’s Cloud Drive service announced in March, using it requires a long upload process. What came between Google and its ambitions was an obstacle familiar to many digital music start-ups: despite months of negotiations, the company could not obtain licenses from the major record companies. In interviews, Google executives put the blame squarely on the labels. “Generally there were demands on the business side that we think were unreasonable and don’t enable us to have a sustainable, scalable music business,” said Zahavah Levine, director of content partnerships for Google’s Android unit and the lead negotiator with the labels. Music Beta was introduced on Tuesday at Google I/O, a developers’ conference in San Francisco. Neither Google nor the labels would specify which points they stumbled over. But their disagreement follows a long pattern of friction in which the labels demand high prices for licenses or withhold the licenses altogether. The stubbornness of the labels has earned them a particular caricature in Silicon Valley: the bridge troll, demanding payment for passage.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Judging and Ranking U.S. Presidents</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>29 Jul 2012 15:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		American political junkies are being treated to a feast this summer: David Maraniss’s acclaimed new book on Barack Obama, the durable Mitt Romney biography by two Boston Globe reporters and, of course, another installment of Robert Caro’s classic series on Lyndon B. Johnson. After reading those, they also might want to pick up Robert Merry’s “Where They Stand: The American Presidents in the Eyes of Voters and Historians,” an analysis of how presidents fare with historians and why. It would make especially instructive reading for Mr. Obama and Mr. Romney. The inspiration for Mr. Merry, a former Washington reporter and editor and author of three other books dealing with U.S. politics, was an interview with Mr. Obama in which he said he’d “rather be a really good one-term president than a mediocre two-term president.” Mr. Merry discovers that’s pretty much a historical non sequitur. The only one-term president who rates highly in historians’ surveys is James K. Polk, who acquired the Oregon territories and California, and annexed Texas after a war with Mexico. (Mr. Merry has written a biography of Polk, a thoroughly pedestrian man who has been described as America’s “least-known consequential president.” Great presidencies usually are born through crises. Abraham Lincoln preserved the Union. Franklin D. Roosevelt led the nation through the Great Depression and World War II. George Washington defined the office. Every major survey considers those the three greatest. (The Lincoln-era bookends James Buchanan and Andrew Johnson are invariably rated among the worst.)
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>New Cancer Threat Lurks Long After Cure</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>16 Jul 2012 16:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Watching Robin Roberts tear up in front of millions of viewers on “Good Morning America” last month, I cried, too. With equal measures of courage and fear, Ms. Roberts, an anchor of the show and a breast cancer survivor, explained that the life-saving treatment she received five years ago was responsible for a new diagnosis, this time myelodysplastic syndrome (MDS), a rare blood and bone marrow disease once called preleukemia. MDS is a potentially fatal condition that can be caused by radiation and chemotherapy, both of which Ms. Roberts had in her initial cancer treatment. In medical-speak, it’s a “secondary cancer.” As a cancer and chemo survivor, I know that I, too, have a higher likelihood of developing these cancers. hen I was given a diagnosis of testicular cancer in 1984, secondary cancers were primarily a threat for pediatric cancer survivors. Their young bodies are most vulnerable to radiation and chemo, and they have more years in which to develop new malignancies. Also at risk were those beating some of the more “curable” adult cancers because of the highly toxic treatment regimens. Secondary cancers now make up the sixth-most-common group of malignancies, in part because more survivors are living longer. Physicians are better at limiting toxicity from radiation and chemotherapy, so fewer people die from the effects of treatments. The bad news: More people are surviving their original cancers only to be haunted by the prospect of new diagnoses later. Cancer survivors generally fall into one of two groups when it comes to our psychological health. First are those plagued by anxiety, depression, even post-traumatic stress disorder, which may afflict up to 58 percent of us, according to a recent American Cancer Society study. Then there are those who experience heightened self-esteem, a greater appreciation of life and its meaning, and sometimes a new or deeper spirituality.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>More Nuclear Talks With Iran Are Set</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>7 Dec 2010 11:5	0:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Tense talks between Iran, the United States and other world powers ended Tuesday with an agreement to hold another meeting toward the end of January in Istanbul. “Our expectations for this meeting were low, and I can’t say that they’ve been exceeded,” said a senior American official, speaking on the condition of anonymity. He characterized the tenor of the discussions, in which Iran was pressed on its nuclear program, as “difficult and candid.” Still, the official said, the simple fact that Iran agreed to meet in the first place, and to a future meeting as well, was positive, coming after more than a year of domestic friction over Iran’s disputed presidential election and the imposition of a fourth round of United Nations economic sanctions that was followed by additional independent measures from the United States and other nations. Iran had maintained that its nuclear program was not open for discussion, but officials who attended the talks said that, despite Iranian denials, most of the day and a half of meetings focused on the deep concerns of many of Iran’s neighbors and much of the West that the country was trying to build a bomb. Iran maintains that its nuclear program is merely to generate power and create medical isotopes. A senior European official said that the talks evidenced a level of mistrust between Iran and the other powers that could be compared only to the situation with North Korea, and that it was important to continue to offer serious negotiations in combination with the possibility of harsher measures, including further sanctions. But the Iranian side ended the meetings on a note of defiance. The head of its delegation, Saeed Jalili, said at a news conference that the only agenda for the Istanbul meeting was “to have talks for cooperation to find common ground” and insisted that international requests for Iran to halt its enrichment of uranium would not be discussed.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>BUSINESS FORUM: AFTER 'BLACK MONDAY' WHAT NEXT FOR THE BANKS?; Keep Banks From the 'Muni' Market</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>8 Nov 1987 16:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		ON Oct. 12, Salomon Brothers Inc. announced plans to discontinue its municipal bond department and dismiss 12 percent of its work force. News that the company with the largest share of the business was pulling out of the ''muni'' business was the hottest topic - until Oct. 19 when the stock market made history. Though unrelated, these two events may become intertwined within a larger issue: whether it is wise or necessary to grant commercial banks the power to underwrite and market municipal revenue bonds. It is not my place to speculate on Salomon's reasons in abandoning the municipal bond business. But, it must be noted this was the decision of only one company, not the entire industry. Nevertheless, a handful of money center banks are using the Salomon decision to allege that there is no longer the capacity or will on the part of securities firms to underwrite municipal revenue bonds. Nothing could be further from reality. Present law permits banks to underwrite general obligation bonds backed by the ''full faith and credit'' of the issuer. Proposals to amend Federal statutory prohibitions on bank participation in revenue bonds have been before Congress for more than 30 years and the subject of comprehensive hearings on at least 10 occasions. Anyone in Congress or the regulatory agencies who believes he or she is filling a need by amending Federal law to permit the entry of commercial banks into this area is incorrect. The 500 or so securities firms that underwrite municipals are eager to fill the void left by Salomon's exit from the market.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
</rss>
