<rss>
	<item>
		<title>Fulham Beats Arsenal</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>2 Jan 2012 22:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Steve Sidwell tied the score in the 85th minute and Bobby Zamora got the go-ahead goal in the second minute of stoppage time, giving Fulham a 2-1 victory over Arsenal that knocked the Gunners from the top four in England’s Premier League. Laurent Koscielny’s 21st-minute goal on a header put Arsenal ahead, but the Gunners played a man short after Johan Djourou was ejected for his second yellow card after a rough tackle in the 78th. Chelsea took over the fourth spot with a 2-1 victory at Wolverhampton, easing the pressure on Manager André Villa-Boas. Frank Lampard scored the tiebreaking goal in the 89th minute, ending the Blues’ four-game winless streak.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Facebook’s Purchases May Hint at Its Future</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>13 May 2011 10:34:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Facebook’s billion-dollar purchase of Instagram made a lot of noise — so much noise that few people noticed when the company snapped up two more start-ups just a few days later. The shopping spree that snagged Tagtile and Glancee was just business as usual for Facebook. It buys small companies on a regular basis — almost two dozen over the last two years — to beef up its team of talented engineers, add to the site’s offerings and sharpen competition with rivals. Because Facebook tends to be tight-lipped about its plans, the company’s string of acquisitions reveals a lot about how Mark Zuckerberg, the chief executive, is charting a course for its future — and potentially sheds some light on what, and who, may be next on the company’s shopping list. The social networking juggernaut does not generally do a lot of long-term planning for its mergers and acquisitions. “They are a fairly nimble company,” said Paul Buchheit, an entrepreneur who created the first version of Gmail for Google and is now a partner at Y Combinator, a popular incubator of tech start-ups in Silicon Valley. “They don’t have a five-year plan for companies they want to buy. When they see a company that makes sense, they focus on getting things done quickly. Facebook’s Mark Zuckerberg, at a Turning Point MAY 12, 201 Mr. Buchheit should know. When he sold his start-up, a social network aggregator called FriendFeed, to Facebook in 2009, the deal was completed at a dizzying pace. “I met with Mark on a Friday afternoon,” he said. “By Sunday night, we’d signed papers and announced the deal on Monday.” It was a similarly fast-paced process for Instagram.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>2nd Place in the Division, and in the Heart of Texas</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>22 Oct 2011 09:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Jason Cohen writes a column for the Texas Report. Cowboys fans outside of Dallas who are in the market for a Tony Romo jersey (is anyone still in the market for a Tony Romo jersey?) can hit one of the team’s 41 pro shops, 18 of which are far beyond the Metroplex. There are three in San Antonio, three in the Rio Grande Valley and even one in Katy, a mere 40 miles from Reliant Stadium, where the Houston Texans have been playing in the N.F.L. for 10 seasons. Needless to say, there is not a Texans pro shop anywhere near Cowboys Stadium in Arlington. Texans fans who live outside of Houston struggle to even find gear. “Every year, I go to Academy, or Dick’s or whatever to buy Texans stuff,” said Norm Andrighetti, 40, a Texans fan in Austin. “And nobody ever has anything.” This is not merely the skewed perception of a sad-sack fan base. Last year, Elise Hasbrook, a spokeswoman for Academy Sports and Outdoors, told The Houston Chronicle that the chain’s stores in San Antonio didn’t carry Texans merchandise. Why would they? Spurs fans hate the Mavericks, but “everyone I know who’s a Spurs fan is also a Cowboys fan,” said John Wessling, a Houston stand-up comic who is a co-host of “Houston Game Day” on ESPN 97.5 FM.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>When Treating Cancer Is Not an Option</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>19 Nov 2012 12:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		When my husband learned he had advanced lung cancer, he didn’t even want to speak to an oncologist about chemotherapy. He saw no point in treatment that could not cure him and might make him feel worse. Not so, though, for a majority of patients diagnosed with cancers of the lung or colon that have spread well beyond their original site and are currently not curable by any drugs in the medical armamentarium. Most patients with these so-called stage 4 cancers who choose to undergo chemotherapy seem to believe, incorrectly, that the drugs could render them cancer-free. That is the finding of a recent national study of nearly 1,200 patients with advanced cancers of the lung or colon. Overall, 69 percent of those with stage 4 lung cancer and 81 percent of those with stage 4 colon cancer failed to understand “that chemotherapy was not at all likely to cure their cancer,” Dr. Jane C. Weeks, an oncology researcher at the Dana-Farber Cancer Institute in Boston, and colleagues reported in The New England Journal of Medicine. When patients do not understand the limitations of such treatment, their consent to undergo it is not truly informed, the authors concluded. This is not to say that chemotherapy is pointless when cancer is far advanced. Various drugs, some with limited toxicity, can be used as palliatives, perhaps shrinking tumors temporarily to relieve symptoms, slowing the cancer’s growth and prolonging the lives of some patients. But aggressive chemotherapy when death is but weeks or months in the offing can seriously compromise the quality of patients’ remaining time and may delay their preparations for the end of life, to the detriment of both patients and their families. “If you think chemotherapy will cure you, you’re less open to end-of-life discussions,” Dr. Weeks said in an interview. When patients pursue chemotherapy under the false belief that they still have a chance for a cure, it often delays their transition to the comfort care of hospice. When patients spend only a few days or a week in hospice, caretakers don’t have enough time to get to know them and their families and offer the physical, emotional and practical benefits hospice can provide.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Iran Nuclear Plans Start New Calls for Sanctions</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>8 Feb 2010 15:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		 Iran told the United Nations nuclear watchdog agency on Monday that it would begin enriching its stockpile of uranium for use in a medical reactor, prompting officials from the United States, France and Russia to call for stronger sanctions against Tehran. Late Monday in Vienna, the International Atomic Energy Agency confirmed that it had received a letter from Iran declaring its intent to begin enriching uranium up to 20 percent. The agency’s statement gave no date for starting the enrichment, though Tehran said that might come as early as Tuesday. Tehran’s decision elicited a sharp reaction in the West. In Paris, the visiting United States defense secretary, Robert M. Gates, said the Obama administration and its allies had done all they could to entice Iran to negotiate. “All of these initiatives have been rejected,” he said. While “we must still try and find a peaceful way to resolve this issue, ” he said, “the only path that is left to us at this point, it seems to me, is that pressure track. But it will require all of the international community to work together.” Even in Russia, which along with China has consistently resisted sanctions against Iran, there were calls for stronger action against Tehran. Konstantin I. Kosachyov, the head of the foreign affairs committee in the lower house of the Russian Parliament, was quoted by the Interfax news agency as urging the international community to prepare “serious measures.” At issue is a proposal for Iran to send its uranium stockpile outside the country to be enriched and processed into fuel rods for use in the medical reactor. This was attractive to the West because it would deprive Iran of stockpiles that it could convert into bomb fuel, while providing Tehran with fuel rods that would be very difficult to use in a weapon. Iran was reported last October to have accepted the proposal, but later backed away. Western officials say Iran has rejected the deal, but Tehran accuses the West of failing to respond to its proposals.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Rocky Road Ahead for Big Banks</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>15 Jan 2016 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		America’s too-big-to-fail cabal is nursing $130 billion in damages. That’s the amount of market value lost by the nation’s top six banks in the last two weeks. The shares of all but Wells Fargo now trade below book value, suggesting stockholders are bracing for a year or more of pain. Whether they’re right looks like a tossup. Few banks ended 2015 on a high note. JPMorgan Chase, which reported fourth-quarter earnings on Thursday, needed a few one-time boosts to eke out an annualized return on equity of 9 percent – just below the 10 percent considered necessary to cover the cost of capital. Citigroup managed just 6 percent for the three months to December. Wells hit a decent 12.2 percent, but as with rivals, revenue is barely growing. Yet all are doing more business: JPMorgan’s core loans rose 16 percent last year, and credit losses are near record lows. Banks will have very little leeway once debt problems arise. Those seem limited at the moment to the energy sector, with low unemployment and falling oil prices cause for optimism. And if the Federal Reserve raises interest rates again, banks should earn a bit more, though not enough to substantially increase returns. Low or nonexistent growth is nothing new, though. What’s changed is that investors are increasingly concerned that China’s troubles presage global economic problems that could hobble America’s plodding recovery. As a result, Citi and Bank of America are trading at less than two-thirds of book value. Morgan Stanley has fallen to 75 percent of assets minus liabilities, Goldman Sachs to 92 percent and JPMorgan to 94 percent. That means shareholders are assuming either that the banks will earn less than expected or that the value of loans, bonds and other assets on their balance sheets is overstated – or both. Bank of America, Goldman and Morgan Stanley have also dropped below tangible book value, which strips out good will from acquisitions and other amorphous assets. That’s a dubious distinction that in the last year or two was limited to Citi.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
</rss>
