<rss>
	<item>
		<title>With a Goal, Scholes Puts United Back in the Hunt</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>14 Jan 2012 09:25:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Paul Scholes scored his first goal since ending his short-lived retirement to help Manchester United to a 3-0 win over visiting Bolton in England’s Premier League on Saturday. In the second match of his comeback, Scholes turned in Wayne Rooney’s cross in the 45th minute for his first goal since August 2010. It was Scholes’s 151st league goal, and it helped United pull two points ahead of third-place Tottenham, which tied, 1-1, with relegation-threatened Wolverhampton. United trails the Manchester City on goal difference, although City can restore its three-point lead by beating Wigan on Monday. Six months after ending a career during which he only played for United, the 37-year-old Scholes returned in last weekend’s F.A. Cup win at Manchester City. On Saturday, he became the oldest Englishman to score a league goal for United.
“It was a surprise to see him at the far post,” United Manager Alex Ferguson said of Scholes. “With his age and the fact he has just come back, we were looking for him to control central midfield, which he did. “But he has the instinct. He always has had.” Danny Welbeck made it 2-0 in the 74th minute from another assist by Rooney, and Michael Carrick completed the scoring with seven minutes remaining. Rooney had a first-half penalty kick saved by goalkeeper Adam Bogdan. Tottenham dominated visiting Wolves at White Hart Lane but Steven Fletcher put the visitors ahead from a rebound in the 22nd minute after Spurs goalkeeper Brad Friedel parried Roger Johnson’s header from a corner. Emmanuel Adebayor had a goal disallowed for offside just before halftime before Luka Modric tied the score in the 51st. City and United have 48 points, two more than Tottenham. Chelsea is another six points back in the final Champions League qualifying position after beating Sunderland, 1-0, on Frank Lampard’s goal.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Facebook vs. the Wireless Industry</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>18 May 2012 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Facebook this month introduced App Center, an app store similar to Apple’s and Google’s. In the store, Facebook users will be able to buy Web apps for smartphones; each sale gives Facebook a 30 percent cut, leaving the developer with 70 percent. But unlike Apple’s and Google’s app stores, Facebook’s gives the carriers  the potential to make some money through a partnership with Facebook to streamline Web-based payments. With the new system, people programming Web apps for Facebook will be able to embed some code to make charges appear on a user’s phone bill, so they don’t have to enter a credit card number to buy an app. Web apps that use this system will give both carriers and Facebook a chunk of each sale Facebook’s huge popularity has given many customers a reason to buy smartphones as opposed to traditional cellphones. And smartphones — in particular, the data plans that customers pay for to get on the Internet — have driven enormous revenue for carriers. ATT and Verizon, for example, both had $6 billion in revenue last quarter from mobile data alone.
Facebook in some cases is letting carriers use its popularity to attract users. Some South American carriers are shipping phones with data plans that use Facebook as the sole gateway to the Internet. Here are some ways Facebook is bad for carriers: Thanks partly to the ease of posting status updates, uploading photos and sending messages with the Facebook mobile app, carriers are seeing a decline in text-message revenue. Strand Consult, a telecommunications consulting firm, says that based on measured minutes of use, smartphone users are spending more time on Facebook and thus probably sending more messages with its service than they are text messages.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Property Tax Is Easy to Hate, but Difficult to Mess With</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>17 Aug 2012 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Ross Ramsey, the managing editor of The Texas Tribune, writes a regular column for the Tribune. The thing about your property tax bill isn’t just that it is big — that, it is. The irritating thing is that if you’re a homeowner or own property for rent, you see it as a lump sum. Sales taxes take lots of money out of the average Texan’s wallet, but they don’t come in at the end of the year in a single bill. You get to see your income tax as a single number every April 15, but most people have already paid most or all of that by the time they see it. And unlike your income tax return, your property tax bill includes what you paid last year — so you can see how much it increased. The tax on property is the biggest source of financing for school districts in Texas, which get 52 percent of their money there, according to a recent report. And with school districts going to court against the state in October to argue about school finance, the whole system — from property taxes to state financing formulas — is up for argument. Property taxes are easy to hate, and politically dangerous to mess with. Sales taxes are based on what you spend. Theoretically, you can control the consumption tax by controlling the consumption. Income taxes float with your income. Make more, pay more. Property taxes change as a result of a kind of black magic. The value of your house is based on the prices agreed to by nearby buyers and sellers. It is mathematical and looks precise, but it’s not science. If it were based on something other than art, there would be no such thing as an appraisal board where you can try to bargain your way out of higher taxes by arguing with the value they put on your humble homestead. Commercial property appraisals are based on any number of things — price, income, development value. And commercial property owners have less political leverage, because homeowners outvote them.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Prognosis: When Cancer Patients Opt for Surgery</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>21 Jun 2010 19:54:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Most lung cancer patients who undergo surgery are still alive three years later, compared with just 10 percent of those who do not. Yet at least one-third of patients choose not to have the operation. Why not? That was the question Dr. Samuel Cykert sought to answer when he and fellow researchers asked 386 new lung cancer patients who were eligible for the operation, called resection, to fill out detailed questionnaires about their backgrounds and access to health care. The results varied by race. Sixty-six percent of the white patients eventually had the operation; the percentage for blacks was 55, said Dr. Cykert, an internist at Moses Cone Hospital in Greensboro, N.C. and the author of a paper published last week in The Journal of the American Medical Association. Patients who reported feeling that they did not communicate well with their doctors were less likely to have the operation, as were those who thought they would not necessarily be better off a year later if they had surgery. Black patients were also less likely to opt for surgery if they had other chronic diseases besides cancer. Having a regular doctor also influenced patients to have surgery. “If you go back to your primary care doctor and he or she says, ‘When’s your surgery?’ and you say, ‘I’m not sure I’m going to have it,’ your doctor will try to get you back in the system,” Dr. Cykert said. By contrast, he continued, if a patient does not have a regular doctor, “you disappear into space and nobody tells you to reconsider.”
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Iran Remains Defiant, Nuclear Agency Says</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>6 Sep 2010 17:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Three months after the United Nations Security Council enacted its harshest sanctions yet against Iran, global nuclear inspectors reported Monday that the country has dug in its heels, refusing to provide inspectors with the information and access they need to determine whether the real purpose of Tehran’s program is to produce weapons. For several weeks the Obama administration has argued that the sanctions are beginning to bite, cutting off Iran’s access to foreign capital, halting investment in its energy sector and impeding its ability to send its ships in and out of some foreign ports. While there are strong indications that Iran is beginning to feel pain — largely from additional sanctions imposed by the United States and European and Asian nations over the summer — the report on Monday from the International Atomic Energy Agency indicates that so far they have failed to force Iran to comply with longstanding requests. The agency protested that Iran had barred two of its most experienced inspectors from the country. They were barred only days after the Security Council passed its latest sanctions, part of a longstanding pattern of reducing access in retaliation for United Nations action. Iran has, however, permitted some other inspectors to enter. The report also reiterated that for two years, since August 2008, Iran has refused to answer questions “about the possible existence in Iran of past or current undisclosed nuclear-related activities involving military-related organizations, including activities related to the development of a nuclear payload for a missile.” The report said it was “essential that Iran engage with the agency on these issues” because evidence can degrade with “the passage of time.”
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>COMPANY NEWS; Barnett Banks Sets Deal to Acquire First Florida</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>19 May 1992 13:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Barnett Banks Inc., seeking to solidify its market-leading position in Florida, said yesterday that it would acquire First Florida Banks Inc. in a merger worth roughly $885 million. The deal would move Barnett, the nation's 18th-largest bank, up one rung to replace Suntrust Banks as the 17th-largest bank in the country. The merger, the latest in a wave of regional consolidations in the banking industry, would add about four percentage points to Barnett's current market share of 23 percent and help distance Barnett from growing competitors, including the First Union Corporation of Charlotte, N.C., for bragging rights as the largest bank in Florida. Terms of the Deal Barnett said the deal, under which First Florida shareholders would receive 1.42 shares of Barnett common stock for each First Florida share, should not dilute Barnett earnings. Barnett offficials said the merged banks would operate more efficiently, in part because two-thirds of First Florida's 144 offices are within a mile of Barnett locations. After the merger, the bank expects to close about 95 branches, some of them current Barnett branches. Barnett, which is based in Jacksonville, Fla., has $32.9 billion in assets and 550 offices in Florida and 42 in Georgia. It is active in commercial lending. First Florida, based in Tampa, has $5.4 billion in assets and operates 144 banks in Florida. Its primary business is in residential lending. The combined bank will have $2.5 billion in equity. Barnett officials acknowledged yesterday that antitrust concerns would probably cause the Justice Department to require a divestiture of some operations.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
</rss>
