<rss>
	<item>
		<title>Jason Garrett Too Cautious in Cowboys’ Defeat</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>28 Jan 2012 02:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Forget that the regular-season overtime rules prevented the Cowboys from even touching the ball after regulation of a 19-13 loss at Arizona – that was merely karmic justice. Any coach that mismanages timeouts and field position as spectacularly as Dallas Coach Jason Garrett did in the final minutes deserves to lose. First, Garrett seemingly iced his own kicker by calling a timeout just before Dan Bailey’s 49-yard field goal on what would have been the game’s final play. (Bailey made the initial kick, but couldn’t repeat it.) Analyzing timeout usage as it pertains to a kicker’s rhythm is like analyzing how your day might have been different if you’d only brushed your teeth three minutes earlier. It’s a fruitless practice that’s all hindsight and presumption. Garrett’s biggest mistake was actually made before Bailey’s kick. When the Cowboys got the ball to the Arizona 31-yard line, they had 31 seconds remaining and two timeouts. Instead of using one of those timeouts, they slowly lined up so that Tony Romo could kill the clock with seven seconds left. They were setting up the game-winning field goal…from 49 yards away! It was almost as if Garrett owed the Fox broadcast a favor. Instead of going for an easier shot at a win, he went for the drama. Another coach might have tried to pick up another 10 or 12 yards. Garrett was content with the Scott Norwood range.  He defended his clock management, saying: “We very well could have taken a timeout there. We felt like we were in field-goal range. We have yard lines that we use as guidelines before the game. We felt like we were in range at that point.” All that means is that the bad decision was made before the game, rather than in the heat of the moment.Extra point Brian Burke of Advanced NFL Stats weighs in: “There is no such thing as field goal range, except in the most technical and useless sense. Closer is always better.”
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>A First Look at Facebook Messenger</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>11 Aug 2011 17:43:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Checking Facebook messages on your phone is now one-tap easy. Facebook has published a new free app for iPhone and Android, Facebook Messenger, that unbundles its private message service from the all-in-one Facebook app. Rather than trying to combine your entire online life into one app, it goes the other way: Messenger, when started, goes straight to your Facebook messages, so you can read and reply to them without having to navigate through all of Facebook. Messenger also pushes messages to the forefront of your phone with optional settings that provide multiple ways for your phone to notify you that you’ve got a new message. On Android it can vibrate, blink, play a sound, or play a ringtone. If you’ve spent as much time as I have tapping though the Facebook app impatiently trying to check messages while the Facebook app tries to load photos and notifications instead, Messenger is a very practical gift. You tap it and poof, up pops your Facebook inbox. That’s it. For me, it’s great because my Facebook inbox contains timely messages from people who want to make plans with me, but who aren’t the professional colleagues in my separate e-mail account, or the guy waiting in the car outside sending me text messages I need to see right this second. I can ignore my Facebook inbox for hours until I have the attention for it. Then, I can check those messages with one thumb-tap while doing something else in the real world. I’m much less likely to get hit by a bus thanks to this thing. I wish more app developers would think this way: Instead of trying to combine everything on the Internet into one mobile interface, create separate apps for stand-alone functions that people perform often and want to do in a hurry. Let the phone’s home screen be the thing that contains and presents them all. Whoever coded this app at Facebook might not win geek points for programming prowess, but they’ve made Facebook more convenient for a lot of users. Can I next get an app that jumps straight to my groups?
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Death Sentence Reviews Leave Unsettled Issues in Texas</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>12 May 2012 22:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Stanley Schneider was shocked last year when Texas’ highest criminal court sent his death row client an early Christmas gift of sorts, ordering the trial court to re-examine evidence from a psychologist who had decided that John Reyes Matamoros was mentally fit to face execution. “We were hopeful their sending it back would mean something,” Mr. Schneider said. But his hope flagged in March when, he said, two Harris County state district judges virtually rubber-stamped Dr. George Denkowski’s findings in the cases of Mr. Matamoros and a fellow death row inmate, Steven Butler. Dr. Denkowski, the psychologist who testified in the cases of 14 current Texas death row inmates that the convicted men were mentally fit for execution, was reprimanded last year after other psychologists and defense lawyers filed a complaint alleging that he had used discredited evaluation methods. Lawyers for Mr. Matamoros and Mr. Butler, who have filed objections with the Texas Court of Criminal Appeals, say any findings by Dr. Denkowski should be disregarded. They said that the trial court judges — who are husband and wife — simply adopted Dr. Denkowski’s conclusions instead of examining reams of evidence from other psychologists that they said proved their clients were mentally retarded and ineligible for the death penalty. “This is a perfect example of the state taking science and trying to prostitute it,” Mr. Schneider said, adding, “The role of the courts is to protect us from junk science.”
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>This Week’s Health Industry News</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>14 Mar 2011 12:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Expect the talk in Washington about the federal health care law to intensify as we approach the one-year anniversary of the passage of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act next week. Congress is holding several hearings, including the Senate Finance Committee meeting on Wednesday morning to discuss “Health Reform: Lessons Learned During the First Year.” On Thursday, the Senate health committee will take a look at the exchanges being developed to offer heath insurance and what the states need to do to implement the new law. Meanwhile, in the House, the oversight committee’s health care subcommittee is holding a hearing on Tuesday about all the waivers federal regulators are granting under the new law. On Thursday, the House Energy and Commerce Committee will take a look at the so-called Class program, a new national insurance plan for long-term care. For those interested in following how this all plays out, Maine, which is the first state to receive a pass under the new health care, is holding some interesting public discussions this week. Anthem Blue Cross Blue Shield, which is part of for-profit insurer WellPoint, is asking for an increase in rates of nearly 10 percent for people who buy health insurance on their own. Regulators and the insurer have a long history in the state, so be prepared for a lot of back and forth.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>NATO Document Addresses Nuclear Disarmament</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>30 Sep 2010 14:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Two months before what could be the most important NATO summit meeting in more than a decade, the 28 member states of the alliance have received a draft of its new strategic concept, which for the first time, at the insistence of Germany and other countries, includes calls for nuclear disarmament. At the same time, according to diplomats who spoke on condition of anonymity, Anders Fogh Rasmussen, NATO’s secretary general, has completed another highly classified document, numbering several hundred pages, that will be attached to the final strategic concept. Mr. Rasmussen’s document sets out in detail how NATO would react and assign units and forces to respond to a range of attacks — terrorist, cyber, conventional, nuclear or other — several diplomats said Thursday. “If you think the strategic concept is classified, you cannot imagine how secretive the operational paper is and will remain,” an East European diplomat said. The members of NATO agreed at their last summit meeting, in April 2009, to update the organization’s 1999 strategic concept, which they said did not address the defense concerns of the 21st century. Even if agreement on the draft is reached in principle at the next gathering, set for Nov. 19-20 in Lisbon, any pact must still be approved by each country, a process that could take considerable time, and any move to ban nuclear arms would face significant practical issues in Europe and the United States. The move by Germany and other nations to place disarmament high in the strategic concept comports with President Barack Obama’s declared goal of eventually abolishing nuclear weapons, but it also exposes a rift between European nations that want to rid the Continent of atomic arms and those that want to keep them both for prestige and as a deterrent to longstanding enemies.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>OIL TRADING IS SLOWER; PRICES FALL</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>23 Jan 1986 11:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Taking a breather from the frenzied trading of earlier this week, prices for crude oil and petroleum products moved lower in sluggish trading yesterday, as traders awaited publication of a key weekly industry report on fuel inventories. On the futures market, crude oil prices declined more than 40 cents a barrel and product prices by about a cent. On the open market the prices of the major British and American crude oils fell by up to 85 cents during trading. While a price move of this magnitude would have been striking in the past, it pales beside daily declines of $1 or more in the last few days. The inventory report, released after the markets closed, indicated that levels of both crude oil and heating oil, as well as the production of heating oil, declined slightly for the first time since the winter began. The report, from the American Petroleum Institute, could have a marginally strengthening effect on prices. Role of Saudi Arabia But while the markets were calm yesterday, the recent sharp break in oil prices has rekindled interest both in Saudi Arabia's role in the unfolding drama and in a novel and disruptive pricing mechanism that the Saudis are using, the netback deal. The netback arrangement, which ties the price of crude oil to the price of the products refined from it, is a relatively new development to the oil world. Ernest J. Wilson 3d, of the Petroleum Finance Company, a Washington-based consulting firm, said Saudi Arabia had used netback deals with ''devastating effect'' to increase its market share.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
</rss>
