<rss>
	<item>
		<title>In Defense of Brian Schottenheimer</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>2 Jan 2012 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		There’s talk of the Jets reshuffling their offensive coaching staff. They’d be fools to let Brian Schottenheimer, one of the best young offensive coordinators in the game, get away. The Jets’ problems pertain to player personnel. They’re constructed to run the ball and win with defense. That’s why they felt comfortable building around a quarterback that has limitations like Mark Sanchez. Game management and defense is a formula that worked for them in ’09 and ’10. This season, their run game flat-lined and Sanchez was exposed as a jittery one-read passer. The Jets must make a decision: do they stick with the run emphasis on offense, which goes against the grain of today’s N.F.L. but is something that defensive aficionado Rex Ryan has pulled off twice before? Or, do they look to upgrade their passing attack? Sticking with the run means finding at least one, and maybe two, new running backs (LaDainian Tomlinson is nearing his end and, after three years, it’s clear that Shonn Greene is a vanilla rotation player). Upgrading the passing attack means finding a new quarterback. It would also mean altering personnel at wide receiver, though that might happen either way, as it’s hard to imagine Santonio Holmes being welcomed back after his display of selfishness down the stretch this season. The Jets were able to acquire Holmes for pennies on the dollar before last season because of his behavior in Pittsburgh. It was a good pickup because Holmes’s behavior was an issue only off the field; he produced between the lines. That’s obviously changed now. What’s more, Holmes stopped consistently beating man coverage this season, which had been his greatest trait. With looming changes at wide receiver, the decision of what to do offensively still comes down to overhauling the running game versus overhauling the passing game. The Jets are already built to run, and it’s easier to find a good ball carrier than a good ball thrower. That seems like the easier solution. It’s a much smarter solution than making scapegoats of the offensive coaching staff.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>From a Facebook Founder Comes a Way to Streamline Work Flow</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>20 May 2012 09:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		SAN FRANCISCO — Facebook’s success has spawned a multimillion-dollar boom in social networking. There are networks for photo-sharers, for children and for workers inside companies. Yammer and Jive, for instance, promise to energize employees and increase their productivity by enabling fast information sharing. Dustin Moskovitz thinks this is a bad idea that won’t fly. “The first time I looked at Yammer, I thought I was on Facebook,” he said. “Work is not a social network, with serendipitous communications and photo collections. Work is about managing tasks, and responding to things quickly.” Mr. Moskovitz does know a little bit about running the operations of a fast-growing company. He helped found Facebook along with Mark Zuckerberg, Eduardo Saverin and Chris Hughes while at Harvard in 2004. His job was to make sure the computers straining to run Facebook’s expanding network never went down. After leaving Facebook in 2008 with enough equity to make him one of the world’s youngest billionaires, Mr. Moskovitz, now 27, works on his own version of company management software for the networked age. He calls it Asana.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>In West Texas, a Chancellor Plays Defense</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>10 Nov 2011 13:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		On the evening of Oct. 24, a small group of local leaders and concerned citizens in this remote West Texas town assembled on the first floor of the historic Holland Hotel. They were there to consider the merits of severing Sul Ross State University’s longstanding ties to the Texas State University System but had not anticipated how quickly the news would spread. That morning, more than 400 miles away in his downtown Austin office, Brian McCall, the system’s chancellor, got wind of the gathering. With little time to spare, he hopped on a westbound plane, showing up unannounced and flanked by a well-dressed entourage that included Sul Ross’s president, Ricardo Maestas. “If people have concern about any of our universities, it’s my job to be there and hear what they have to say,” Mr. McCall said later. As the administrators listened, Rod Ponton, the incoming district attorney, said that the community was anxious about the release of the university’s latest enrollment figures — which showed a decline of nearly 10 percent between 2011 and 2012, following a dip the previous year — and a perceived lack of responsiveness to that troubling trend. The disheartening numbers, coupled with state leaders’ recent readiness to slash financing and cut unproductive academic programs, have stirred local fears over the future of the university — a campus that caters to West Texas students and enrolls higher-than-average rates of Hispanic and first-generation students. Sul Ross is the city’s largest employer and the only four-year institution of higher education in the sparsely populated Big Bend region, with an enrollment that has hovered around 2,000 students for the last decade.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>F.D.A. Backtracks and Returns Drug to Market</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>3 Sep 2011 21:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Two weeks ago, the Food and Drug Administration announced that it would remove the drug midodrine from the market because the drug’s maker never confirmed that the medicine — approved in 1996 under an abbreviated process — actually worked against dizziness and fainting. But 100,000 patients take midodrine for conditions many say would otherwise be disabling, and many flooded the agency with complaints. So on Friday morning, top F.D.A. officials announced that they had backtracked and would continue to allow midodrine to be sold. The announcement came after inquiries by The New York Times. “In a different situation, we might act differently,” said Dr. Joshua Sharfstein, principal deputy commissioner. “But in this case, it does not make sense to pull access to the drug while we get better data.” Dr. Janet Woodcock, director of the agency’s drug center agreed. “Patients are out there thinking doom is about to fall, and they can’t go about their normal business,” she said. Lindsey Mills, a 20-year-old from Baltimore, was among those granted a reprieve. Five years ago, she came back from a trip to the mall and found that she could barely stand because of dizziness. After seeing a parade of doctors, a specialist finally prescribed midodrine, which “was the only thing that allowed me to keep some function and attend classes and not be completely bedridden,” Ms. Mills said. The agency’s flip-flop demonstrates the difficult choices regulators face in policing the nation’s drug market. Cracking down on drug makers sometimes means stranding desperate patients. And now that Congress has given the Food and Drug Administration greater powers to insist on better information about life-saving medicines, such disputes may become more common.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Obama's Tack on Iran Is Hard to Read</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>13 Sep 2010 17:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Secretary of State Hillary Rodham Clinton, just last week, proclaimed that the world was entering “a new American moment when our global leadership is essential.” Presumably, that’s good news. But when it comes to leading, the task involves clarity, and on Iran’s sprint toward a nuclear weapon, there’s reason to see the Obama administration heading into confusion. With Iran now estimated to be in possession of enough low-enriched uranium to produce, with further enrichment, two nuclear weapons, and administration officials saying manufacturing one would take the mullahs about a year, American policy is hard-pressed to be credible. Either the administration is demonstrating a new toughness, or it has once again decided to reach out a diplomatic hand in Iran’s direction. People who heard President Barack Obama out on the subject here last month left a meeting divided about which of those notions he has in mind. If this is a new American Moment, the administration’s approach to Iran appears to be providing its friends with at least as much uncertainty as motivation and resolve. Talking to a small group of journalists and commentators at the White House early in August, Mr. Obama clearly sought to portray himself as holding the Iran issue in firm hands. The yield, instead, was two conflicting descriptions of his intent — in one case, more groping for diplomatic leads, in the other, no new diplomacy but an increasingly pugnacious stance — from two experienced writers, each with good administration contacts, who published their opposing accounts a couple of days apart on the opinion pages of The Washington Post.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
	<item>
		<title>Fracking Still Controversial in Europe</title>
		<link>
		http://feeds.nytimes.com/click.phdo?i=aabe9b64b06f18f74bf6196db8cd5244
		</link>
		<pubDate>13 Nov 13 2012 20:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<category>
		<![CDATA[ ? ]]>
		</category>
		<description>
		<![CDATA[
		Just outside Blackpool, a town of faded cabarets and amusement rides on the Irish Sea, a drilling rig sits in a muddy farm field. The big white and yellow machine represents the latest attempt by Cuadrilla Resources to see if it can bring Northwest England the sort of shale gas revolution that has transformed the U.S. energy picture. Cuadrilla’s chief executive, Francis Egan, who joined the company four months ago after a career spent in the international oil industry at giants like Marathon and BHP Billiton, says that Cuadrilla believes there is 200 trillion cubic feet of gas beneath the company’s 900-square-kilometer, or 348-square-mile, concession in the area. “That is a huge amount of gas,” he says. Even if only 10 percent were extractable, it would be enough to fuel Britain’s current consumption for about seven years. Britain is one of several European countries where experts think there could be commercially exploitable shale gas. The U.S. Energy Information Administration estimates that there may be as much as 600 trillion cubic feet of recoverable shale gas in Europe, or about 40 years’ consumption.
But there is still uncertainty about whether significant volumes of gas can be produced in Europe through drilling and hydraulic fracturing, or fracking, as has been done in the United States. The industry is barely getting started in Europe, but opposition is already strong.
		]]>
		</description>
	</item>
</rss>
